<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-01-18T21:52:18+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Life of a Modern Man</title><subtitle>Advising in Lifestyle and Finance</subtitle><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Work From Anywhere</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/work-form-anywhere/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Work From Anywhere" /><published>2023-01-08T03:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2023-01-08T03:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/work-form-anywhere</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/work-form-anywhere/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
Nomad work refers to a type of work that is not tied to a specific location or office, and can be done from anywhere in
the world with an internet connection. This type of work is becoming increasingly popular as more and more people are
able to take advantage of the flexibility and freedom that it offers. Besides, more and more companies are embracing
remote work and the use of technology makes it easier to stay connected and productive from any location.</div>

<p>Working from anywhere refers to the ability to do your job from any location, as long as you have access to the
necessary tools and resources. popular as the use of technology makes it easier to stay connected and productive from
any location.</p>

<p>If you don’t like monotony, who would not be willing to work while skiing in the Italian Alps, sunbathing in the Spanish
Canary Islands or diving in the exotic Bali?</p>

<h2 id="how-to-do-it">How to do it</h2>

<p>There are different types of nomad work, including remote work, freelancing, and digital nomadism. Remote work
refers to any type of work that is done remotely, usually from home or a coworking space. Freelancing refers to working
as a self-employed individual, offering services to clients on a project-by-project basis. Digital nomadism is a
specific type of nomad work that involves traveling the world while working remotely.</p>

<p>One of the main benefits of nomad work is the flexibility it offers. Instead of being tied to a specific location or
office, nomad workers have the freedom to choose where they want to work from. This allows them to work from home, a
coffee shop, a coworking space, or even from a different country.</p>

<p>Another benefit of working remotely is the ability to choose your own schedule. Many nomad workers have the freedom to
set their own schedule and work when it is convenient for them. This can be especially beneficial for those with
children or other responsibilities that make it difficult to work a traditional 9-5 job.</p>

<p>Nomad work also allows for a better work-life balance. Since nomad workers are not tied to a specific location, they
have the ability to travel and experience new cultures while still being able to work. This can be a great way to see
the world and have new experiences while still making a living.</p>

<p>However, nomad work is not for everyone. It can be challenging to stay motivated and focused when you are working from
home or a coworking space, and it can be difficult to build a professional network when you are constantly on the move.
It is also important to be self-disciplined and organized when working as a nomad, as there may not be the same level of
structure and oversight as there is in a traditional office setting.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/nomad/japan.jpeg" alt="Travel more, discover new things" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Having the benefit or chance of working from anywhere is a great opportunity to discover new countries and cultures. Maybe after that visit you would like to relocate this new place</span>
</p>

<h2 id="tips">Tips</h2>

<p>These are some tips to help you when changing your mind and embracing this new lifestyle:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Determine your work needs: Consider what type of work you do and what resources you need in order to be productive.
This will help you determine the best location for your nomad work.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Find a reliable internet connection: A strong and stable internet connection is essential for nomad work, so make
sure you have access to one wherever you go.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Set boundaries: It can be easy to get caught up in work when you are a nomad, so it is important to set boundaries
and make sure you take breaks and have a healthy work-life balance.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Stay organized: Nomad work can be disorganized at times, so it is important to have systems in place to keep track of
your work and stay on top of tasks.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Find a community: It can be lonely working as a nomad, so it is important to find a community of like-minded
individuals who can provide support and connection. This can be through online groups or by joining a coworking
space.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Plan for the future: Nomad work is not for everyone, and it is important to have a plan in place for the future in
case you decide to transition back to a more traditional work arrangement.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Protect your finances: Nomad work can be unpredictable, so it is important to have a financial safety net in place to
protect yourself in case of unexpected expenses or income fluctuations.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Stay in touch with home: Working abroad can be exciting, but it can also be homesickness. Make sure to stay in touch
with friends and family back home and keep them updated on your adventures.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Find temporary housing: If you will be working in a country for an extended period of time, it is a good idea to find
temporary housing rather than staying in a hotel. This can be more cost-effective and will also allow you to get a
better feel for local life.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Take care of your physical and mental health: It is important to prioritize your physical and mental health when you
   are a nomad, as it can be easy to neglect self-care when you are constantly on the move.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>Overall, nomad work offers many benefits, including flexibility, freedom, and the ability to choose your own schedule
and work from anywhere. However, it is not for everyone, and it is important to carefully consider whether it is the
right fit for you before making the decision to become a nomad worker.</p>

<p>Employees who are can enjoy working from anywhere may have more flexibility in their schedules, which can be especially
beneficial for those who have non-traditional work schedules or who may have difficulty taking time off due to family or
other commitments.</p>

<p>This aspect does not just benefit the employee, but the enterprise. Employees who have this type of flexibility are also
able to work more hours, be more creative and more productive. Furthermore, taking holidays should not be the only time
we have to visit other countries or regions.</p>

<p>Is the shift to remote work a temporary trend caused by the latest pandemic or a permanent change in the way we do
business? I think the last one, and I also have the opinion that still a lot of corporations have still to discover this
range of possibilities. Let’s hope I’m right about this last thought.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Work" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How working remotely can benefit you and your employer]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/nomad/nomad.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/nomad/nomad.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Shops for the Modern Man - Part II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/shops-for-the-modern-man-part-II/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shops for the Modern Man - Part II" /><published>2022-12-28T03:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-28T03:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/shops-for-the-modern-man-part-II</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/shops-for-the-modern-man-part-II/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
The modern man is a multifaceted individual who defies traditional gender roles and expectations. He is confident, ambitious, and driven, with a diverse range of interests and passions.
</div>

<p>One of the key characteristics of the modern man is his ability to adapt and evolve. He is open-minded and flexible,
always willing to learn and try new things. Whether it’s exploring new hobbies, learning a new skill, or taking on a new
challenge, the modern man is constantly seeking new experiences and ways to grow and improve.</p>

<p>It is great and interesting to have your unique style but catching up with all the shops and trends takes time and
efforts. In addition to this problem, we also lack inspiration on several occasions that makes our objective more
complicated.</p>

<h2 id="shops">Shops</h2>

<p>In order to help you with these problems, we included some examples of some shops some months ago. There are many
fashion brands that cater to the modern man. Here comes the second list with options for different tastes and from
various parts of the world. In today’s edition, we have shops from Brazil, Denmark, Japan and Spain.</p>

<p>The shortlisted shops for this article are included below, and we start with one with roots in Brazil and the UK.</p>

<h3 id="frescobol-carioca">Frescobol Carioca</h3>

<p>Frescobol Carioca is a luxury clothing brand that is based in Brazil. The company was founded in 1992 and is known for
its high-quality, stylish beachwear and resort wear. The company’s collections often feature bold, colorful prints and
designs that are inspired by Brazilian culture and the vibrant colors of Rio de Janeiro. The brand’s clothing and
accessories are made using traditional techniques and high-quality materials, and are popular among fashion-conscious
travelers and beachgoers.</p>

<p>The company was founded by two friends who were inspired by the city’s vibrant beach culture. Frescobol Carioca offers a
range of high-quality men’s swimwear, beachwear, and</p>

<p>accessories, with a focus on classic designs and high-end materials. Not just from Rio, but the designs of this brand
are also inspired in other aspects such as music, landscapes or vegetations.</p>

<p>Some of the most famous collections include designs around Azulejos, Bossa Nova or Jardim Botánico. Nonetheless, they
are also expanding into other apparel and had some interesting collaborations.</p>

<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.frescobolcarioca.com/">Frescobol Carioca</a></p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/shops2/frescobol.jpg" alt="Rio Inspiration" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">If you look at their prints Frescobol Carioca's swimwear is a brand always creating bold and original designs to wear at the beach</span>
</p>

<h3 id="mango">Mango</h3>

<p>Mango is a popular fashion brand that is based in Barcelona, Spain. The company was founded in 1984 and is known for its
trendy clothing, shoes, and accessories for both men and women. It also owes its name to the tropical fruit when the
founder tasted it on a trip to the Philippines. Mango’s collections often feature a mix of modern and classic styles,
and the brand has stores in more than 100 countries around the world. In addition to its own label, Mango also offers a
more affordable line called Mango Man, as well as a more premium line called Mango Committed, which features sustainable
and ethical fashion.</p>

<p>The Spanish company is a fashion brand that is known for its trendy and modern styles. The brand’s collections often
feature a mix of classic and contemporary pieces, with a focus on high-quality fabrics and attention to detail. Mango’s
clothing is often described as being chic and sophisticated, with a touch of playfulness and innovation.</p>

<p>Overall, the Spanish brand’s aesthetic is influenced by a range of global styles, from European fashion to the latest
streetwear trends, and is designed to appeal to a wide range of customers. Mango’s collections include a range of
clothing, shoes, and accessories for both men and women.</p>

<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.mango.com/">Mango</a></p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/shops2/mango.jpg" alt="Jack of all trades" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Mango is known for having a great selection of quality and affordable garments, designed for different occasions </span>
</p>

<h3 id="mismo">Mismo</h3>

<p>Mismo is a Danish luxury accessories brand that was founded in 2003. The company is known for its high-quality bags and
accessories for men, which are made from the finest materials and designed to be both functional and stylish.</p>

<p>Founded in 2003, Mismo’s collections include a range of briefcases, backpacks, tote bags, and travel accessories, as
well as smaller items such as wallets and cardholders. The brand is known for its minimalist aesthetic and attention to
detail, and has a loyal following among men who appreciate well-made, timeless accessories.</p>

<p>In addition to its own line of products, Mismo also offers a range of limited edition collaborations with other
designers and brands that makes their product unique and lasting a lifetime.</p>

<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.mismo.dk/">Mismo</a></p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/shops2/mismo.JPG" alt="Modern classics" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Mismo's weekend bags are an iconic product that you can use in your trips and that even family members will be able to inherit</span>
</p>

<h3 id="kamakura">Kamakura</h3>

<p>Kamakura is a city located in the Kanagawa Prefecture of Japan. It is situated about 50 kilometers south of Tokyo on the
Pacific coast, and is known for its many temples and shrines. The city served as the political center of Japan from 1185
to 1333, during which time it was the seat of the Kamakura shogunate. Kamakura is also home to many historical
landmarks, including the Tsurugaoka Hachimangū shrine and the Great Buddha of Kamakura.</p>

<p>With their headquarters in this city, Kamakura is also the brand of dress shirts located in the Asian country. Although
they agree that shirts are not coming from Japan, they are inspired by other countries and western styles with the goal
of making perfect shirts.</p>

<p>This way, Kamakura Shirts has become an icon of dress with top-notch quality and service. Their dress shirts take
inspiration from many regions. For example, theirslim fit shirts are inspired by Italian model shirts from Napoli, with
a slender silhouette. On the other hand their classic fit shirts, give a feeling of British and American elements.</p>

<p>In addition to these iconic models, they also offer other services such as shirts for women or made to measure shirts.
If you happen to by close to this city, it may be worth to visit the shop.</p>

<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.kamakurashirts.com/">Kamakura</a></p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/shops2/kamakura.JPG" alt="Japanese craftsmanship" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Kamakura is synonym of adopting and mixing other styles in order to build a top-quality product. Their dress or sport shirts will not deceive you</span>
</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>Shopping for the modern man can be a daunting task. With so many options available, it can be difficult to know where to
start. However, with a little research and some careful consideration, you can find the perfect shop for all your needs.
In this article, we have included other 4 shops that you can add for your inspiration or in your wardrobe.</p>

<p>With these tips in mind, you should be well on your way to finding the best shops for the modern man. Whether you’re
looking for a new suit, a casual weekend outfit, or something in between, there’s a shop out there that can meet your
needs. Happy shopping!</p>

<p>These are just a few examples of fashion brands that cater to the modern man. There are many other options available,
and the right choice will depend on personal style and preferences.</p>

<p>Overall, the modern man is a complex and dynamic individual who is constantly evolving and growing. He is confident,
ambitious, and driven, but also deeply compassionate and committed to personal and societal growth. He is the embodiment
of the modern man – complex, multifaceted, and constantly striving to be his best self.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Style" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apparel from Brazil, Denmark, Japan and Spain to add to your unique style]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/shops2/shops.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/shops2/shops.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Deep Work and How to Get There</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/deep-work-and-how-to-get-there/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deep Work and How to Get There" /><published>2022-12-17T03:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-17T03:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/deep-work-and-how-to-get-there</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/deep-work-and-how-to-get-there/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
What’s deep work and why you are hearing more and more this term? Deep work is the ability to focus without distraction
on a cognitively demanding task. It is a state of flow in which you are fully immersed in the task at hand and able to
produce high-quality work in a short amount of time. There are several benefits to practicing deep work.
</div>

<p>Deep work is a term coined by productivity expert and author Cal Newport to describe the state of intense focus and
concentration on a cognitively demanding task. In today’s world, where we are constantly bombarded with distractions and
notifications from our smartphones and computers, it can be difficult to achieve this state of deep work. However,
learning to engage in deep work can have significant benefits for our productivity and creativity.</p>

<h2 id="benefits">Benefits</h2>

<p>One of the key benefits of deep work is that it allows us to produce high-quality work in less time. When we are able to
focus intensely on a task without distractions, our brains are able to work more efficiently and we can make faster
progress. This is especially important in the age of information overload, where we often have a large amount of work to
do and limited time to do it.</p>

<p>In addition to being more efficient, deep work can also lead to higher-quality results. When we are able to focus deeply
on a task, we are able to think more critically and creatively, and this can result in better ideas and solutions. This
is especially important in fields that require a high level of creativity and problem-solving, such as research,
writing, and software development.</p>

<p>Although this may seem easy, different factors can affect our life.</p>

<p>achieving deep work is not always easy. In order to engage in deep work, we need to be able to eliminate distractions
and create an environment that is conducive to focus and concentration. This can involve setting aside dedicated blocks
of time for deep work, finding a quiet and comfortable place to work, and using tools and techniques to block out
distractions.</p>

<p>For example, some people find it helpful to use a Pomodoro timer to break their work into focused 25-minute intervals,
with short breaks in between. Others use noise-cancelling headphones or ambient noise apps to block out background noise
and help them concentrate. Some people even go to extreme lengths, such as disconnecting from the internet or working in
a secluded cabin in the woods, to create the optimal conditions for deep work.</p>

<p>There are several benefits of engaging in deep work:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Increased productivity: Deep work allows us to produce high-quality work in less time. When we are able to focus
intensely on a task without distractions, our brains are able to work more efficiently and we can make faster
progress.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Higher-quality results: In addition to being more efficient, deep work can also lead to higher-quality results. When
we are able to focus deeply on a task, we are able to think more critically and creatively, and this can result in
better ideas and solutions.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Improved mental clarity and focus: Engaging in deep work can improve our mental clarity and focus. When we are able
to eliminate distractions and concentrate on a single task, our minds are able to process information more
effectively and we can think more deeply and clearly.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Enhanced creativity and problem-solving skills: Deep work can also enhance our creativity and problem-solving skills.
By focusing intensely on a task, we are able to tap into our unconscious mind and generate new ideas and solutions
that we might not have come up with otherwise.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Greater sense of accomplishment and fulfillment: Finally, engaging in deep work can give us a greater sense of
accomplishment and fulfillment. When we are able to focus deeply on a task and produce high-quality work, we feel
proud of our achievements and satisfied with our efforts. This can boost our motivation and drive to continue
pursuing our goals and passions.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Improved problem-solving skills: Deep work allows you to fully engage with and understand a problem, which can lead
to better and more creative solutions.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Enhanced learning and memory: Focusing deeply on a task can help you better understand and retain information.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Increased job satisfaction: The sense of accomplishment and progress that comes from completing a task can lead to
increased job satisfaction.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Better time management: Deep work can help you make better use of your time, as you are able to complete tasks more
efficiently.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Reduced stress: By focusing on one task at a time, you can avoid the stress that comes with multitasking and trying
   to juggle multiple tasks at once.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/deep_work/tiger_dw.jpeg" alt="Areas and Applications" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">At the office or at school, there are multiple areas where we can apply our Deep Work results. This is not exclusive to these places, but also other applications such as languages, at home office or performing our favourite sport. </span>
</p>

<h2 id="deep-work-techniques">Deep Work Techniques</h2>

<p>As we have said, achieving this state, it’s not easy. Nonetheless, these are some tricks and techniques that can help
you with this task.</p>

<p>There are several strategies you can use to improve your focus and concentration at work. Although as you can see, these
ideas can also benefit in other aspects of your daily life.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Set clear goals: Clearly define what you need to accomplish and why it is important. This will help you stay focused
on the task at hand.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Create a conducive work environment: Find a quiet, comfortable, and well-lit place to work. Minimize distractions by
closing unnecessary programs and silencing your phone.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Take breaks: Taking breaks can help you recharge and refocus. Step away from your work every hour or so to stretch,
walk around, or get a snack.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Use the Pomodoro Technique: The Pomodoro Technique involves working in 25-minute blocks followed by a short break.
This can help you stay focused and avoid burnout.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Remove unnecessary tasks: Prioritize your tasks and eliminate those that are not necessary or can be delegated to
someone else.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Use techniques to block distractions: There are several techniques you can use to block out distractions, such as the
Pomodoro Technique, the “Do Not Disturb” function on your phone, or noise-cancelling headphones.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Get enough sleep: Make sure you are getting enough rest so you can focus better during the day.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Practice mindfulness: Focusing on the present moment can help you stay engaged with your work. Try incorporating
mindfulness practices such as meditation or deep breathing into your daily routine.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>By following these strategies, you can improve your focus and concentration at work and increase your productivity and
squeeze the most of us.</p>

<p>Overall, practicing deep work can help you increase your productivity, improve your problem-solving skills, enhance your
learning and memory, increase your job satisfaction, and better manage your time.</p>

<p>That said, deep work is a valuable skill that can have significant benefits for our productivity and creativity. While
it can be challenging to achieve, the rewards of being able to focus deeply on our work are well worth the effort. By
learning to eliminate distractions and create an environment that is conducive to focus, we can engage in deep work and
produce our best work.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Different techniques and benefits of applying Deep Work in our life, including how we can achieve this easier]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/deep_work/deep-work.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/deep_work/deep-work.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Benefits of Trail Running</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/benefits-of-trail-running/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Benefits of Trail Running" /><published>2022-12-10T03:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-10T03:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/benefits-of-trail-running</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/benefits-of-trail-running/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
Trail running is a form of off-road running that takes place on hiking trails, dirt paths, and other natural terrain. It
is a popular outdoor activity that allows runners to explore the beauty of nature while also challenging themselves
physically and mentally.</div>

<p>One of the main benefits of trail running is the variety of scenery that it offers. Unlike road running, which often
takes place on dull, monotonous stretches of pavement, trail running allows runners to experience the beauty of forests,
mountains, and other natural environments. This can provide a much-needed change of scenery for runners who are used to
running on roads, and it can make the activity more enjoyable and stimulating.</p>

<p>In addition to the beautiful scenery, trail running also offers a number of physical and mental benefits. Running on
natural terrain can be more challenging than running on pavement, as it often involves steep hills, uneven surfaces, and
other obstacles. This can provide a more intense workout and help to improve a runner’s strength, endurance, and overall
fitness level.</p>

<h2 id="benefits">Benefits</h2>

<p>Trail running can also be a great way to reduce stress and improve mental health. Being outdoors in nature has been
shown to have a calming effect on the mind, and the physical exertion of running can help to release endorphins and
other feel-good chemicals in the brain. As a result, many people find that trail running helps them to relax, de-stress,
and feel more positive and energized.</p>

<p>To get started with trail running, it is important to have the right equipment. In addition to a good pair of running
shoes, it is also a good idea to invest in some other gear that is designed specifically for trail running. This can
include items such as a hydration pack or water bottle, trail running gaiters, and a hat or visor to protect your eyes
from the sun.</p>

<p>It is also important to choose a trail that is appropriate for your skill level. Beginners should start with easy,
well-maintained trails, and gradually work their way up to more challenging terrain as they become more experienced. It
is also a good idea to run with a buddy or in a group, as this can provide additional support and motivation.</p>

<p>There are many benefits to trail running, including:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Beautiful scenery: Unlike road running, which often takes place on dull, monotonous stretches of pavement, trail
running allows runners to experience the beauty of forests, mountains, and other natural environments. This can
provide a much-needed change of scenery and make the activity more enjoyable and stimulating.</li>
  <li>Increased physical challenge: Running on natural terrain can be more challenging than running on pavement, as it
often involves steep hills, uneven surfaces, and other obstacles. This can provide a more intense workout and help to
improve a runner’s strength, endurance, and overall fitness level.</li>
  <li>Mental health benefits: Being outdoors in nature has been shown to have a calming effect on the mind, and the
physical exertion of running can help to release endorphins and other feel-good chemicals in the brain. As a result,
many people find that trail running helps them to reduce stress, improve their mood, and feel more positive and
energized.</li>
  <li>Improved coordination and balance: Trail running requires a higher level of coordination and balance than road
running, as runners must navigate uneven terrain and avoid obstacles. This can help to improve a runner’s overall
balance and coordination, and reduce the risk of falls and injuries.</li>
  <li>Social interaction: Many people find that trail running is a great way to meet new people and make friends who share
their love of the outdoors. Running with a buddy or in a group can provide additional support, motivation, and a
sense of community.</li>
</ol>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/trail/lost.jpeg" alt="Dangers of Trail Running" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">If you are new doing this activity, some aspects to consider are high temperatures, sunburn, wild animals or getting lost.</span>
</p>

<h2 id="things-to-consider">Things to consider</h2>

<p>There are several potential problems and dangers that can arise when trail running, including the following:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Dehydration: Trail running can be strenuous, and it is important to stay hydrated by drinking plenty of water before,
during, and after your run.</li>
  <li>Blisters: Ill-fitting shoes or wet socks can cause blisters to form on your feet, which can be painful and interfere
with your ability to run comfortably.</li>
  <li>Slips and falls: Trail running often involves running over uneven terrain, which can increase your risk of slipping
and falling. This can lead to injuries such as sprains, strains, and fractures.</li>
  <li>Sunburn: Many trail runs take place outdoors, where you may be exposed to the sun for extended periods of time. This
can lead to sunburn, which can be painful and increase your risk of skin cancer.</li>
  <li>Insect bites: Trail running can expose you to a variety of insects, such as mosquitoes and ticks, which can bite and
cause irritation.</li>
  <li>Wild animals: Depending on where you are trail running, you may encounter wild animals such as snakes, bears, and
mountain lions. It is important to be aware of your surroundings and take appropriate precautions to avoid any
potential encounters.</li>
  <li>Overuse injuries, such as shin splints or stress fractures, if you don’t properly warm up or cool down</li>
  <li>Exposure to the elements, such as cold temperatures or heavy rain, which can be dangerous if you’re not prepared</li>
  <li>Getting lost if you don’t have a map or don’t pay attention to your surroundings</li>
</ol>

<p>To avoid these dangers, it’s important to be prepared before heading out on the trail. Make sure you have the right
equipment and supplies, plan your route carefully, and pay attention to your surroundings. If you’re not sure about the
trail or if you’re unsure of your abilities, it’s always a good idea to start with shorter, easier trails and work your
way up to more challenging routes.</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>In conclusion, Trail running is a great way to explore nature and get some exercise at the same time.</p>

<p>To get started with trail running, here are a few tips:</p>

<ol>
  <li>First, make sure you have the right equipment. You will need a good pair of trail running shoes with good traction to
help you navigate the terrain. It’s also a good idea to bring a small backpack with water, snacks, and a map of the
trail.</li>
  <li>Before heading out on the trail, take some time to plan your route and check the weather. Choose a trail that is
appropriate for your skill level, and make sure you have a good idea of how long it will take you to complete the
route.</li>
  <li>When you’re out on the trail, pay attention to your surroundings and be aware of any potential hazards, such as steep
drop-offs or unstable ground. If you’re running with a group, make sure to stay together and help each other out if
anyone needs assistance.</li>
  <li>As you run, focus on maintaining a steady pace and keeping your breathing and heart rate under control. It’s okay to
take breaks if you need to catch your breath or rest your muscles, but try to keep moving forward to avoid getting
tired or losing motivation.</li>
  <li>Finally, listen to your body and pay attention to how you’re feeling. If you start to feel pain or discomfort, slow
down or stop and take a break. It’s important to take care of yourself while trail running to avoid injury and ensure
you have a safe and enjoyable experience.</li>
</ol>

<p>Overall, trail running is a fun and rewarding outdoor activity that offers a range of physical and mental benefits.
Whether you are a seasoned runner looking for a new challenge, or a beginner who is just starting to explore the world
of off-road running, trail running is a great way to stay active, healthy, and happy.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What trail running can add to our sport activity, recommendations and other aspects to take into account]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/trail/trail.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/trail/trail.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">The Future of Deep Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-future-of-deep-learning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Future of Deep Learning" /><published>2022-12-06T13:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-06T13:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-future-of-deep-learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-future-of-deep-learning/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Deep Learning are two closely related fields that have garnered a lot of attention in
recent years. AI is a broad term that refers to the ability of a machine or computer program to simulate human
intelligence and perform tasks that typically require human cognition, such as learning, problem-solving, and
decision-making.</div>

<p>Deep learning, on the other hand, is a subset of AI that uses large neural networks with multiple layers of processing
to learn and make decisions based on data.</p>

<p>The history of AI can be traced back to the 1950s, when researchers began exploring the possibility of creating machines
that could perform tasks that required human intelligence.</p>

<p>Early AI research focused on creating algorithms that could mimic human decision-making processes and problem-solving
abilities. However, the limitations of computing power at the time meant that these early AI systems were not able to
handle the large amounts of data and complex calculations required for more advanced tasks.</p>

<p>The rise of the internet and the availability of large datasets in the 1990s provided a major boost to AI research. This
led to the development of new algorithms and techniques, such as decision trees and support vector machines, that could
handle large amounts of data and make more accurate predictions. However, these algorithms still relied on human input
to define the rules and criteria used to make decisions, which limited their ability to learn and adapt to new
situations.</p>

<p>Deep learning, on the other hand, uses large neural networks with multiple layers of processing to learn and make
decisions based on data. These networks are inspired by the structure of the human brain, with each layer of neurons
performing a specific function and passing information to the next layer for further processing. Unlike traditional AI
algorithms, deep learning algorithms do not require human input to define the rules and criteria used to make decisions.
Instead, they are able to learn from the data they are given and improve their performance over time.</p>

<h2 id="deep-learning">Deep Learning</h2>

<p>One of the key advantages of deep learning is its ability to handle unstructured data, such as images, audio, and text.
This has made it particularly useful in fields such as computer vision, natural language processing, and speech
recognition, where traditional AI algorithms struggle to make sense of complex and unstructured data. For example, deep
learning algorithms have been used to develop image recognition systems that can accurately identify objects in images,
and language translation systems that can accurately translate text from one language to another.</p>

<p>Deep learning has also been used in a variety of other fields, including healthcare, finance, and transportation. In
healthcare, deep learning algorithms have been used to identify patterns in medical images that may indicate the
presence of certain diseases, such as cancer. In finance, deep learning algorithms have been used to analyze large
amounts of market data and make predictions about stock prices and other asset classes.</p>

<p>Despite these advantages, there are also challenges and limitations to the use of deep learning. One of the main
challenges is the need for large amounts of data to train the algorithms, which can be difficult to obtain in some
applications. In addition, deep learning algorithms can be complex and difficult to interpret, making it difficult to
understand why they make certain predictions or decisions. This can be a problem in applications where explainability is
important, such as in medical diagnosis or financial decision-making.</p>

<h2 id="utilities">Utilities</h2>

<p>The future of deep learning looks bright, with researchers and companies continuing to invest in this field to develop
new applications and technologies. In the next few years, we can expect to see deep learning algorithms become even more
powerful and versatile, with the ability to handle even larger and more complex datasets.</p>

<p>One of the key areas where deep learning is expected to have a significant impact is in healthcare. Deep learning
algorithms are already being used to analyze medical images and identify patterns that may indicate the presence of
certain diseases. In the future, we can expect to see these algorithms become even more accurate and able to handle a
wider range of medical data, such as genomics and electronic health records. This could potentially lead to more
personalized and effective treatments for patients, and help healthcare providers to diagnose and treat diseases more
efficiently.</p>

<p>Another area where deep learning is expected to have a major impact is in transportation. Deep learning algorithms are
already being used in self-driving cars to enable them to navigate roads and avoid obstacles. In the future, we can
expect to see these algorithms become even more advanced, with the ability to handle a wider range of driving conditions
and scenarios. This could potentially lead to the development of safer and more efficient self-driving cars, and pave
the way for the widespread adoption of autonomous vehicles.</p>

<p>In addition, deep learning is also expected to play a significant role in the development of smart cities. Deep learning
algorithms can be used to analyze large amounts of data from sensors and other sources to identify patterns and trends,
and help city planners and policymakers to make more informed decisions. For example, deep learning algorithms could be
used to analyze traffic data to optimize the flow of vehicles on roads, or to monitor energy usage in buildings to
improve efficiency.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/deep_learning/surgeon.jpg" alt="Medicine and Deep Learning" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">In fields such as Medicine, Deep Learning is already being used to analyze medical images and identify patterns that may indicate the presence of certain diseases.</span>
</p>

<h2 id="deep-learning-and-the-workforce">Deep Learning and the workforce</h2>

<p>The rise of deep learning has had a significant impact on the workforce, with many companies and industries starting to
adopt this technology to improve efficiency and productivity. Deep learning algorithms are able to learn from large
amounts of data and make predictions and decisions based on that data, which makes them well-suited for a wide range of
tasks and applications.</p>

<p>One of the key ways that deep learning is being used in the workforce is in automating tasks that were previously
performed by humans. Many companies are using deep learning algorithms to automate repetitive and time-consuming tasks,
such as data entry and analysis, customer service, and scheduling. This allows employees to focus on more complex and
value-added tasks, and can improve overall productivity and efficiency.</p>

<p>However, the widespread adoption of deep learning in the workforce has also raised concerns about job displacement. As
deep learning algorithms become more advanced and are able to perform more tasks, there is a risk that they could
replace human workers in many industries. This could potentially lead to job losses and increased unemployment, and
could have a negative impact on the economy.</p>

<p>To address this concern, it is important for companies and policymakers to invest in training and education programs
that can help workers acquire the skills and knowledge necessary to work alongside deep learning algorithms and adapt to
new technologies. This could include training programs in areas such as data analysis, programming, and machine
learning, which can help workers to develop the skills needed to work with deep learning algorithms and other emerging
technologies.</p>

<p>In conclusion, deep learning is having a significant impact on the workforce, with many companies using this technology
to automate tasks and improve efficiency. While this has the potential to bring many benefits, it also raises concerns
about job displacement and the need for workers to adapt to new technologies. To address these challenges, it is
important for companies and policymakers to invest in training and education programs that can help.</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>Overall, the future of deep learning looks very promising, with the potential to transform a wide range of industries
and applications. As deep learning algorithms continue to evolve and become more powerful, we can expect to see even
more exciting other useful applications in this field.</p>

<p>For example, if you have noticed,this article is just an example of what Deep Learning can achieve generating the text you have just read. 
Therefore, the future we are describing above may not be that far away.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Different examples of how Deep Learning works, including some cases such as this article]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/deep_learning/deep.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/deep_learning/deep.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">NFT Utilities and How To Create Them</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/NFT-utilities-and-how-to-create-them/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NFT Utilities and How To Create Them" /><published>2022-12-03T13:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-03T13:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/NFT-utilities-and-how-to-create-them</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/NFT-utilities-and-how-to-create-them/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="utilities-of-nfts">Utilities of NFTs</h1>

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
2021 was the year of the NFTs where we saw a boom in the Non-Fungible Token trading transaction volume thanks to the
ERC-721 standard created back in 2018. This trend seems that has diminished recently in the current crypto bear market,
but contrary to what some people thought we have more and more marketplaces and sites that offer you the chance to
discover your next collectible.</div>

<p>Although NFTs are known for art and just some characteristic images, this article will not be focused merely on the
artistic side, but also other utilities that Non-Fungible Tokens can bring to your entertainment and lifestyle.</p>

<p>The term Non-Fungible Token means that this item is unique and cannot be duplicated. If you are the owner of an NFT,
this piece belongs just to you and this ownership is reflected in the blockchain network. Different Blockchain network
such as the mentioned one from Ethereum or others such as Avalanche, or Solana make this possible.</p>

<h2 id="origins-of-nfts">Origins of NFTs</h2>

<p>It all happened in 2021. There is no exact reason for the boom of NFTs during this year, but there some events that most
probably had something to do with the rise of NFTs.</p>

<p>During this period, more and more people jumped into the crypto world. In some cases, they did not have a previous
investment background and this phenomenon opened many doors in the retail industry. Furthermore, some famous people and
investment firms also promoted this change. Besides, Investment banks that had criticized Bitcoin in the past changed
their mind and some of these firms started also offering these alternative assets to their clients.</p>

<p>On one hand, the central banks low-interest or quantitative easing policies caused a huge increase on the price of the different
crypto assets. Another topic that helped with this was the creation of different communities such as Bored Apples or
CryptoPunks</p>

<p>If we put everything into the mix, we saw what we saw with the explosion of NFTs that occurred some years ago and the
adoption of these in the society.</p>

<h2 id="utilities">Utilities</h2>

<p>However, although NFTs may be linked to pictures or avatars, there are a lot of areas beyond this topic where NFTs can
play a great role, either now or in the years to come. Although it may seem interesting too, we will not talk about the
several millions that were paid to acquire some NFTs in auction houses such as Christie’s or on-chain.</p>

<p>If you have not realized about the potential across sectors that NFTs have, you will probably see that these will impact
for good these sectors in the future.</p>

<h3 id="art">Art</h3>

<p>With the democratization of art, this means that all artists can promote their creativity and by doing so, they are also
able to reach to more people. With NFTs, you and only you are the owner of these unique pieces. Who know where the next
Picasso or Dali will be? This means that art lovers and the search of the next gem is not limited to just some
privileged collectors with good connections, but to everyone who loves art and beauty.</p>

<h3 id="videogames">Videogames</h3>

<p>Non-Fungible Tokens have a lot of possibilities when it comes to the gaming industry. The boom of online video games,
e-sports and open world games have helped achieve this. If we think about the most iconic series, several utilities can
be proposed.</p>

<p>For example, in MOBA games such as League of Legends, having a unique skin and spell effects for you character could not
just improve your gaming experience but also trade with them after you get tired of it.</p>

<p>Although the normal price of skins is considerably low, this means that they are not unique, and you may see all the
time the same ones when playing the game. Knowing the number of fanatic gamers, it would be interesting for some of them
to have a unique skin that would make other players jealous. For companies, it would need to be checked whether this
business model makes sense (high volume and low price or selling just one single skin for several thousands of dollars)</p>

<h3 id="music">Music</h3>

<p>Instead of collecting limited edition vinyl records or CDs, the next step in our constantly changing world could be
having the original copy or even special edition versions or unreleased remixes of top hits. Instead of having the
physical copy you would have it registered in the blockchain.</p>

<p>For musicians and DJs, this can be a great very interesting mechanism, same as art makers, to promote their job and
access to different users around the world. This also removes intermediaries that take a big piece of the cake.</p>

<p>For example, if you like EDM and you go to festivals often, you may have noticed that recently the songs that the
different DJs play are the ones that are being played everywhere, and they tend to play the latest hits. You may have
seen this in festivals such as Ultra or Tomorrowland. This makes the music sessions not as original as before.</p>

<p>If you attend one of these sets, this can be the only time you can hear a specific unreleased song because they are the
sole owners of this one. Some collectors may be interested on this specific version and request the artist to buy it.</p>

<p>In connection to the commercial side of this feature, since you are the owner of this song, you could set a
subscription/reproduction fee if someone wants to play your song.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/nfts/dog-vinyls.jpg" alt="The new collection method" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Nostalgic collectors may not think the same, but collecting music in new format files add many new possibilities and reduces problems such as storage or conservation of old formats
</span>
</p>

<h3 id="videos">Videos</h3>

<p>The movies sector didn’t change much in the last decade until Covid arrived. Starting 2020, since people could not go
out, there were several days for some long-awaited movies. In other cases, that they allowed was to offer the movies via
some streaming platforms.</p>

<p>However, what could really revolutionize the art of collecting records of the different movies would be the chance of
having original and unique recordings, such as shorts or cut scenes of your favorite movie. If you think about fans of
the most well-known sagas such as Star Wars or the Godfather, these items could have an exponential increase in a few
years from now.</p>

<h3 id="tickets">Tickets</h3>

<p>Imagine going to a football game or concert. This is nothing unusual and something that everyone has done. If you for
example go to a world cup final, you may record videos, etc., but one of the things probably you will want to keep it
for this unique experience will be the tickets of the match you attended.</p>

<p>The same could be applied to other events. Imagine going to last tour of your favorite music band before they split or
retire. This is also something quite unique that would like to keep, and it’s probably that something will increase their
value with the years should you want to sell it later.</p>

<h3 id="creating-and-minting-nfts">Creating and minting NFTs</h3>

<p>The good thing about the NFTs is that the steps to create them are quite easy. It’s not correct that in order to take
part in these topics you are required to have a technical profile. You may have heard the term “Mint”. This is basically
registering the NFT on the blockchain, which in this case will show that belong to your wallet. Obviously, you will need
to create something unique, for which you will need to show some creativity and originality. However, once you completed
your first work, the steps can be summarized as follows:</p>

<h3 id="creating-a-wallet">Creating a Wallet</h3>

<p>If you are new to the crypto world, don’t be afraid of terms. Creating a wallet is something that not many people do at
the moment, but I can guarantee that as with other technologies, in the future everyone will have their own wallet where
they can keep and guard their assets without the need of a middleman. As just discussed, this is something that anyone can do
regardless of their background and technology skills.</p>

<p>Some of the most popular wallets out there are Metamask, Coinbase Wallet or Phantom.</p>

<h3 id="choosing-the-chain">Choosing the chain</h3>

<p>The choice of the wallet is linked to the blockchain where you operate and the marketplace where you want to show your
item. Some blockchains you may consider are Ethereum, Polygon, Solana, Tezos. The chain you use will have an impact
in the site or platform where you want to show your NFTs. As with the wallet, the marketplace you choose in the second
point is also linked to this step.</p>

<h3 id="selecting-the-nft-marketplace">Selecting the NFT marketplace</h3>

<p>Some of the most famous sites to trade NFTs are OpenSea, Magic Eden or Rarible and they offer different However, as we
discussed in the introduction, you see more and more often new places dedicated to certain niche markets.</p>

<p>If you are new into this world, some benefits of OpenSea is that you don’t pay any gas fees when minting and
these fees are just paid if you sell your NFT.</p>

<h3 id="tokenizing-the-nft">Tokenizing the NFT</h3>

<p>When creating the NFT, it is recommended to provide additional information and not just the basic details. For example,
include some details like the name, the collection, and other technical details.</p>

<h3 id="showing-and-selling-the-nft">Showing and selling the NFT</h3>

<p>Once you have linked your wallet to the desired site, you can just show your collection, sell the items, or buy new NFTs
to add to your collection. In this example, I just included the basic steps, but of course the industry is constantly
evolving, and you will see new wallets, marketplaces and chains.</p>

<p>If you want to have a look at my collection, you can just go to the links below:</p>

<p><a href="https://opensea.io/collection/animals-badass">https://opensea.io/collection/animals-badass</a></p>

<p><a href="https://opensea.io/collection/gaming-gnigmag">https://opensea.io/collection/gaming-gnigmag</a></p>

<p><a href="https://opensea.io/collection/jeopard">https://opensea.io/collection/jeopard</a></p>

<p><a href="https://opensea.io/collection/realcybercryptopunk">https://opensea.io/collection/realcybercryptopunk</a></p>

<p><a href="https://opensea.io/collection/welcome-to-the-metajungle">https://opensea.io/collection/welcome-to-the-metajungle</a></p>

<p>That should be all for now. You will see that the process is not complicated at all. Good luck and Happy Minting!</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[From art to videogames and sports, what NFTs can change in these sectors and the neccesary steps to create them]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/nfts/nfts.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/nfts/nfts.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">How Nutrition Is Impacting Your Life</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/how-nutrition-is-impacting-your-life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Nutrition Is Impacting Your Life" /><published>2022-11-04T13:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2022-11-04T13:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/how-nutrition-is-impacting-your-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/how-nutrition-is-impacting-your-life/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
Eating is one of the pleasures of life and apart from that a way of being able to meet with family and friends. However, although we are not conscious of it, eating well or bad plays an important role in our life (mood, work, sport, etc.). Although it was probably today when we have more access to information, it is also the era where producers try to include in the market products with ingredients that can be harmful for us. It’s quite also understandable that more and more people have obesity problems. Although governments are trying to put a remedy to this trend or even “modern disease”, instead of rules, what we should do is educate people and let them know about all consequences.
</div>

<p>I, as probably you, love eating and probably you are also trying to taste new flavors or discover new restaurants.
However, I’m also telling you nothing new when I say that this exercise in excess can have very bad consequences, that
will slowly hurt your body.</p>

<p>It’s strange, but true, we are what we eat. Whoever said this sentence for the first time, he knew what he was doing.</p>

<p>It’s strange, but true, we are what we eat. Whoever said this sentence for the first time, he knew what he was doing.</p>

<h2 id="problems">Problems</h2>

<p>Although it may seem that eating just negative consequences in few aspects (our physical body and the shape), it
probably has even worse consequences in other aspects of our life, which are of course more important than keeping a
flat belly. You will see for example people who eat poor quality food, they remain thin, but you will see other aspects
that are indicative of their diet. These symptoms are more severe than the look of their silhouette.</p>

<h3 id="fatigue">Fatigue</h3>

<p>When you eat heavy food, with a lot of calories, our organs need to switch to “hard-work” mode, and they consume more
energy in order to be able to digest them. Simply mathematics, our organs need to allocate more energy to this task, and
there will be less energy in order to do the remaining tasks, leading to feeling tired and without desired to do
anything.</p>

<p>Some examples of unhealthy nutrients having a considerable impact in this point are those containing too much sugar,
salt, or flour. They can be an instant boost of energy, but this effect is lost some minutes later, leading to the
opposite results.</p>

<h3 id="mood">Mood</h3>

<p>We have more and more advances and breakthroughs in different aspects, making our life easier. The problem is that
despite these improvements, why with better conditions there are more and more burnouts, depressions, and even people
committing suicide? Of course, there are other reasons, but one of the factors is related to the food. One of the
reasons, is that eating products high in trans-fat, they have a direct impact into our stress hormones. This causes us
to be more aggressive, irritable, and making our mood and motivation drop to the bottom.</p>

<h3 id="focus">Focus</h3>

<p>Related to our intellectual activity, try to study, or work, and you will also see that having a bad diet will cause
problems with your lucidity and agility. You can see this for example when focusing on a complex task or memorizing
topics, or even a single number.</p>

<h3 id="long-term-diseases">Long-term diseases</h3>
<p>It is not surprise that countries with healthy diets have a higher expected life. Furthermore, there are several studies
that link the effects of eating unhealthy food to different diseases. This of course is not applicable to food, but
other products we drink or inhale. The solution is easy: If you want to live longer, start taking care of what your body
is using as fuel.</p>

<h3 id="recovery">Recovery</h3>

<p>Nutrition has an important role in both, mental and physical. Try to practice sport with a good diet and a bad diet and
you will note the difference and how much it some activities cost or how you are tired after the workout.</p>

<p>As we have seen for concentration, we need to take care of what we provide to our brain, so it is possible to</p>

<h2 id="how-to-fix-this">How to fix this</h2>

<p>Having seen what is causing problems to our health, there should be something we can do about it. These are some tricks
in order to help us with a perfect nutrition aimed to achieve the best performance.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/nutrition/fruit.jpg" alt="Fruits and Vegetables" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Eating seasons vegetables and fruits is an excellent way to discover new and tasty combinations
</span>
</p>

<h3 id="plan">Plan</h3>

<p>When it comes to food, as in many other aspects in life, you cannot improvise. Have an empty fridge and go to the last
minute to the supermarket, and I can assure you that you will probably end up with post processed food and low-quality
nutrients. This is definitely not the way. Another benefit is that with this technique you can avoid unnecessary
products in the supermarket and save a considerable amount of money.</p>

<h3 id="be-constant">Be constant</h3>

<p>This one may be also quite evident, but it is usual that a lot of people start with their diet very motivated. In this
case being constant is of course much more important than the intensity. Define realistic and feasible goals. Otherwise,
in 1 week you will get back where you started.</p>

<h3 id="variety">Variety</h3>
<p>Changing what you eat, while innovating makes sure that you are not bored of the monotony. With this in mind, you can
create multiple combinations and have fun avoiding already prepared post processed foods.</p>

<p>You may be thinking that having to think about what you need to each every day may sound a bit annoying at first sight.
However, this will give you a better organization of what to prepare. Furthermore, one of the tricks is also to take
benefit of the seasonal products and enjoy the flavor of these products.</p>

<h3 id="time-to-break-the-rules-sometimes">Time to break the rules (sometimes)</h3>

<p>Although this seems the opposite of what’s included above, you could have your cheat day, e.g., on the weekend. However,
even if in the beginning you will be probably yearning for this day to arrive, you may realize about the following. The
day after you go for this special day, you will feel heavier and not as healthy as the previous days. Our body is
intelligent enough to warn us about something they did not like and it’s causing our body to suffer.</p>

<p>With time, you will see that this cheat day is probably causing more problems to your body, and you will not ask for it
anymore. And your mind and body will thank you for this.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why you should start taking care of what you eat and why the food may be slowly killing you]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/nutrition/fr.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/nutrition/fr.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Algorand Governance Period 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/algorand-governance-period-5/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Algorand Governance Period 5" /><published>2022-10-13T14:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-10-13T14:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/algorand-governance-period-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/algorand-governance-period-5/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
The fifth period of the Algorand Governance is about to start and there are some changes being introduced in this phase. The registration will close on October 20th and the rewards will be paid once the period ends on December 31st. 
As in previous governances, the payout of the rewards should be on the first week of January and depending on the wallet you use, you may also receive an NFT.
</div>
<div>
<p>
The page where you can connect your wallet is included below:
            <a href="https://governance.algorand.foundation/governance-period-5">Algorand Governance Period 5</a>

Nonetheless, before continuing, it may be relevant to know more about how it works.
</p>
</div>
<h2 id="process">Process</h2>

<p>As described some months ago, in the Governance Period you can vote and participate in cool initiatives that are
proposed by the Algorand Foundation. By voting on the different proposals, you get rewarded. It’s important to note that
during the 3-month period, the amount of ALGO tokens you commit must be untouched. Reducing the balance means losing the
access to the reward. In addition to holding, it is key that you vote for your preferred option. For example, one user
committing 20,000 ALGO and selling 100 ALGO on the last day will not get anything. Instead another user committing 1,000
ALGO and keeping that amount or more will get the reward. Therefore, it is important to pay attention to the committed
amount and just include there what you are sure you can maintain. Nothing happens if you allocate more than the
committed ALGO once the governance period has started on 15 October. The rewards you earn are calculated by dividend the
total number of tokens (70.5 million) by the number of committed ALGOs from all governors. You can also see the
statistics in the following page: https://www.algorandstats.com/governance-period-5</p>

<h2 id="criticism">Criticism</h2>

<p>One of the points that some users have brought is that guaranteeing a risk-free return of 10% (around 2.5% every
quarter) cannibalizes other DeFi projects around Algorand. This was one of the topics in previous voting sessions, where
there were some initiatives to push different DeFi and FutureFi projects, giving some benefits to these projects.</p>

<p>In order to respond to this, one of the measures was to incentivize DeFi users in order to push different projects and
allocate 7M ALGO tokens to DeFi governors. This was the option the Governance Foundation supported in the last
Governance period.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/algorand_5/timeline.jpg" alt="Steps" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">The different 4 steps can be defined above for the fifth period
</span>
</p>

<h2 id="key-projects">Key projects</h2>
<p>As you may recall from this article, the main 3 pillars of the Algorand usage are:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Payments</li>
  <li>NFTs</li>
  <li>Stablecoins</li>
</ul>

<p>Most of the projects built on the Algorand network are related to DeFi and some of them
have been also developed thanks to grants coming the Algorand foundation. Knowing the most important topics, it’s also
the moment to talk about the most popular projects. Some of the most well-known projects using the Algorand network are
the following</p>

<h3 id="1-tinyman">1. Tinyman</h3>

<p>Tinyman is a decentralized exchange where swappers trade different assets and poolers provide liquidity to the liquidity
pools. What’s the objective of doing so? In this DEX, Poolers get a part of the fees that swappers pay when exchanging
the different tokens.</p>

<p><a href="https://tinyman.org/">Tinyman</a></p>

<h3 id="2-folks-finance">2. Folks Finance</h3>
<p>Folks Finance is built on top of the Algorand chain and it’s used to grant users the possibility
lend and borrow assets in this platform. One of the benefits of this platform is that users can still participate in the
Algorand governance session without renouncing to the liquidity. This is achieved with an ALGO token twin called gALGO
with a 1 to 1 equivalent.</p>

<p><a href="https://folks.finance/">Folks Finance</a></p>

<h3 id="3-algofi">3. AlgoFI</h3>
<p>AlgoFi is also a decentralized exchange and a lending protocol. By lending different assets, the owners can
get rewarded with some interest. The borrowers of these assets deposit some assets as collateral. One of the advantages
of this is that even if used as collateral, the ALGO tokens can be committed to the Algorand Governance.</p>

<p><a href="AlgoFI">AlgoFI</a></p>

<h3 id="4-algoswap">4. AlgoSwap</h3>
<p>AlgoSwap is another decentralized exchange which can be integrated into different dApps with just a few
lines of code. This makes it a great integration tool enabling users to build their DEX platforms with minimum effort.</p>

<p><a href="https://algopay.finance/algoswap/">AlgoFI</a></p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/algorand_5/folks_finance.jpg" alt="Folks Finance" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Due to its innovation, Folks Finance is one of the key stars supported by the Algorand Foundation
</span>
</p>

<h2 id="wallets">Wallets</h2>
<p>Continuing with the next steps and the Governance process, it is time to focus on how to store our ALGO
tokens. As you have seen, there are many projects around Algorand and many ways to commit your ALGO Tokens. Some of the
most popular wallets out there are:</p>

<h3 id="a-myalgo">a) MyAlgo</h3>
<p>MyAlgo is one of the most intuitive wallets out there, with some advance features such as signing multiple
transactions at the same time or transaction-grouping.</p>

<p><a href="https://wallet.myalgo.com/">MyAlgo</a></p>

<h3 id="b-perawallet">b) PeraWallet</h3>
<p>PeraWallet is a decentralized wallet, easily used in both mobile and laptops, with ledger support too.
It’s easy to access the transaction history, holdings or NFTs.</p>

<p><a href="https://perawallet.app/">PeraWallet</a></p>

<h3 id="c-algosigner">c) AlgoSigner</h3>
<p>AlgoSigner an extension for Chrome that can be used as an Algorand wallet. It lets users approve and
sign transactions that are generated by Algorand applications. The benefit of AlgoSigner is that there is you can grant
access to different dApps without giving them access you your keys and that it can be integrated into easily into DEX.</p>

<p><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/algosigner/kmmolakhbgdlpkjkcjkebenjheonagdm">AlgoSigner</a></p>

<p>Related to getting ALGO, it is in most popular centralized exchanges such as Binance, Coinbase or Kraken. Therefore, it
should not be a problem to get it you’re your preferred platform. As with crypto, it is recommended that as soon as you
get it, if you are not trading it, you move it to one of the mentioned wallets in order to participate in the Goverance
period or in your cold wallet.</p>

<h2 id="measures--other">Measures &amp; Other</h2>
<p>Related to the voting, the measures that will be proposed in the upcoming period are still not now
and nothing is expected until November. Nonetheless, considering the latest proposals and ongoing projects around
Algorand, it would not surprise that the voting sessions go in the direction of boosting the power of DeFi and FutureFi.</p>

<p>In this governance period, it seems that there are some people sending some small amounts to the different governors.
They include some messages and are not coming from the official Algorand Foundation. The most important thing is not to
click on them because they are spam messages.</p>

<h2 id="participation">Participation</h2>
<p>Taking part in the Governance period, you are contributing to the future of finance. Algorand, one of the most sustainable chains, is proof of stake, and we have
seen the positive impact in the environment that this mechanism has with the Ethereum Merge. It’s also one of the
reasons for being named the Green Blockchain- Other benefits of the Algorand network are the low fees, speed and its
zero downtime, which cannot be said from other networks such as Solana. Therefore, if you want to be part of this
adventure, don’t forget to commit your ALGO before the deadline on 21 October.</p>

<p>Once the voting session is published, you
should not forget to vote, since just users who voted for any of the options will be eligible to receive a stake of the
70.5 million ALGO tokens to be paid on beginning of January</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Algorand Governance Period is about to start. These are some of the most important topics to consider, including some of the most important wallets in this blockchain]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/algorand_5/algorand.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/algorand_5/algorand.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">The Ethereum Merge Explained</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-ethereum-merge-explained/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ethereum Merge Explained" /><published>2022-09-18T14:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-18T14:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-ethereum-merge-explained</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-ethereum-merge-explained/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
In the last weeks we have seen a lot of excitement coming from different places in regards to  what’s called the event of the year in crypto world. I’m
referring to Ethereum and what is not a gamechanger just for Ethereum itself for the whole crypto industry as as result of the big changes that this fork carries.
</div>

<p>The Ethereum Merge has been one of the most ambitious and awaited changes in the network. Long-awaited because there
first plans about this software upgrade data back to 2014, and the upgrade occurred on 15 September 2022, almost 10
years later. The fork also opens new opportunities for the usage of blockchain in different components and standards,
due to the problems and inefficiency that the new consensus mechanism brings.</p>

<p>Furthermore, although Ethereum is the already network with more utilities and business cases, this can boost the
commerciality of this network and push it to thew next level with the entry of new players.</p>

<p>Besides, this event can be the one that turn the tables in order to recover the lost trust and see that there are
different projects trying to enhance the utilities of the different chains</p>

<p>Nonetheless, even if some sources said that this Merge will fix some of the known issues in the Ethereum network, they
don’t have any impact on them. We will need to see additional upgrades in order to see if these topics are modified.</p>

<p>This is basically the points that this network upgrade entails and what, in order to avoid misunderstandings, problems
that are not tackled with this modification in this software change.</p>

<h2 id="what-are-the-main-changes">What are the main changes?</h2>

<h3 id="1-energy">1. Energy</h3>

<p>Switching from the Proof of Work to Proof Stake protocols means that the energy consumption will decline approximated by
99%.</p>

<p>Energy waste and efficiency has been one of the topics that some crypto detractors such as regulators have included as
one of the disadvantages of the growth of blockchain.</p>

<p>Several have criticized some of the PoW blockchains such as Bitcoin or Ethereum because of the negative environmental
impact they had and the excessive usage of energy to validate the transactions in the network.</p>

<p>Some of the most known - and controversial - usages of Ethereum is the minting of NFTs using ERC-721. This change will
have a much better impact on the volatile market of the NFTs because of the drop of the energy usage to mint them,
enabling the growth of this business.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/ethereum/sustainable.jpeg" alt="Thinking about the future" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Regardless of the other technical details, it is a great milestone to reduce the energy usage on around 99% thanks to the Merge
</span>
</p>

<h3 id="2-more-democratic-rewards">2. More democratic rewards</h3>

<p>Apart from the change in the energy efficiency, the switch to Proof of Work also means that via this mechanism, the
staking rewards for validating and securing the network that were reserved for those with powerful computers is over.</p>

<p>Please note you will need at least 32 ETH (around 48,000 USD at the time of writing) plus the computer to perform
staking on your own. However, there are more used options such as liquidity staking, using ERC-20, where you may
allocate part of your ETH tokens to a pool (in order to reach the minimum of 32 ETH).</p>

<p>In case you are not happy with none of these options, despite not being that popular, another possibility in order to
receive staking rewards for your share are staking them via a centralized exchange.</p>

<p>As with all these cases, please do your own research before delegating your tokens.</p>

<h3 id="3-price-and-value">3. Price and value</h3>

<p>Price and value must not be understood in the wrong way. This is also not a good or bad thing coming from the Merge.</p>

<p>Although the Merge has been waited for years, the truth is that Ether has lost around 60% of its market value during 2022.
However, if we use the CMC 200 index as reference, the price drop is also aligned with the drop in the CMC 200
index.</p>

<p>On the other hand, for instance, it had an increase of 100%, when the prices went in August from 1,000 USD to 2,000 USD.</p>

<p>As discussed in other topics, there has not been a drastic change – upwards or downwards- in Ethereum’s price on the
date the fork was completed. As with other assets, the price is already discounted when these big events occur. As you
may have noticed, there were a surge on the price in the months prior to the Merge.</p>

<p>In the future, Ethereum will be transition to a deflationary asset. Before the Merge and with the PoW, 13,000 new Ether
tokens were issued on a daily basis. The change changes this and from 13,000 we will see around 1,600 Ether tokens per
day.</p>

<p>The less tokens there are, the higher the price should be for Ether tokens, being an alternative deflationary asset.</p>

<h2 id="aspects-that-remain-unchanged">Aspects that remain unchanged</h2>

<p>Probably some of the most common topics when it comes to Ethereum are fees. The bad news is that the logic for these remains unchanged.
These are other problems that Ethereum Merge does not solve or haven’t been modified with the Merge.</p>

<h3 id="1-fees">1. Fees</h3>

<p>“The fork will definitely make the gas fees cheaper.” This is wrong and the changes that occurred in the network did not
have any consequences on the fees that must be paid on each blockchain transaction to reward the validators of the
transactions occurring in the chain. The last change in the network that affected how the Wei that must be paid per
transaction was the London Upgrade in 2021.</p>

<h3 id="2-speed">2. Speed</h3>

<p>Related to the blockchain dilemma, the Merge does not make the speed faster neither increases that number of
transactions that can be processed per minute. There may be a slight improvement in the speed, but it will be
unnoticeable for users. For the speed changes, we will have to wait in case this modification arrives one day.</p>

<h2 id="key-takeaways">Key takeaways</h2>

<p>There has been a lot of hype because of this Merge milestone, and it has been waited for some time now. Due to all the
news surrounding this topic for the last year, these are the main facts that we can say in order to conclude and see how
this topic evolves.</p>

<h3 id="environmental-impact">Environmental impact</h3>

<p>This is definitely the biggest changes and main advantage of the software upgrade. Not just related to the current energy crisis, this is a huge step in order to protect our
planet with a more sensible and responsible usage of electricity. This can be a key milestone for a reaching
sustainability in the crypto industry (although for example there are no plans for example for Bitcoin and switching
from PoW to PoS in this case) because of the new possibilities on the different networks and standards that enables.</p>

<h3 id="staking-for-all-users">Staking for all users</h3>

<p>While validating and securing the network was an action reserved for those with more computing power, hence the rewards
were just for them, the change to PoS means that all of us can take part securing the transactions and getting rewarded
for the Ether tokens we use to achieve that.</p>

<h3 id="commercial-impact">Commercial impact</h3>

<p>Having reduced the energy usage and improving the energy efficiency has also opened new ideas to Ethereum, which already had many apps
around this ecosystem. Furthermore, this is not just important to Ethereum, but other chains, and it also means that the
evolution of the different blockchains will lead to a better experience for the users and more business ideas that some
years ago were unthinkable because of sustainable issues.</p>

<hr />

<p>Having explained the most important changes and having also denied things that the Merge does not change, it’s true that some of these changes can boost Ethereum and the crypto sector. 
At the same time, it cannot be denied that some users have been disappointed because they were expecting much more. Time will tell.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The changes that the Ethereum Merge, including the impact they create and what aspects are not modified with this fork in the network]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/ethereum/eth.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/ethereum/eth.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="enn"><title type="html">10 Benefits of HIIT</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/09/11/benefits_10_hiit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 Benefits of HIIT" /><published>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/09/11/benefits_10_hiit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/09/11/benefits_10_hiit/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        In the past years, there is being a surge on sport and health topics. We
        look more and more for some alternatives or variations of the most classic
        sports that keep evolving throughout years. One of the activities that has
        been quite trendy in the last years it’s HIIT.
    </p>
</div>

<p>
    In this post we will discuss how HIIT - High Intensity Interval Training
    works and how it may help you in your day-to-day life.
</p>
<p>
    The different advantages that HIIT has goes from mere performance
    improvement to health improvements. However, there is more than this and
    HIIT also includes some advantages to our well-being and the enjoyment of
    our activities.
</p>
<p>
    But before we start describing, in case you don’t know, what’s HITT and how
    it works?
</p>
<p>
    In simple terms, HIIT is the combination of both:
</p>
<ul>
    - High intensity intervals
</ul>
<ul>
    - Low intensity intervals that are used to recover from the high intensity
</ul>
<p>
    By high intensity intervals, it’s meant by those intervals where the heart
    rate capacity is equal to at least 80% of the maximum heart rate.
</p>
<p>
    The frequency of the high and low intensity may vary, and it can go from to
    2:1 or 1:2
</p>
<p>
    An example may be clearer if we add some numbers.
</p>
<p>
    Let’s imagine runner who performs the following steps:
</p>
<ul>
    1. 60-seconds sprint
</ul>
<ul>
    2. 120-second Low intensity jogging
</ul>
<ul>
    3. 60-seconds sprint
</ul>
<ul>
    4. 120-second Low intensity jogging
</ul>
</li>
<p>
    And like that you can play with different variations. For example, sprints
    of 60 seconds and rest 60 seconds, etc.
</p>
<p>
    The goal of the HIIT session is to give everything and end exhausted at the
    end of it.
</p>
<p>
    Starting with HIIT means also getting out of your comfort zone and it may
    be challenging for you at the beginning. Nevertheless, being progressive
    and reading the following benefits will for sure help you go to the next
    level.
</p>
<h3>
    1. Lack of time
</h3>
<p>
    We would like to have days of 48 hours, but this is not possible. With HIIT
    you can reduce your sessions to more than half of it. From a 60-minute
    low-intensity session, you can switch it to a 15/20-minute HIIT session.
</p>
<p>
    A 20-minute session will be enough to complete your daily activity and
    objectives.
</p>
<p>
    In other words, the usual 45 minutes sessions you have can be to just
    20-minute session. The minutes you don’t use can be used for any other
    thing.
</p>
<p>
    Even if shorter duration, you will with a higher sensation of completeness
    and job well done because of the work that your body does after the work.
</p>
<p>
    Further, there is no need to do these sessions every day. Since in every
    session, a lot of stress is added to your organs and muscles, 3 or 4 HITT
    sessions will be more than enough for you and your body. We will later see
    the post-process.
</p>
<p>
    This benefit is a good argument to tell people who complain that they don’t
    do any exercise because they have too many things to do and no time. Most
    of us should be able to take 20 minutes from other daily tasks.
</p>
<h3>
    2. Get fit
</h3>
<p>
    As we have described above, if you have been without performing sport for
    some time, you should start slowly with HIIT. At the same time, this is a
    great technique to get in shape quite quickly compared to low-intensity
    trainings. Therefore, it may be a good idea in case you have joined a race
    in a few months, and you should prepare it beforehand.
</p>
<h3>
    3. Multiple variations
</h3>
<p>
    Although HIIT is more associated to jogging, many sports and activities can
    be applied to this technique. This means that you can enrich your portfolio
    of exercises and increase the fun.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/diverse_hiit.jpg" alt="Cientos de maneras">
    <span class="caption text-muted">El HIIT no es exclusivo de trotar, y puedes experimentarlo de muchas maneras
</span>
</p>
<p>
    Some of the most important activies are:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Swimming
    </li>
    <li>
        Cycling
    </li>
    <li>
        Weight training
    </li>
    <li>
        Rope jumping
    </li>
    <li>
        Rowing
    </li>
    <li>
        Burpees
    </li>
    <li>
        Dancing
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
</p>
<p>
    As it occurs with nutrition, having a diversified set of exercises will
    help you not get bored and opening your mind to practice new ones.
</p>
<h3>
    4. Muscular mass
</h3>
<p>
    For professionals who compete, you may have heard different opinions about
    the different exercises and planning. Some argue that with running, they
    may lose part of their muscular mass that they have gained.
</p>
<p>
    The benefit of HIIT, linked also to the duration is that you can achieve
    the following:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Reduce the body fat
    </li>
    <li>
        Maintain the muscular mass
    </li>
    <li>
        Increase the muscular mass in the legs
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Another example is if in the Olympics or you have a look at the bodies of
    different sports.
</p>
<p>
    If you have a look at the bodies of marathon runners or long-distance
    cyclists you may see very thin athletes with low fat, but also low muscular
    mass except for the legs. The reason is that when performing these long-duration activities, the
    glucogen reserves are empty and the body starts taking energy from: fat and
    lipids.
</p>
<p>
    For that reason, HIIT is a clear win-win solution and the reason for being
    the preferred choice for many athletes.
</p>
<h3>
    5. Metabolism
</h3>
<p>
    High Intense Interval Training is also called metabolic booster. The reason is that practicing HIIT
    produces a considerable acceleration in the metabolism of our body. But why
    is that? Due to the work that is performed, our body is pushed to the next
    level. Our body is clever enough and demands a bigger amount of oxygen to
    provide to our organs: heart, lungs, etc. However, it is not that the only
    reason only.
</p>
<p>
    Apart from that, some components that were broken in the exercise must be
    restored and the energy that must be used to recover these proteins,
    tendons, etc., in the recovery phase is why our body keeps working even if
    we are in our sofa.
</p>
<p>
    This process last around 48 hours and that’s why during this time, our body
    keeps burning calories. This is another reason for just having to perform
    this activity 3-4 times per week.
</p>
<h3>
    6. Better performance
</h3>
<p>
    Depending on the activity, some parts of our body will be development.
    However, HIIT has a great impact in the performance, and you may see
    improvements in the following factors:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Speed
    </li>
    <li>
        Agility
    </li>
    <li>
        Power
    </li>
    <li>
        Resistance
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    If you practice HIIT you may have noticed that your performance in other
    sports such as swimming or cycling has also improved.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/cycling.jpg" alt="Useful for other sports">
    <span class="caption text-muted">HIIT can boost your VO2 Max levels that can be very beneficial for sports such as cycling</span>
</p>
<p>
    One common thin with these sports is the VO2 max effectiveness. VO2 max
    measures the efficiency that your body uses the oxygen while performing
    your activity. Higher VO2 Max higher performance. There is a story back to
    the times of when triathlons were created in 1970 and who would win?
    Runners, swimmers, or cyclists? Some said that cyclists would be the
    winners because back then Eddy Merckx had the highest VO2 levels.
</p>
<h2>
    7. Heart
</h2>
<p>
    Not everything must be fun and performance. One of the most important
    characteristics is related to our health. If you suffer from health issues
    such as high pressure, you will be happy to hear that runners that practice
    HIIT benefit from a much better heart health.
</p>
<p>
    Further, HIIT increases the amount of blood that the heart can pump.
</p>
<p>
    Of course, if you have some health issues, another piece of advice would be
    having some medical checks before starting practicing this technique.
</p>
<h3>
    8. Cost
</h3>
<p>
    Starting with other sports and activities means increasing the fun.
    Nonetheless, in most cases to invest in different articles (bicycle,
    dumbbells, skis, goggles, etc.) If you are already jogging, there is
    nothing that you would have to buy.
</p>
<p>
    This one is obvious, but with HIIT, you will be able to reuse the equipment
    you already have, and this will not mean an extra cost.
</p>
<h3>
    9. Kill the monotony
</h3>
<p>
    Coming back to the duration, being running at the same pace for 45 or 60
    minutes may not be the most exciting activity. If you live in a big city, you
    will not find many tracks close to your place with 45/60 minutes routes.
</p>
<p>
    Since the duration for HIIT is much shorter, this also gives you many more
    possibilities when combining the different routes.
</p>

<p>
    Related to the variations and the monotony, there are also many other
    variations that we may say in other articles. For example, you may practice
    HIIT while doing some trail or as we have seen in other sports.
</p>
<h2>
    10 Risk of injuries
</h2>
<p>
    Finalizing with another health topic, being running for 60 minutes every
    day on the road or any other hard surface may not be the most convenient
    way to keep your knees.
</p>
<p>
    I remember this was my main reason for switching to HIIT some 5-6 years
    ago.
</p>
<p>
    After 20-30 minutes low-intensity running, I had a strong pain in the left
    knee, and I had to stop running. After 3-4 times, I decided I had to reduce
    the duration of these exercises or just stop. I decided to continue but
    compensating the lower duration with a more active and high interval
    trainings. That’s how I started and ever since I did not have any problem.
</p>
<p>
    Every time we run our knees and other articulations may be subject to
    prolonged times of and a wrong way of running may lead to injuries. By
    reducing the duration of our training, we also reduce the risk of injuries
    and conserve intact our articulations.
</p>
<h2>
    What’s next
</h2>
<p>
    In conclusion, you have seen different advantages of practicing HIIT. It
    may sound challenging for you at the beginning, but I can assure you that
    this will not deceive you and will push your body to the next level.
</p>
<p>
    We have found what the different benefits in terms of time, fun, health, and
    performance are. As discussed in one of the points, trying is free, and you may start with a just 10-minute session
    to give it a
    try.
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[From performance to health, what HIIT can add to your daily routines]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>