<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-03-12T19:13:17+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Life of a Modern Man</title><subtitle>Suggestions to help you improve</subtitle><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><entry><title type="html">Shops for the Modern Man - Part I</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/03/06/shops-for-the-modern-man-part-I/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shops for the Modern Man - Part I" /><published>2022-03-06T04:45:13+01:00</published><updated>2022-03-06T04:45:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/03/06/shops-for-the-modern-man-part-I</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/03/06/shops-for-the-modern-man-part-I/"><![CDATA[<h2 class="section-heading">Introduction</h2>
<p>In this article we are changing completely the topic and we are introducing 4 online shops where modern men can go for shopping and find the next essential item for their daily activities.</p>
<p>The shops listed here have been included since they are international, and they should be accessible to all or most visitors around the world.&nbsp; They have been on business for several years and apart from the quality, you should always expect a top-notch customer service.</p>
<p>The list has been prepared with the utmost care based on my experience after so many years of shopping in these stores.</p>
<h2 class="section-heading"><a href="https://www.mrporter.com/">Mr Porter</a></h2>
<p>We start the list with a company that was created from to the Net a Porter group, focused on the men apparel. Some years ago, the Net-a-Porter group merged with Yoox and that&rsquo;s why you will see in this page some articles that were available at Mr Porter in previous seasons.</p>
<p>Mr Porter is an online retailer for men fashion. Since the need to put emphasis on the digital world, the application and the website are top quality. They have multiple brands of the most recognizable brands in the world and every year they add new brands (whether they are newcomers to the industry or old players).</p>
<p>Since a few years, they have their own brand: Mr Porter which offers a good quality for the price. Needless to say, that the designs and quality are of the same standards of the other brands listed in this site.</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/stores/mp/mrp.jpg" alt="Unique design">
<span class="caption text-muted">Both website and application offer an outstanding experience</span>
<h3>Key topics</h3>
<p>The most important things to pay attention to for me are:</p>
<p>The exclusive collections just available at Mr Porter. Some of them in the past are.</p>
<ul>
<li>Ermenegildo Zegna for Fear of God</li>
<li>Brunello Cuccinelli x Mr Porter</li>
<li>Kingsman, (yes, the ones from the film)</li>
<li>Tom Ford x Mr Porter</li>
</ul>
<p>Despite starting with a few brands, the portfolio of brands and categories is today countless: shoes, bags, art, watches, or sports are other things that you will see in this store.</p>
<p>There is a section called &ldquo;The Journal&rdquo; which is also interesting, introducing other lifestyle topics such as cities or restaurants. What I also like is to receive the news about what&rsquo;s new every week.</p>
<p>The sale season starting end of December and June is one of the most waited periods of the year for many people. &nbsp;In this period, you can have huge discounts on the most reputable brands of the world.</p>
<h2 class="section-heading"><a href="https://www.uniqlo.com/">Uniqlo</a></h2>
<p>We continue with a Japanese which is very famous in this country, but maybe not that much in other regions of the world. Nonetheless, with their current expansion plans, it may not take long until you hear it about Uniqlo more often.</p>
<p>The retailer from Yamaguchi was founded in 1984 and their focus is on clothes that are basic, functional, have good quality, beauty and they have a fair price. On top of these characteristics, they offer good quality and affordable prices. Who wants more?</p>
<p>The designs you will see in this shop (for men and women) are for that reason not innovative in terms of fashion, but they will be modern classics that will last long in terms of quality and design.</p>
<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/stores/un/uni.jpg" alt="Basic and functional">
<span class="caption text-muted">Apart from these two attributes, they also combine beauty and collaborate with other top designers</span>
<p></p>
<h3>Key topics</h3>
<p>Apart from the essentials, which offer an excellent price quality relation, one of the other remarkable characteristics from Uniqlo are the collaborations they have at almost every time of the year. They collaborate with different artists and brands.</p>
<p>Some of the most remarkable collections and collaboration are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Heattech (Specific technology for cold temperatures)</li>
<li>Uniqlo x <a href="https://www.jwanderson.com/">JW Anderson</a></li>
<li>J+ (<a href="https://www.jilsander.com/">Jil Sander</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>If you a have a store close to you, it may worth checking it. They have some promotions, where you may receive some free articles and you will have to rate them and publish a review.</p>
<h2 class="section-heading"><a href="https://www.massimodutti.com/">Massimo Dutti</a></h2>
<p>We leave two Spanish brands for the final part of this article. Although the name could indicate that the company is Italian, this is not the case. The brand from Arteixo is one of my favorites when it comes to quality and price. Although the products are made in different parts of the world, it is not strange to see clothes and accessories made in Spain, Portugal or even Italy.</p>
<p>Compared to the sister brands such as Zara, it offers a more classic style, higher quality and the prices are just slightly more expensive than the other fast-fashion brands.</p>
<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/stores/md/lis_01.jpg" alt="Moden classic">
<span class="caption text-muted">Massimo Dutti is synonymous of a classic sophisticated style</span>
<h3>Key topics</h3>
<ul>
<li>Limited edition: Around September and April, you may see special limited edition collections with nice designs.</li>
<li>Personal Tailoring: Since several years, Massimo Dutti has been offering a special service focused on suits and tailoring. The quality of the suits and shirts is above their &ldquo;normal&rdquo; ones, and I would suggest going for this option.</li>
</ul>
<p>In terms of leather items, they are also very good such as bags and other wallets or mobile cases. In terms of sale season, although the price is already quite affordable, you may also see some aggressive discounts too.</p>
<h2 class="section-heading"><a href="https://www.meermin.com/">Meermin</a></h2>
<p>Since we are talking about leather items, we stay in Spain, but we close our journey to the Mediterranean Sea. More specifically. we stay in the town of Inca in Mallorca.</p>
<p>This online shop is not about clothes, but shoes. You will be different classic shoes such as: oxford, brogues, boots or buckles at very good price ranges.</p>
<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/stores/me/me.jpg" alt="MTO groups">
<span class="caption text-muted">MTO groups are an original idea from Meermin</span>
<h3>Key topics</h3>
<p>Apart from the quality and prices, something I really like are the MTO (Mate to Order) groups.</p>
<p>For a specific period, there are some specific models available. These shoes will be unique because they will not be available again. The process is based on the crowdfunding model for which the customers decide which shoe model is produced. In order to fund the shoes, the 100% of the goal must be reached.</p>
<p>Please note that since the prices are already too competitive. It is not common that you will see sales or special orders here, as in the previous three stores we described above.</p>
<p>If you prefer to try the shoes physically, there a few stores in the word: Madrid, Paris, and New York. Otherwise, they send order to almost every part of the world.</p>
<p>With these 4 stores we conclude today&rsquo;s story. However, it will not take long until I present you another 4 stores I use and buy from.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="porter" /><category term="uniqlo" /><category term="clothes" /><category term="massimo" /><category term="dutti" /><category term="ford" /><category term="zegna" /><category term="meermin" /><category term="cuccinelli" /><category term="kingsman" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction In this article we are changing completely the topic and we are introducing 4 online shops where modern men can go for shopping and find the next essential item for their daily activities. The shops listed here have been included since they are international, and they should be accessible to all or most visitors around the world.&nbsp; They have been on business for several years and apart from the quality, you should always expect a top-notch customer service. The list has been prepared with the utmost care based on my experience after so many years of shopping in these stores. Mr Porter We start the list with a company that was created from to the Net a Porter group, focused on the men apparel. Some years ago, the Net-a-Porter group merged with Yoox and that&rsquo;s why you will see in this page some articles that were available at Mr Porter in previous seasons. Mr Porter is an online retailer for men fashion. Since the need to put emphasis on the digital world, the application and the website are top quality. They have multiple brands of the most recognizable brands in the world and every year they add new brands (whether they are newcomers to the industry or old players). Since a few years, they have their own brand: Mr Porter which offers a good quality for the price. Needless to say, that the designs and quality are of the same standards of the other brands listed in this site.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/06.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/06.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">DeFi: Anchor Protocol (20% APY)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/02/11/anchor-protocol/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DeFi: Anchor Protocol (20% APY)" /><published>2022-02-11T04:45:13+01:00</published><updated>2022-02-11T04:45:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/02/11/anchor-protocol</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/02/11/anchor-protocol/"><![CDATA[<h2 class="section-heading">Introduction</h2>
<p>
    In the recent years, we have been suffering a 0% interest rate policy in
    our deposits. In some cases, this has been translated even into negative
    interest into some countries or abusive custody or management fees.
    I have been always not happy about this topic, since we are lending our
    money to the banks (in some cases charging us for that money) and with that
    money, they lend it to other customers, for which they charge an abusive
    interest rate.
</p>
<p>
    Although in the past decades there has not been any breakthrough in
    traditional finance (I just think about ATMs and credit cards), for the
    past years a new concept known as DeFi has been introduced and it’s getting
    more traction. Every year, there are several projects related to it, mainly
    linked to blockchains and different crypto currencies.
</p>
<p>
    The purpose of this article is not praising the different benefits of DeFi
    and criticising the traditional finance. The goal is just to show that
    there are more alternatives to depositing the money in the bank, giving us
    a 0% on it.
</p>

<h2 class="section-heading">What's Anchor?</h2>

<p>
    For that, I am showing those who are not aware of Anchor Protocol. What’s
    this? Anchor is a platform that offers both savings account and a lending
    platform.
</p>
<p>
    In this article we are just focusing on the savings account, for which
    depositors get approximately an APY of 19.5%.
</p>
<p>
    The deposits are in TerraUSD (UST) , which is the Terra stable coin. The
    value of this coin is pegged to the USD and there is a mechanism to make
    sure that the value keeps pegged to the UST. There are some interesting
    videos about this algorithm and other projects such as White Whale that
    use it to get additional APY on the arbitrage. You can find addtional references in this link <a href="#z">Useful links</a>.
</p>
<p>
    This means that with a deposit of 10,000 UST, we will get around 2,000 UST
    after one year. The UST is compounded daily and reflected in your deposit.
    For example, in one week, you get around 38 UST with the example above.
</p>
<p>
    Please note that the APY slightly varies and it is likely the case that
    once there are several adopters of UST, the APY will reduced.
</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/anchor.jpg" alt="Anchor Protocol">
<span class="caption text-muted">Anchor Protocol offers a flexible savings account with no minimum deposit and no commitment.</span>

<h2 class="section-heading">How to deposit into Anchor Protocol</h2>

<p>
    We have said that the Anchor works with UST. You cannot deposit fiat or any
    other stable coins. Some months ago, it was more difficult to get UST.
    Fortunately, it is now more and more extended and there are more and more
    different options. The last exchange that listed UST was Kraken. In terms
    of fees, this may be also the most convenient one if you are living in
    Europe.
</p>
<p>
    Before explaining briefly the different alternatives, you will need a Terra
    Station wallet. This wallet is the official one from TerraForm Labs and
    it’s used to manage the different Terra tokens (UST, LUNA, etc.)
</p>
<p>
    There are some Chrome extensions and mobile applications for it. Once you
    have set it up, you will be able to send the UST (or LUNA) to your Terra
    Station address.
</p>
<h2 class="section-heading">How to buy UST</h2>

<p>
    There is an option to buy directly UST from Fiat in the Anchor protocol.
    The service is called Transact and it is displayed in the Anchor Protocol
    site. However, the conversion fees are quite high and there are cheaper
    options explained below.
</p>
<p>
    Preparing the document, I have just seen that there is a new option (more
    and more exchanges are listing UST). This service is called Kado Ramp and
    the fee (2 UST) seems more affordable than Transakt.
</p>
<p>
  <h3 class="section-heading">Kraken</h3>
    <a href="https://www.kraken.com/">https://www.kraken.com/</a>
<p>
    Kraken is one of the most famous exchanges. In this case, the fiat deposit
    is free. You have options such as EUR and USD and you have pairs EUR/UST
    and USD/UST, meaning that you don’t have to convert to another coin to get
    UST.
</p>
<p>
    The withdrawal fee to your Terra Station is 1 UST. The trading fees are
    quite low and the details are in the website. Expect around 1 UST per 1,000
    EUR.
</p>
  <h3 class="section-heading">Binance</h3>
    <a href="https://www.binance.com/">https://www.binance.com/</a>
<p>
    I cannot give my opinion about Binance US. The solution in Finance is
    depositing USD, and you get BUSD (the stable coin from Binance). This means
    that you are losing some part of the USD because the ratio is not exactly
    1:1. Furthermore, you may also incur some transactions fees or exchange
    rate fees if your account currency is not quoted in USD.
</p>
<p>
    From there, you can buy UST with BUSD. In this exchange, the withdrawal fee
    to the Terra Wallet is also 1 UST.
</p>
  <h3 class="section-heading">Coinbase</h3>
    <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/">https://www.coinbase.com/</a>
<p>
    Please note that UST is also available in Coinbase, but this is not native
    UST and you cannot send it directly to Terra Station. You will need to
    convert it (e.g. using MetaMask) and this will incur high fees.
</p>
<p>
    What you can do in Coinbase (Coinbase Pro for smaller fees) is either buying XLM (Stellar) or LTC
    (Litecoin) due to the low trading / transfer fees. You can send those to
    KuCoin and convert them to another stable coin such as USDT in order to
    convert them again to UST. The withdrawal fee in this case is 2 UST (it
    used to be 4 UST).
</p>
<p>
    In Kucoin there are also SOL/UST pairs, so you could buy Solana in Coinbase
    and send it to KuCoin to the different transactions.
</p>
<p>
    This option may be more expensive compared to the ones listed below.
</p>
<p>
    Another option that exists is buying LUNA (TERRA) in any of the stock
    exchanges and sending it to your Terra Station. Terra Station has an option
    to swap LUNA / UST and the fee is 0.1%. This was the most convenient
    approach when UST was not listed in many exchanges.
</p>
<p>
    What Anchor brings is a new concept for people tired of traditional banks
    and abusive rates. This is the crown of the jewell of the DeFi projects out
    there. Furthermore, this is a more conservative approach than buying crypto
    currencies, whose value fluctuates so much.
</p>
<p>
    On the other hand, this is not a risk-free value and there may be some
    risks to be evaluated:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Smart contracts hack
    </li>
    <li>
        Depeg of UST to USD
    </li>
    <li>
        Losing the Wallet
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    My piece of advice is not putting all the eggs on the same nest,
    regardless of the reputation of the protocol or asset type. In the next
    weeks, I will introduce other DeFi protocols that could be interest to you.
</p>
  <h2 class="section-heading">Useful links</h2>
<p>
    <a name="z">You may find additional information in the links below.</a>
</p>

  <h3 class="section-heading">Anchor Protocol</h3>
<p>
    You can read more about this in <a href="https://www.anchorprotocol.com/"> https://www.anchorprotocol.com/</a>
</p>
<h3 class="section-heading">Terra</h3>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KqpGMoYZMhY" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>
<p>
You can read more about this in <a href="https://www.terra.money/">https://www.terra.money/</a>
</p>
<h3 class="section-heading">White Whale</h3>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ttdYpSmSx4Y" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>
<p>
You can read more about this in <a href="https://www.whitewhale.money/">https://www.whitewhale.money/</a>
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="anchor" /><category term="defi" /><category term="blockchain" /><category term="crypto" /><category term="finance" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction In the recent years, we have been suffering a 0% interest rate policy in our deposits. In some cases, this has been translated even into negative interest into some countries or abusive custody or management fees. I have been always not happy about this topic, since we are lending our money to the banks (in some cases charging us for that money) and with that money, they lend it to other customers, for which they charge an abusive interest rate. Although in the past decades there has not been any breakthrough in traditional finance (I just think about ATMs and credit cards), for the past years a new concept known as DeFi has been introduced and it’s getting more traction. Every year, there are several projects related to it, mainly linked to blockchains and different crypto currencies. The purpose of this article is not praising the different benefits of DeFi and criticising the traditional finance. The goal is just to show that there are more alternatives to depositing the money in the bank, giving us a 0% on it.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/01.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/01.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Emerging Countries for the Next Decade</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/31/emerging-countries-2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Emerging Countries for the Next Decade" /><published>2022-01-31T15:45:13+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-31T15:45:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/31/emerging-countries-2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/31/emerging-countries-2022/"><![CDATA[<h2>Introduction</h2>
<p>The emerging markets had the worst decade since the 30&rsquo;s in 2020 and 2021 was not much better compared to previous years. In 2022, we are seeing some minor improvements in these markets. But is there any hope for countries composing the emerging countries?</p>
<p>Here are some reasons to think that something is changing quietly to some of these markets or regions.</p>
<p>With the current interest rate policies from the ECB or the Federal Reserve, the currencies from the analyzed emerging countries are now more competitive compared to previous years. Further, they have avoided borrowing and increasing their national debt.</p>
<p>While western developed countries (US and Europe) are focused on conflicts, emerging countries have the time to focus on economy.</p>
<p>Apart from these common advantages, these are 5 of the emerging countries that will play&nbsp;an important role in the years to come.</p>
<h2>Vietnam</h2>
<p>An underdog and unknown by many in terms of financial markets, Vietnam is silently growing and leaving some analysts with the mouth open.</p>
<p>Not long ago, Vietnam was one of the poorest countries in the world. However, since the reform of the Đổi Mới in the 80s, the growth has been stellar and there are several reasons to believe that this growth will continue</p>
<p>With the recent Covid and other situations, Vietnam is one of the fastest growing countries. For example, in 2020, Vietnam&rsquo;s economy was the best perform amongst all Asian countries. and its objective by 2045 is to be a high-income country. In order to achieve this objective, the population is expected to grow by 10% during this time, which will of course help with this goal</p>
<h3>ETF to invest in Vietnam</h3>
<p><a href="https://etf.dws.com/en-lu/LU0322252924-ftse-vietnam-swap-ucits-etf-1c/">https://etf.dws.com/en-lu/LU0322252924-ftse-vietnam-swap-ucits-etf-1c/</a></p>
<p>
<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/vietnam.jpg" alt="Vietnam">
<span class="caption text-muted">Vietnam has been one of the best-performer economies in the recent years and it is expected to grow further.</span>
</p>
<h2>Philippines</h2>
<p>By 2050, Philippines is expected to have a population of around 150 million. It is at that time, when it is expected that Philippines will be in the Top 15 economies of the world. Philippines did not grow much until the 21st century. However, the growth has been fast in the last two decades, focusing on the services sector. Due to these reasons, it has become one of the rising tigers in the Pacific region.</p>
<p>Some of the reasonings for this growth is that Philippines has a young workforce, the population speaks English and the household debt that is low compared to other countries in Asia and the rest of the world.</p>
<h3>ETF to invest in Philippines</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.ishares.com/us/products/239675/ishares-msci-philippines-etf">https://www.ishares.com/us/products/239675/ishares-msci-philippines-etf</a></p>
<h2>Thailand</h2>
<p>Not long ago, Thailand was in the list of undeveloped countries, as some of the countries listed in this article. However, since the 80&rsquo;s, its economy grew almost at a rate of 10%. This was until the financial crisis of 1997-1998 and 2007-2008. Ever, since the growth has been not that high, but still acceptable and better than the ones of countries in this region.</p>
<p>One of the obstacles is that Thailand has a military government and the instability has been a negative factor during the 21st century. On the other hand, the strategic plan for the next years, called Thailand 4.0, has put emphasis on the transformation of the country into a more modern country by focusing on hi-tech companies and services. In this new era, the technology and the private sector will play an important role in the country&rsquo;s digital transformation that will push and bolster the country&rsquo;s economy.</p>
<h3>ETF to invest in Thailand</h3>
<p><a href="https://etf.dws.com/en-lu/LU0514694701-msci-thailand-ucits-etf-1c/">https://etf.dws.com/en-lu/LU0514694701-msci-thailand-ucits-etf-1c/</a>&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/thailand.jpg" alt="Thailand">
<span class="caption text-muted">Although the political instability, Thailand has a clear roadmap defined in Thailand 4.0</span>
</p>
<h2>China</h2>
<p>It should not be a surprise seeing China in this list. On the other hand, China was the second-worst performing emerging market in 2021. Some of the reasons are the regulations and isolation affecting some of the most important technology companies and other big conglomerates. The economic has grown more slowly in the past year, raising some alerts.</p>
<p>In the long term, one thing that is common knowledge is that the goal of China is to dominate the world economically. It is expected that China be the number 1 economy by 2030, overtaking USA. China may be facing some conflicts or obstacles that delay this forecast. However, China knows that they should remain prudent since they don&rsquo;t want to be the new hegemony over a devastated world.</p>
<p>They have the potential to do so in the upcoming years. Furthermore, while other developed countries were struggling, they have been using different techniques in the recent years: investment in high-tech, R&amp;D, purchase of debt from foreign countries, etc. There is no doubt China will be in the contenders list.</p>
<h3>ETF to invest in China</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.blackrock.com/cl/productos/239619/ishares-msci-china-etf">https://www.blackrock.com/cl/productos/239619/ishares-msci-china-etf</a>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>India</h2>
<p>While different superpowers are engaged in different conflicts or crisis, the sleeping giant India remains silent.</p>
<p>With the economic policy changes introduced at the beginning of the 90s, India has been constantly growing every year. Furthermore, this growth is expected to continue at least for the next 20 years.</p>
<p>The growth is expected thanks to diverse factors such as population, urbanization, technology, private sector. For example, less than 10% of the companies are public. Another advantage compared to countries in this region is that India has inherited the British law system. This means, that regardless of the origin, all investors have the same rights - opposed for example to China -.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Furthermore, although China is the most populated country today, there are some fertility issues in the Asian country. With this decrease in population in China and the increase in India, it is expected that India will be the most populated country in 30 years.</p>
<p>If the CEOs from the most important companies in the world are from Indian origin, why this cannot be replicated to the different companies in India?</p>
<h3>ETF to invest in India</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.franklintempleton.co.uk/our-funds/etf/price-and-performance/products/27853/SINGLCLASS/franklin-ftse-india-ucits-etf/IE00BHZRQZ17">https://www.franklintempleton.co.uk/our-funds/etf/price-and-performance/products/27853/SINGLCLASS/franklin-ftse-india-ucits-etf/IE00BHZRQZ17</a>&nbsp;</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="emerging" /><category term="markets" /><category term="etf" /><category term="fund" /><category term="china" /><category term="thailand" /><category term="india" /><category term="vietnam" /><category term="philipinnes" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction The emerging markets had the worst decade since the 30&rsquo;s in 2020 and 2021 was not much better compared to previous years. In 2022, we are seeing some minor improvements in these markets. But is there any hope for countries composing the emerging countries? Here are some reasons to think that something is changing quietly to some of these markets or regions. With the current interest rate policies from the ECB or the Federal Reserve, the currencies from the analyzed emerging countries are now more competitive compared to previous years. Further, they have avoided borrowing and increasing their national debt. While western developed countries (US and Europe) are focused on conflicts, emerging countries have the time to focus on economy. Apart from these common advantages, these are 5 of the emerging countries that will play&nbsp;an important role in the years to come. Vietnam An underdog and unknown by many in terms of financial markets, Vietnam is silently growing and leaving some analysts with the mouth open. Not long ago, Vietnam was one of the poorest countries in the world. However, since the reform of the Đổi Mới in the 80s, the growth has been stellar and there are several reasons to believe that this growth will continue With the recent Covid and other situations, Vietnam is one of the fastest growing countries. For example, in 2020, Vietnam&rsquo;s economy was the best perform amongst all Asian countries. and its objective by 2045 is to be a high-income country. In order to achieve this objective, the population is expected to grow by 10% during this time, which will of course help with this goal ETF to invest in Vietnam https://etf.dws.com/en-lu/LU0322252924-ftse-vietnam-swap-ucits-etf-1c/ Vietnam has been one of the best-performer economies in the recent years and it is expected to grow further. Philippines By 2050, Philippines is expected to have a population of around 150 million. It is at that time, when it is expected that Philippines will be in the Top 15 economies of the world. Philippines did not grow much until the 21st century. However, the growth has been fast in the last two decades, focusing on the services sector. Due to these reasons, it has become one of the rising tigers in the Pacific region. Some of the reasonings for this growth is that Philippines has a young workforce, the population speaks English and the household debt that is low compared to other countries in Asia and the rest of the world. ETF to invest in Philippines https://www.ishares.com/us/products/239675/ishares-msci-philippines-etf Thailand Not long ago, Thailand was in the list of undeveloped countries, as some of the countries listed in this article. However, since the 80&rsquo;s, its economy grew almost at a rate of 10%. This was until the financial crisis of 1997-1998 and 2007-2008. Ever, since the growth has been not that high, but still acceptable and better than the ones of countries in this region. One of the obstacles is that Thailand has a military government and the instability has been a negative factor during the 21st century. On the other hand, the strategic plan for the next years, called Thailand 4.0, has put emphasis on the transformation of the country into a more modern country by focusing on hi-tech companies and services. In this new era, the technology and the private sector will play an important role in the country&rsquo;s digital transformation that will push and bolster the country&rsquo;s economy. ETF to invest in Thailand https://etf.dws.com/en-lu/LU0514694701-msci-thailand-ucits-etf-1c/&nbsp; Although the political instability, Thailand has a clear roadmap defined in Thailand 4.0 China It should not be a surprise seeing China in this list. On the other hand, China was the second-worst performing emerging market in 2021. Some of the reasons are the regulations and isolation affecting some of the most important technology companies and other big conglomerates. The economic has grown more slowly in the past year, raising some alerts. In the long term, one thing that is common knowledge is that the goal of China is to dominate the world economically. It is expected that China be the number 1 economy by 2030, overtaking USA. China may be facing some conflicts or obstacles that delay this forecast. However, China knows that they should remain prudent since they don&rsquo;t want to be the new hegemony over a devastated world. They have the potential to do so in the upcoming years. Furthermore, while other developed countries were struggling, they have been using different techniques in the recent years: investment in high-tech, R&amp;D, purchase of debt from foreign countries, etc. There is no doubt China will be in the contenders list. ETF to invest in China https://www.blackrock.com/cl/productos/239619/ishares-msci-china-etf&nbsp; India While different superpowers are engaged in different conflicts or crisis, the sleeping giant India remains silent. With the economic policy changes introduced at the beginning of the 90s, India has been constantly growing every year. Furthermore, this growth is expected to continue at least for the next 20 years. The growth is expected thanks to diverse factors such as population, urbanization, technology, private sector. For example, less than 10% of the companies are public. Another advantage compared to countries in this region is that India has inherited the British law system. This means, that regardless of the origin, all investors have the same rights - opposed for example to China -.&nbsp; Furthermore, although China is the most populated country today, there are some fertility issues in the Asian country. With this decrease in population in China and the increase in India, it is expected that India will be the most populated country in 30 years. If the CEOs from the most important companies in the world are from Indian origin, why this cannot be replicated to the different companies in India? ETF to invest in India https://www.franklintempleton.co.uk/our-funds/etf/price-and-performance/products/27853/SINGLCLASS/franklin-ftse-india-ucits-etf/IE00BHZRQZ17&nbsp;]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/06.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/06.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Achieving Economic Independence</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/26/achieving-economic-independence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Achieving Economic Independence" /><published>2021-12-26T15:45:13+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-26T15:45:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/26/achieving-economic-independence</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/26/achieving-economic-independence/"><![CDATA[<h1>
    Introduction
</h1>
<p>
    This is my first post in this blog, and I would like to address to a topic
    I may come back in the future to people without much time to analyse the
    different financial options for their future.
</p>
<p>
    Nowadays, the future economic outcome is a constant headache for many
    people across several countries: inflation, economic recovery, pensions,
    etc.
</p>
<p>
    There are many options out there for each type of investor: shares, bonds,
    real estate, crypto currencies, gold, etc. Each person has his preferences
    and depending on the age/risk-aversion different options can be multiple.
</p>
<p>
    More sophisticated investors are not discovering anything new about this
    story. If you continue reading, I am focusing on what I think is the best
    for most people, with the least possible risk: the indexed funds or
    exchange-traded funds.
</p>
<h1>
    Passive funds: Index funds &amp; Exchange Traded Fund
</h1>
<p>
    The behaviour for index funds and ETF is similar. Both replicate an index
    or basket of assets, meaning that with one single instrument you gain
    exposure to multiple securities (e.g., S&amp;P 500 companies). Between
    those, the main difference is that ETFs are traded in real-time, whereas
    the funds are just redeemed at the end of the day. The fees for the ETFs
    tend to be slightly lower too. On the other hand, they are subject to
    transaction fees, but many brokers offer transactions on the most popular
    ETFs for free.
</p>
<p>
    For a person without knowledge and looking for long-term returns, I am of
    the opinion of using a broad index and not a niche funds, which are focused
    a specific sector (e.g., eCommerce, video games, etc). Furthermore,
    although previous returns do not guarantee future returns, in the long-run
    most indexed funds outperform actively managed funds. The latter ones are
    famous for high fees, and although they may outperform passive funds in
    short periods, this is normally not the case in the long run. If you want
    to dig deeper, there are some formulas that determine the performance of
    the fund: For example: The Sharpe or Trentino ratio.
</p>
<p>
<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/07.jpg" alt="Step by step">
<span class="caption text-muted">With the constant growth of fundd and the power of compounding you can get surprising results in the long run</span>
</p>
<h1>
    Some examples
</h1>
<p>
    Depending on your risk-aversion, you may choose different funds depending
    on the allocation. People near the retirement age should be more
    conservative. The way to do in this case is focusing on bond funds, which
    are less risky than equities.
</p>
<p>
    A famous rule is the “100 – age” rule. The result should be the amount of
    your portfolio invested on share funds. However, given the current
    situation, if you are young, there should not be problem on having a 100%
    equities asset location.
</p>
<p>
    Below, there is a list with the most famous ones for different profiles.
</p>
<h2>
    SPDR® S&amp;P 500® ETF Trust
</h2>
<p>
    Probably the most known ETF, which tracks the performance of the S&amp;P
    500 index. This is also the one with less expense ratio. It is considered
    one of the benchmarks.
</p>
<p>
    <a
        href="https://www.ssga.com/us/en/intermediary/etfs/funds/spdr-sp-500-etf-trust-spy"
    >
        https://www.ssga.com/us/en/intermediary/etfs/funds/spdr-sp-500-etf-trust-spy
    </a>
</p>
<h2>
    Invesco QQQ Trust℠, Series 1
</h2>
<ul>
    <li align="center">
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    This ETF tracks the Nasdaq 100 index (non-financial companies) and it is
    riskier than the SPDR. Taking into account the returns from the past 15
    years, it is the best performing large-cap growth funds.
</p>
<p>
    <a href="https://www.invesco.com/qqq-etf/en/home.html">
        https://www.invesco.com/qqq-etf/en/home.html
    </a>
</p>
<h2>
    Vanguard Global Stock
</h2>
<p>
    This fund tracks the MSCI World Index (around 1,500 shares). Almost 70% of
    the exposure of the fund is in the United States with almost 70% of the
    fund. The second largest market is Japan with around 6%.
</p>
<p>
    <a
        href="https://www.morningstar.es/es/funds/snapshot/snapshot.aspx?id=F0GBR04SKK">
        https://www.morningstar.es/es/funds/snapshot/snapshot.aspx?id=F0GBR04SKK
    </a>
</p>
<h2>
    Vanguard Total Bond Market Index Fund Admiral Shares
</h2>
<p>
    For more conservative investors, we have this fund, which focuses on U.S.
    bonds (Treasuries and Mortgage-backed-securities). The returns are lower
    compared to the other 4 funds analyzed here, but it is also less risky.
</p>
<p>
    <a href="https://investor.vanguard.com/mutual-funds/profile/VBTLX">
        https://investor.vanguard.com/mutual-funds/profile/VBTLX
    </a>
</p>
<h2>
    iShares MSCI Emerging Markets ETF
</h2>
<p>
    This is an ETF tracking the equities from companies located in Emerging
    markets (China, Brazil, India, etc.) For that reason, the fund is
    considered riskier than those included above. Furthermore, the expense
    ratio is also higher in these funds tracking shares from emerging markets.
</p>
<p>
    <a
        href="https://www.ishares.com/us/products/239637/ishares-msci-emerging-markets-etf"
    >
        https://www.ishares.com/us/products/239637/ishares-msci-emerging-markets-etf
    </a>
</p>
<p>
    Please note that depending on the location, you may not be able to access
    some of these (e.g., most European investors do not have access to US
    funds). However, you should always be able to find similar funds to these.
</p>
<p>
    Some of the ones listed above are ETF or index funds, but you may always
    find the equivalent depending on your preferences. In these cases, the
    expense ratio is considerably low. The more specific you go (e.g. specific
    sector) the higher the expense ratio tends to be .In my case, my preference
    is the ETF because the expense ratios are slightly cheaper and you can
    track the price as in the case of shares.
</p>
<p>
<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/08.jpg" alt="Access to any market">
<span class="caption text-muted">Today there are passive investment funds that replicate almost any available index or sector</span>
</p>
<h1>
    The impact of currency
</h1>
<p>
    Although the USD has been dominating for many years, nobody knows when
    other contenders may appear. For the long-term, the recommendation would be
    to pick up an ETF or fund quoted in your local currency.
</p>
<h1>
    One-shot versus Dollar cost averaging
</h1>
<p>
    From my experience, the most dificult process is starting to invest, making
    sure that is it the right time. For this reason, although there are
    different studies showing that one-shot gives on average better results
    (time in the market beats timing the market), most people would not be
    comfortable dumping all the savings in one single transaction.
</p>
<p>
    For that reason, the Dollar Cost Averaging is the preferred method for
    common investors. By using this method, whatever happens in the market, you
    buy every month the same amount of units/shares of the chosen fund.
</p>
<p>
     
</p>
<h1>
    Tax implications
</h1>
<p>
    The way you are taxed on the returns from investment funds may have a huge
    impact. The main difference is whether the fund/ETF is an accumulation or
    distributing investment vehicle.
</p>
<p>
    In accumulation funds, the dividends received from the fund are reinvested.
    While this event is not seen as taxable for investors in many countries, it
    is seen as taxable for investors resident in countries such as Germany or
    Switzerland. Please consider that may be also other rules: For example, in
    Norway, the tax rate differs depending on whether the fund is an equity
    fund or a fixed-income fund. Therefore, please consider your situation in
    advance before choosing a specific fund.
</p>
<p>
    Thus, depending on the country you may want to look at what options are
    best for you. Furthermore, there are some tax-savings accounts in some
    countries that may be useful to make sure that you get benefited from the
    best product-
</p>
<p>
    Together with the expenses and commissions, taxes may be the most important
    factor eating your total returns. Imagine that you are paying 25% of tax in
    the dividends you receive. You are already not receiving this money, and
    more importantly, this amount is not used for the compounding, which
    reduced considerably the future value of the fund.
</p>
<p>
     
</p>
<h1>
    Where to start
</h1>
<p>
    Now that we have seen the theory, it is time to jump into the action.
    Depending on the location you may have just access just to some brokers.
    Here are some examples where you may start investing in some ETFs or
    investment funds.
</p>
<ul>
<li>
    <strong>Degiro</strong> - <a href="https://trader.degiro.nl/">https://trader.degiro.nl/</a>
</li>
<li>
<strong>Fidelity</strong> -    <a href="https://www.fidelity.com/">https://www.fidelity.com/</a>
</li>
    <strong>Vanguard</strong> -
    <a
        href="https://investor.vanguard.com/investing/transaction-fees-commissions/etfs"
    >
        https://investor.vanguard.com/investing/transaction-fees-commissions/etfs
    </a>
</li>
<li>
    <strong>Investment Brokers</strong>  -
    <a href="https://www.interactivebrokers.com/es/home.php">
        https://www.interactivebrokers.com/es/home.php
    </a>
</li>
<li>
    <strong>eToro</strong> - <a href="https://www.etoro.com">https://www.etoro.com</a>
</li>
<li>

    <strong>Saxo Bank</strong> - <a href="https://www.home.saxo/">https://www.home.saxo/</a>

</li>
<li>
<strong>Charles Schwab</strong> -    <a href="https://www.schwab.com/">https://www.schwab.com/</a>
</li>
<li>
<strong>MyInvestor</strong> - <a href="https://myinvestor.es/">https://myinvestor.es/</a>    
</li>
<li>
<strong>Robinhood</strong> - <a href="https://robinhood.com/">https://robinhood.com/</a>  
</li>
<li>
<strong>Swissquote</strong> -    <a href="https://en.swissquote.com/">https://en.swissquote.com/</a>
</li>
</ul>
<p>
    As discussed above, some of them are just available on certain locations.
    However. You will certainly find one available
</p>
<h1>
    Resources
</h1>
<p>
    These are some of the books or that I have read and that I recommend if you
    would like to know more about this topic can be also found below:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
<p>
    <strong>The Bogleheads' Guidex to Investing</strong> by <strong>Taylor Larimore</strong>
    <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/381355">
        https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/381355
    </a>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>
    <strong>If You Can: How Millennials Can Get Rich Slowly</strong> by <strong>William J. Bernstein</strong>
    <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/21852252">
        https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/21852252
    </a>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>
    <strong>The Psychology of Money</strong> by <strong>Morgan Housel</strong>
    <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41881472">
        https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41881472
    </a>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>
    <strong>The Intelligent Investor</strong> by <strong>Benjamin Graham</strong>
    <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/106835">
        https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/106835
    </a>
</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="etf" /><category term="funds" /><category term="fees" /><category term="long-term" /><category term="finance" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction This is my first post in this blog, and I would like to address to a topic I may come back in the future to people without much time to analyse the different financial options for their future. Nowadays, the future economic outcome is a constant headache for many people across several countries: inflation, economic recovery, pensions, etc. There are many options out there for each type of investor: shares, bonds, real estate, crypto currencies, gold, etc. Each person has his preferences and depending on the age/risk-aversion different options can be multiple. More sophisticated investors are not discovering anything new about this story. If you continue reading, I am focusing on what I think is the best for most people, with the least possible risk: the indexed funds or exchange-traded funds. Passive funds: Index funds &amp; Exchange Traded Fund The behaviour for index funds and ETF is similar. Both replicate an index or basket of assets, meaning that with one single instrument you gain exposure to multiple securities (e.g., S&amp;P 500 companies). Between those, the main difference is that ETFs are traded in real-time, whereas the funds are just redeemed at the end of the day. The fees for the ETFs tend to be slightly lower too. On the other hand, they are subject to transaction fees, but many brokers offer transactions on the most popular ETFs for free. For a person without knowledge and looking for long-term returns, I am of the opinion of using a broad index and not a niche funds, which are focused a specific sector (e.g., eCommerce, video games, etc). Furthermore, although previous returns do not guarantee future returns, in the long-run most indexed funds outperform actively managed funds. The latter ones are famous for high fees, and although they may outperform passive funds in short periods, this is normally not the case in the long run. If you want to dig deeper, there are some formulas that determine the performance of the fund: For example: The Sharpe or Trentino ratio. With the constant growth of fundd and the power of compounding you can get surprising results in the long run Some examples Depending on your risk-aversion, you may choose different funds depending on the allocation. People near the retirement age should be more conservative. The way to do in this case is focusing on bond funds, which are less risky than equities. A famous rule is the “100 – age” rule. The result should be the amount of your portfolio invested on share funds. However, given the current situation, if you are young, there should not be problem on having a 100% equities asset location. Below, there is a list with the most famous ones for different profiles. SPDR® S&amp;P 500® ETF Trust Probably the most known ETF, which tracks the performance of the S&amp;P 500 index. This is also the one with less expense ratio. It is considered one of the benchmarks. https://www.ssga.com/us/en/intermediary/etfs/funds/spdr-sp-500-etf-trust-spy Invesco QQQ Trust℠, Series 1 This ETF tracks the Nasdaq 100 index (non-financial companies) and it is riskier than the SPDR. Taking into account the returns from the past 15 years, it is the best performing large-cap growth funds. https://www.invesco.com/qqq-etf/en/home.html Vanguard Global Stock This fund tracks the MSCI World Index (around 1,500 shares). Almost 70% of the exposure of the fund is in the United States with almost 70% of the fund. The second largest market is Japan with around 6%. https://www.morningstar.es/es/funds/snapshot/snapshot.aspx?id=F0GBR04SKK Vanguard Total Bond Market Index Fund Admiral Shares For more conservative investors, we have this fund, which focuses on U.S. bonds (Treasuries and Mortgage-backed-securities). The returns are lower compared to the other 4 funds analyzed here, but it is also less risky. https://investor.vanguard.com/mutual-funds/profile/VBTLX iShares MSCI Emerging Markets ETF This is an ETF tracking the equities from companies located in Emerging markets (China, Brazil, India, etc.) For that reason, the fund is considered riskier than those included above. Furthermore, the expense ratio is also higher in these funds tracking shares from emerging markets. https://www.ishares.com/us/products/239637/ishares-msci-emerging-markets-etf Please note that depending on the location, you may not be able to access some of these (e.g., most European investors do not have access to US funds). However, you should always be able to find similar funds to these. Some of the ones listed above are ETF or index funds, but you may always find the equivalent depending on your preferences. In these cases, the expense ratio is considerably low. The more specific you go (e.g. specific sector) the higher the expense ratio tends to be .In my case, my preference is the ETF because the expense ratios are slightly cheaper and you can track the price as in the case of shares. Today there are passive investment funds that replicate almost any available index or sector The impact of currency Although the USD has been dominating for many years, nobody knows when other contenders may appear. For the long-term, the recommendation would be to pick up an ETF or fund quoted in your local currency. One-shot versus Dollar cost averaging From my experience, the most dificult process is starting to invest, making sure that is it the right time. For this reason, although there are different studies showing that one-shot gives on average better results (time in the market beats timing the market), most people would not be comfortable dumping all the savings in one single transaction. For that reason, the Dollar Cost Averaging is the preferred method for common investors. By using this method, whatever happens in the market, you buy every month the same amount of units/shares of the chosen fund.   Tax implications The way you are taxed on the returns from investment funds may have a huge impact. The main difference is whether the fund/ETF is an accumulation or distributing investment vehicle. In accumulation funds, the dividends received from the fund are reinvested. While this event is not seen as taxable for investors in many countries, it is seen as taxable for investors resident in countries such as Germany or Switzerland. Please consider that may be also other rules: For example, in Norway, the tax rate differs depending on whether the fund is an equity fund or a fixed-income fund. Therefore, please consider your situation in advance before choosing a specific fund. Thus, depending on the country you may want to look at what options are best for you. Furthermore, there are some tax-savings accounts in some countries that may be useful to make sure that you get benefited from the best product- Together with the expenses and commissions, taxes may be the most important factor eating your total returns. Imagine that you are paying 25% of tax in the dividends you receive. You are already not receiving this money, and more importantly, this amount is not used for the compounding, which reduced considerably the future value of the fund.   Where to start Now that we have seen the theory, it is time to jump into the action. Depending on the location you may have just access just to some brokers. Here are some examples where you may start investing in some ETFs or investment funds. Degiro - https://trader.degiro.nl/ Fidelity - https://www.fidelity.com/ Vanguard - https://investor.vanguard.com/investing/transaction-fees-commissions/etfs Investment Brokers - https://www.interactivebrokers.com/es/home.php eToro - https://www.etoro.com]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/09.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/09.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>