<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-07T10:33:20+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Life of a Modern Man</title><subtitle>Advising in Lifestyle and Finance</subtitle><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">10 Reasons For Having Cheat Meals</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/30-10-reasons-for-having-cheat-meals/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 Reasons For Having Cheat Meals" /><published>2023-05-07T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-07T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/30-10-reasons-for-having-cheat-meals</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/30-10-reasons-for-having-cheat-meals/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="guilty-no-its-a-boost">Guilty? No, it’s a boost!</h2>

<p>We may feel guilty or have bad conscience when having our favorite food on the weekend. However, this meal has been proven, that instead of delaying our progress, it can be a real boost both mentally and physically.</p>

<p>Cheat meals have become a popular trend in the health and fitness industry. A cheat meal is a meal where you consume foods that are typically avoided when following a healthy diet. These meals are usually high in calories, carbohydrates, and fat, and often include foods such as pizza, burgers, fries, ice cream, and other indulgent treats. While cheat meals have been criticized by some health experts for promoting unhealthy eating habits, there are actually several benefits to incorporating cheat meals into your diet. In this article we focus on 10 of them.</p>

<h3 id="1-craving-prevention">1. Craving Prevention</h3>

<p>When you follow a strict diet, it’s natural to experience cravings for your favorite foods. These cravings can be difficult to resist and can eventually lead to binge eating. Incorporating cheat meals into your diet can help to satisfy these cravings and prevent you from breaking the strict diet.</p>

<p>Furthermore, indulging in a cheat meal can help you to feel more satisfied with your diet overall. When you restrict yourself from eating the foods you enjoy, you may feel deprived and unhappy with your diet. This can lead to a lack of motivation to continue with your healthy eating plan. By incorporating cheat meals, you can give yourself a sense of freedom and flexibility in your diet, making it easier to stick to a healthy eating plan in the long run.</p>

<p>It’s important to note that cheat meals should be consumed in moderation and not as an excuse to indulge in unhealthy foods all the time. When incorporating cheat meals into your diet, it’s essential to balance them with healthy foods and to make sure that you are still meeting your nutritional needs.</p>

<h3 id="2-metabolism-boost">2. Metabolism Boost</h3>

<p>When you follow a low-calorie diet for an extended period, your metabolism can slow down, making it more difficult to lose weight. By consuming a high-calorie cheat meal, you can actually give your metabolism a boost, which can help you to burn more calories and lose weight faster.</p>

<p>One of the benefits of incorporating cheat meals into your diet is that it can boost your metabolism. When you consume a high-calorie cheat meal, your body responds by increasing its metabolic rate. This is because your body needs to burn more calories to digest and process the excess food you have consumed.</p>

<p>When you are following a low-calorie diet for a prolonged period, your metabolism can slow down. This is because your body adjusts to the lower calorie intake by conserving energy and burning fewer calories. This can make it difficult to lose weight and may even lead to weight gain over time.</p>

<p>Incorporating cheat meals into your diet can help to counteract this effect by giving your metabolism a boost. When you consume a high-calorie meal, your body is forced to work harder to digest the excess calories, which can increase your metabolic rate and help you burn more calories throughout the day.</p>

<p>Furthermore, consuming a high-calorie meal can also help to increase the production of certain hormones in your body, such as leptin and thyroid hormones. These hormones play a role in regulating your metabolism and can help to promote weight loss and fat burning.</p>

<h3 id="3-healthy-relationship-with-food">3. Healthy relationship with food</h3>

<p>Following a strict diet can be mentally exhausting and can lead to a negative relationship with food. By allowing yourself to indulge in a cheat meal every now and then, you can develop a healthier relationship with food and learn to enjoy it without feeling guilty.</p>

<p>Incorporating cheat meals into your diet can also promote a healthy relationship with food. When you follow a strict diet, it’s common to feel guilty or ashamed when you indulge in your favorite foods. This can lead to negative feelings around food and a cycle of restriction and binge eating.</p>

<p>By incorporating cheat meals into your diet, you can learn to enjoy your favorite foods without feeling guilty or ashamed. This can help to break the cycle of restriction and binge eating and promote a healthier relationship with food overall.</p>

<h3 id="4-mental-break">4. Mental Break</h3>

<p>Sticking to a strict diet can be challenging. Incorporating a cheat meal into your routine can provide a much-needed mental break and can help to alleviate stress.</p>

<p>Following a strict diet can be mentally exhausting, especially if you are constantly tracking your food intake and restricting your calorie intake. Incorporating cheat meals into your diet can provide a much-needed mental break and help to reduce the stress and pressure that can come with strict dieting.</p>

<p>When you indulge in a cheat meal, you are giving yourself permission to take a break from the strict rules and restrictions of your diet. This can help to reduce feelings of stress and anxiety and provide a sense of relief and relaxation. It can also help you to maintain a more positive and balanced mindset around food.</p>

<h3 id="5-performance">5. Performance</h3>

<p>If you’re an athlete or someone who engages in regular physical activity, a cheat meal can actually enhance your performance. The high-calorie meal can provide you with the energy you need to perform at your best, and can help to replenish glycogen stores that are depleted during exercise.</p>

<p>In addition to the other benefits, incorporating cheat meals into your diet can also enhance your physical performance. When you follow a strict diet for a prolonged period, your body can start to feel fatigued and your workouts may suffer as a result. Cheat meals can provide a much-needed boost of energy and fuel to help you perform better during your workouts.</p>

<p>Cheat meals typically contain higher amounts of carbohydrates, which are the body’s primary source of energy during exercise. When you consume a high-carbohydrate meal, your body can store the excess energy as glycogen in your muscles and liver. This can help to increase your energy levels and endurance during workouts, allowing you to perform better and longer.</p>

<p>Furthermore, cheat meals can also provide a psychological boost to your workouts. When you allow yourself to indulge in your favorite foods, you may feel more motivated and excited to exercise. This can help to improve your mood and mindset, leading to a more productive and effective workout.</p>

<h3 id="6-plateauing">6. Plateauing</h3>

<p>When you follow the same diet for a prolonged period, your body can adapt to it, causing a plateau in weight loss or muscle gain. Incorporating a cheat meal can shock your system and give it a new challenge, helping you to break through the plateau.</p>

<p>Incorporating cheat meals into your diet can also help to prevent plateauing, which is a common issue that can occur when following a strict diet for an extended period. Eating what you want will help decrease cortisol levels. Plateauing refers to a state where your weight loss or muscle gain progress slows down or comes to a halt, despite continued efforts.</p>

<p>When you follow a strict diet for a prolonged period, your body can adapt to the changes and become more efficient at using the calories you consume. This can lead to a decrease in the rate of weight loss or muscle gain over time. By incorporating cheat meals into your diet, you can disrupt this adaptation process and prevent plateauing.</p>

<p>Cheat meals can help to increase your calorie intake temporarily, which can shock your body and prevent it from becoming too efficient at using the calories you consume. This can help to rev up your metabolism and prevent your weight loss or muscle gain progress from plateauing. Additionally, consuming higher amounts of carbohydrates during a cheat meal can help to increase your leptin levels, a hormone that plays a key role in regulating metabolism and energy balance.</p>

<h2 id="7-adherence">7. Adherence</h2>

<p>Following a strict diet can be challenging, and many people eventually give up because they feel deprived or restricted. Incorporating cheat meals can make it easier to stick to a healthy diet in the long run, as it provides some flexibility and enjoyment.</p>

<p>Strict diets can be difficult to adhere to in the long term, as they require a high level of discipline and consistency. Many people find it challenging to stick to a strict diet for an extended period, which can lead to feelings of frustration and discouragement.</p>

<p>Incorporating cheat meals into your diet can help to improve adherence by providing a sense of flexibility and balance. When you allow yourself to indulge in your favorite foods from time to time, you are less likely to feel deprived or restricted by your diet. This can make it easier to stick to your healthy eating plan in the long term.</p>

<p>Furthermore, incorporating cheat meals into your diet can also help to prevent binge eating or overeating. When you restrict yourself too much or for too long, you may experience intense cravings for unhealthy foods. This can lead to binge eating episodes, which can set you back in your weight loss or muscle gain progress. By incorporating cheat meals into your diet, you can satisfy your cravings in a controlled and moderate way, reducing the likelihood of binge eating.</p>

<h3 id="8-social-outlet">8. Social outlet</h3>

<p>Dieting can often be isolating, especially if you are avoiding social events due to the temptation of unhealthy foods. Incorporating a cheat meal can allow you to participate in social events and enjoy your favorite foods without feeling guilty.</p>

<p>Incorporating cheat meals into your diet can also provide a social outlet and make it easier to enjoy meals with friends and family. When you follow a strict diet, you may feel limited in your food choices and find it difficult to participate in social gatherings that involve food.</p>

<p>By incorporating cheat meals into your diet, you can allow yourself to indulge in your favorite foods without feeling guilty or restricted. This can make it easier to enjoy meals with friends and family without worrying about your diet. Additionally, by having a cheat meal or two planned into your week, you can still stick to your healthy eating plan while enjoying a social life that involves food.</p>

<h3 id="9-better-mood">9. Better mood</h3>

<p>Eating your favorite indulgent foods can release feel-good hormones, such as serotonin, which can boost your mood and improve your overall well-being.</p>

<p>Incorporating cheat meals into your diet can also boost your mood by providing a temporary break from your routine and allowing you to indulge in foods that you enjoy. Eating foods that you like can trigger the release of dopamine, a neurotransmitter that is associated with pleasure and reward. This can lead to feelings of happiness and satisfaction.</p>

<p>Furthermore, cheat meals can also help to reduce stress levels, which can have a positive impact on mood. When you follow a strict diet, it can be stressful to constantly monitor your food intake and avoid certain foods. This can lead to feelings of anxiety and tension. By incorporating cheat meals into your diet, you can reduce the stress associated with following a strict diet and enjoy a temporary break from your routine.</p>

<h3 id="10-nutrient-absorption">10. Nutrient absorption</h3>

<p>Consuming a high-calorie cheat meal can stimulate the production of digestive enzymes, making it easier for your body to absorb nutrients from the healthy foods you consume the rest of the time.</p>

<p>Incorporating cheat meals into your diet can also enhance nutrient absorption by promoting the secretion of digestive enzymes. When you eat a cheat meal that contains a variety of foods, your body produces more digestive enzymes to break down and absorb the nutrients from the meal. This can improve your overall nutrient absorption and utilization.</p>

<p>Besides, incorporating cheat meals into your diet can also help to prevent nutritional deficiencies that may arise from following a strict diet. When you follow a strict diet that limits certain food groups or nutrients, you may be at risk of developing nutritional deficiencies over time. By incorporating cheat meals that contain a variety of foods, you can help to ensure that you are getting all of the essential nutrients that your body needs.</p>

<h2 id="plan-the-cheat-meal">Plan the cheat meal</h2>

<p>It’s important to note that incorporating cheat meals into your diet should be done strategically and in moderation. Consuming unhealthy foods on a regular basis can have negative effects on your health and fitness goals. To see the benefits of enhancing nutrient absorption, it’s essential to balance cheat meals with a healthy and nutritious diet, as well as regular exercise and proper recovery techniques.</p>

<p>Overall, incorporating cheat meals into your diet can provide a variety of benefits, including preventing cravings, boosting metabolism, improving adherence, providing a mental break, enhancing performance, preventing plateauing, providing a social outlet, boosting mood, and enhancing nutrient absorption. As with any dietary change, it’s important to consult with a healthcare professional before making any drastic changes to your diet.</p>

<p>However, it’s important to note that incorporating cheat meals into your diet should not be used as a license to overindulge in unhealthy foods. To see the benefits of a boosted metabolism, it’s essential to balance cheat meals with a healthy and nutritious diet, as well as regular exercise.</p>

<p>In order to avoid this, planning is key and one of the tricks could be defining in your calendar just 1 cheat meal per week maximum. Ideally, if on that day it’s when you are very active.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cheat meals are a great way to boost your motivation and help you to achieve your goals. Here are 10 reasons why you should have cheat meals.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/cheat/cheat.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/cheat/cheat.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">30 Tips for MTB beginners</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/30-tips-for-mtb-beginners/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="30 Tips for MTB beginners" /><published>2023-04-19T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2023-04-19T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/30-tips-for-mtb-beginners</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/30-tips-for-mtb-beginners/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="more-investment-compared-to-other-sports">More investment compared to other sports</h2>

<p>Compared to other sports, starting practicing sports like cycling entails some serious investing. Other sports with similar spending could be golf or skiing, but the maintenance and the impact it has in different aspects worth some comments. While most people will think on the bike – and they are not wrong – there are other areas where we should look at to start practicing this fascinating sport.. Apart from the 2-wheel vehicle, there are some tools or accessories that are must. Since most people start with Mountain biking, and this modality requires more maintenance and care compared to road bikes, this post focuses mainly on MTB,</p>

<p>The goal of this article is to help those beginners with some useful tools and tricks that are important when you start. Not just from the initial checks or tools to have, but also the accessories and clothes to wear and what the best nutrients are.
<br /><br /></p>
<h2 id="essential-tools-in-your-routes">Essential tools in your routes</h2>

<p>Starting with the tools and components, here are some steps you could follow to get your tools ready for your MTB:</p>

<h4 id="1-gather-all-the-necessary-tools">1. Gather all the necessary tools</h4>
<p>Make sure you have all the tools you’ll need for the ride, such as a multitool, tire levers, a pump or CO2 inflator, and any specific tools for your bike components (e.g. cassette tool, chain tool, etc.). Some of these tools may be too specific and for these cases, Allen keys could be enough in most cases.</p>
<h4 id="2-check-the-tools">2. Check the tools</h4>
<p>You have the tools, but before heading out, inspect your tools to ensure they’re in good condition and functioning properly. Check that your tire levers aren’t cracked or bent, your pump is working, and your multitool isn’t missing any pieces.</p>
<h4 id="3-pack-the-tools">3. Pack the tools</h4>
<p>Organize your tools in a way that makes them easy to access when you need them. You could store them in a saddle bag, frame bag, or hydration pack, or attach them to your bike with a tool roll or strap.</p>
<h4 id="4-familiarize-yourself-with-the-tools">4. Familiarize yourself with the tools</h4>
<p>Make sure you know how to use each tool, especially if you’re bringing new tools you haven’t used before. Practice changing a flat tire or adjusting your brakes before you hit the trail.</p>
<h4 id="5-bring-spare-parts">5. Bring spare parts</h4>
<p>In addition to your tools, bring along spare parts that could be useful in case of a breakdown, such as a spare tube, chain links, and derailleur hanger.</p>

<p><br /><br /></p>

<h2 id="always-check-your-bike-before-a-ride">Always check your bike before a ride</h2>

<p>Together with the tools, performing regular checks on your bike before a mountain bike ride is important for ensuring that your bike is in good condition and ready to handle the demands of the trail. Here are some checks you can perform:</p>

<h4 id="6-check-the-saddle-height-and-position">6. Check the saddle height and position</h4>
<p>Make sure your saddle is at the correct height and angle for your riding style and body type. This will help you ride more efficiently and comfortably. Adjust the saddle height and angle as needed. The magic number here is 0.88. For example, if you inner length is 87 cm, you multiply it by 0.88, to get a height of 76.5 cm. This is the height of the saddle, starting to measure it from the center of the pedallier.</p>
<h4 id="7-check-tire-pressure">7. Check tire pressure</h4>
<p>Proper tire pressure is important for getting good traction and avoiding flats. Check the recommended tire pressure for your bike’s tires and use a pump with a pressure gauge to inflate the tires to the correct pressure. Depending on the route you may adjust it.</p>
<h4 id="8-inspect-the-tires-for-wear-and-damage">8. Inspect the tires for wear and damage</h4>
<p>Check the tires for any signs of wear or damage, such as cuts or tears in the tread. If the tires are worn or damaged, replace them before your ride. If you fall, also check the bike to make sure that everything is correct.</p>
<h4 id="9-check-the-brakes">9. Check the brakes</h4>
<p>Make sure the brakes are working properly and are adjusted correctly. Test the brakes before your ride to ensure they’re responsive and provide enough stopping power.</p>
<h4 id="10-check-the-chain">10. Check the chain</h4>
<p>Inspect the chain for any signs of wear, such as rust or stretching. Lubricate the chain as needed and replace it if it’s excessively worn.</p>
<h4 id="11-check-the-suspension">11. Check the suspension</h4>
<p>If your bike has suspension, check that it’s working properly and is set up correctly for your weight and riding style. Adjust the suspension as needed, depending on the elevation, terrain, and your weight.</p>

<h3 id="12-plan-your-route">12. Plan your route</h3>
<p>This is  not related to the tools, but also consider planning your route before you head out. This will help you avoid getting lost and will give you a better idea of how long your ride will take. You can use a GPS device or a mobile app to plan your route. You can also use a mobile app to track your ride and share your progress with friends and family.</p>

<p>By taking these steps to initialize your tools, you’ll be better prepared for any mechanical issues that may arise during your MTB ride. Nobody wants to come back walking with the bike in hand, so these 5 steps are to avoid this. Should you not be able to fix the issue, it’s also of the essence to carry your mobile phone and some money with you.</p>

<p><br /><br /></p>
<h2 id="apparels-and-accessories">Apparels and accessories</h2>

<p>When it comes to the clothes, this is not about fashion. Choosing the right clothing for mountain biking is essential for both comfort and safety. Here are some tips to help you select appropriate clothing for your MTB ride:</p>

<h4 id="13-wear-moisture-wicking-clothing">13. Wear moisture-wicking clothing</h4>
<p>Mountain biking can be a sweaty activity, so it’s important to wear clothes that wick away moisture to keep you dry and comfortable. Look for synthetic or merino wool fabrics that are designed to pull moisture away from your skin. Cyclists don’t wear bib shorts and maillots you see in the races for any other reason.</p>
<h4 id="14-dress-in-layers">14. Dress in layers</h4>
<p>Weather conditions can change quickly when you’re out on the trail, so it’s a good idea to dress in layers that you can add or remove as needed. Start with a base layer that wicks away moisture, add a mid-layer for warmth, and finish with an outer layer that protects against wind and rain. You will go through many ups and downs and depending on this you will need to adjust your layers.</p>
<h4 id="15-choose-padded-shorts">15. Choose padded shorts</h4>
<p>Mountain bike shorts are designed with padded liners to protect your bottom and reduce friction while you’re riding. Look for shorts with high-quality padding and a comfortable fit. Don’t do this and your ass will suffer the consequences.</p>
<h4 id="16-wear-a-helmet">16. Wear a helmet</h4>
<p>A properly fitting helmet is essential for mountain biking safety. Look for a helmet that meets safety standards and has plenty of ventilation to keep your head cool. Investing in a good helmet to protect our head is one of the most important things. Riding without helmet should be out of the question.</p>
<h4 id="17-protect-your-eyes">17. Protect your eyes</h4>
<p>Dust and debris can fly up from the trail and get in your eyes, so it’s important to wear protective eyewear while mountain biking. Look for glasses or goggles that provide full coverage and have lenses that are designed for varying light conditions.</p>
<h4 id="18-consider-gloves">18. Consider gloves</h4>
<p>Gloves can help improve your grip on the handlebars and protect your hands in case of a fall. Look for gloves that are designed for mountain biking and have padding in the right places.</p>

<h4 id="19-elbows-and-knees">19. Elbows and knees</h4>
<p>If you are more conservative or you are planning several jumps or very technical areas, yo should also considering adding some protection for your elbows and knewws. This will help you to avoid any injuries.</p>

<p>By selecting appropriate clothing and gear for your mountain bike ride, you’ll be better prepared to enjoy your ride safely and comfortably.</p>

<p>Performing these checks before each ride will help ensure that your bike is in good condition and ready for the demands of the trail. It’s also a good idea to have your bike serviced regularly by a professional mechanic to address any issues that may be developing.</p>

<p><br /><br /></p>
<h2 id="fueling-your-body">Fueling your body</h2>

<p>Proper nutrition is essential for sustained energy and endurance during a mountain bike ride. Forget about it and you will not last much riding. Here are some tips to help you plan and pack food for your ride:</p>

<h4 id="20-eat-a-balanced-meal-before-your-ride">20. Eat a balanced meal before your ride</h4>
<p>Start your day with a balanced breakfast that includes protein, complex carbohydrates, and healthy fats. This will provide you with sustained energy throughout your ride.</p>
<h4 id="21-pack-snacks-for-the-ride">21. Pack snacks for the ride</h4>
<p>Plan to eat small snacks every 1-2 hours during your ride to keep your energy levels up. Good options include energy bars, trail mix, fruit, and sandwiches.</p>
<h4 id="22-hydrate-properly">22. Hydrate properly</h4>
<p>Drink plenty of fluids before and during your ride to stay hydrated. Water is essential, but you may also want to bring an electrolyte drink or sports drink to replenish your electrolytes.</p>
<h4 id="23-pack-foods-that-are-easy-to-eat">23. Pack foods that are easy to eat</h4>
<p>Choose foods that are easy to eat while you’re riding, such as energy gels, fruit, or drinks. Avoid foods that are difficult to chew or require a lot of prep work.</p>
<h4 id="24-consider-the-weather">24. Consider the weather</h4>
<p>In hot weather, you may want to pack more water and hydrating foods, such as fruits and vegetables with high water content. In cold weather, you may want to pack more calorie-dense foods, such as nuts and energy bars.</p>
<h4 id="25-practice-your-nutrition-plan">25. Practice your nutrition plan</h4>
<p>It’s a good idea to practice your nutrition plan during training rides to see what works best for you. Everyone’s nutritional needs are different, so experiment with different foods and hydration strategies to find what works best for you.</p>

<p>By planning and packing the right foods for your mountain bike ride, you’ll be able to sustain your energy levels and enjoy your ride to the fullest. Nonetheless, this is not done when you are done. For a proper recovery, as soon as you stop, eat additional nutrients and hydrate yourself.
<br /><br /></p>

<h2 id="usual-pain-zones">Usual pain zones</h2>

<p>Having talked about clothes and our vehicle, we cannot forget about our body. Mountain biking is a physically demanding activity that can cause soreness or pain in certain areas of the body. If you are starting, ere are some common pain zones experienced by mountain bikers:</p>

<h4 id="26-hands-and-wrists">26. Hands and wrists</h4>
<p>Holding onto the handlebars for extended periods can put pressure on the hands and wrists, causing pain or numbness. This can be prevented by wearing gloves with padding, adjusting the handlebar position, or using grips with more cushioning.</p>

<h4 id="27-lower-back">27. Lower back</h4>
<p>Mountain biking can put a lot of strain on the lower back, especially during long rides or when riding over rough terrain. This can be prevented by maintaining good posture while riding and doing exercises to strengthen the core muscles.</p>
<h4 id="28-neck-and-shoulders">28. Neck and shoulders</h4>
<p>Looking up to see the trail or hunching over the handlebars for extended periods can cause neck and shoulder pain. This can be prevented by taking breaks to stretch, using a handlebar with a more upright position, or doing exercises to strengthen the neck and shoulder muscles.</p>
<h4 id="29-knees">29. Knees</h4>
<p>The repetitive motion of pedalling can cause pain in the knees, especially if the bike’s fit is not optimized. This can be prevented by adjusting the saddle height and position, using clipless pedals with the proper float, or doing exercises to strengthen the leg muscles. The part of the knee you have the pain in may indicate if the saddle is too high or low.</p>
<h4 id="30-feet-and-ankles">30. Feet and ankles</h4>
<p>The repetitive motion of pedalling can also cause pain in the feet and ankles, especially if the shoes are not properly fitted or if the pedals are not properly adjusted. This can be prevented by using shoes with a stiff sole and proper support, adjusting the pedal cleats, or doing exercises to strengthen the foot and ankle muscles.
<br /><br /></p>

<h2 id="basic-recommendations-and-more-to-come-soon">Basic recommendations and more to come soon</h2>

<p>By being aware of these common pain zones and taking steps to prevent them, you can enjoy your mountain bike ride without discomfort or injury. It’s also a good idea to talk to a professional bike fitter or physical therapist if you experience chronic pain or discomfort while riding. Taking the right tips from the start will make sure that you enjoy every pedalling.</p>

<p>As we have seen, we have seen the basic of MTB and aspects to consider in different areas. If you have been riding for years, probably there is nothing new here. However, in some cases, it is good to review the basics and make sure that we are doing things right. Being humbler is always a good thing that in the case of MTB can save us from many problems and injuries.</p>

<p>More advanced tips such automatic pedals, tubeless or anti-puncture are left for the next session regarding this topic. Talk to you soon!</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Sport" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Before starting MTB, there are some things you should know. This post will help you to get started with the right tools and accessories with 30 tips for MTB beginners.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/mtb/mtb_tips.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/mtb/mtb_tips.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Everything about wrapped crypto</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/everything-about-wrapped-crypto/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everything about wrapped crypto" /><published>2023-04-15T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2023-04-15T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/everything-about-wrapped-crypto</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/everything-about-wrapped-crypto/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="new-methods-of-playing-with-crypto">New methods of playing with crypto</h2>

<p>Wrapped crypto refers to a type of cryptocurrency that has been “wrapped” or tokenized to operate on a different blockchain network. For example, Bitcoin is a cryptocurrency that operates on its own blockchain network, but it’s obvious that it cannot operate in other networks.</p>

<p>However, it can be “wrapped” or tokenized to operate on other blockchain networks such as Ethereum. Talking about Ethereum, and after one of their most memorable months, most wrapped crypto assets occur in the Ethereum network. However, there are other networks such as BNB or Solana, that are also very important in the wrapping process.</p>

<p>In the case of wrapped Bitcoin, the actual Bitcoin is held in custody by a custodian, while a representation of the Bitcoin is issued on the Ethereum blockchain as an ERC-20 token called wrapped Bitcoin (WBTC). This allows users to access the liquidity and features of the Ethereum blockchain while still holding and owning Bitcoin.</p>

<h2 id="how-it-works">How it works</h2>

<p>The process of wrapping crypto involves depositing the original cryptocurrency with a custodian who then mints an equivalent amount of wrapped tokens on the target blockchain. The wrapped tokens are pegged to the original cryptocurrency in a 1:1 ratio, meaning that each wrapped token represents the same value as the original cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>Wrapped crypto has gained popularity as it allows for cross-chain interoperability and enables users to access the benefits of different blockchain networks without having to convert their cryptocurrencies into other tokens or currencies.</p>

<p>Wrapped crypto involves the creation of an asset-backed token on a different blockchain network. This process involves depositing the original cryptocurrency with a custodian who holds it in custody and then issuing an equivalent amount of wrapped tokens on the target blockchain. The wrapped tokens are typically issued as ERC-20 tokens on the Ethereum blockchain or as BEP-20 tokens on the Binance Smart Chain.</p>

<p>To ensure that the wrapped tokens maintain a 1:1 peg with the original cryptocurrency, the custodian must maintain an equivalent amount of the original cryptocurrency in reserve. This reserve is audited by third-party auditors to ensure that the peg is maintained.</p>

<p>Wrapped crypto is used to enable cross-chain interoperability, which allows users to access the benefits of different blockchain networks. For example, a user may hold Bitcoin and want to participate in a decentralized finance (DeFi) application that operates on the Ethereum blockchain. By wrapping their Bitcoin and converting it to wrapped Bitcoin (WBTC), the user can then use their WBTC to participate in the Ethereum-based DeFi application without having to sell their Bitcoin.</p>

<p>One advantage of wrapped crypto is that it allows for greater liquidity and accessibility for assets. Wrapped crypto can be traded on decentralized exchanges (DEXs) and used as collateral for borrowing and lending on DeFi platforms. This can increase the liquidity and usability of assets, which can in turn lead to greater adoption and value for the underlying asset. With the recent problems in some CEXs, DEX can allow the problem of centralization. Some of these projects are:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Uniswap: Uniswap is a decentralized exchange that uses the Ethereum blockchain. It allows users to trade ERC-20 tokens, including wrapped versions of Bitcoin (wBTC), Ether (wETH), and other cryptocurrencies.</li>
  <li>Curve Finance: Curve Finance is a decentralized exchange that specializes in stablecoin trading. It supports trading pairs between various stablecoins, including wrapped versions of Bitcoin (wBTC) and Ethereum (wETH).</li>
  <li>PancakeSwap: PancakeSwap is a decentralized exchange that runs on the Binance Smart Chain. It supports trading pairs between various BEP-20 tokens, including wrapped versions of Bitcoin (wBTC) and Binance Coin (wBNB).</li>
  <li>SushiSwap: SushiSwap is a decentralized exchange that runs on the Ethereum blockchain. It allows users to trade various ERC-20 tokens, including wrapped versions of Bitcoin (wBTC) and Ethereum (wETH).</li>
  <li>1inch: 1inch is a decentralized exchange aggregator that searches multiple DEXs to find the best prices for traders. It supports trading pairs between various ERC-20 tokens, including wrapped versions of Bitcoin (wBTC) and Ethereum (wETH).</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="investing-in-these-projects-or-assets">Investing in these projects or assets</h2>

<p>As with any investment, investing in wrapped crypto involves risk and should be approached with caution. However, there are some potential benefits and considerations to keep in mind when investing in wrapped crypto.</p>

<p>One potential benefit of investing in wrapped crypto is the potential for higher returns. Wrapped crypto can be used for various DeFi activities such as lending, borrowing, trading, staking, and yield farming. These activities can generate returns that may be higher than traditional investments. However, it’s important to note that these activities also come with additional risk, such as smart contract risk, liquidity risk, and volatility risk.</p>

<p>Another potential benefit is the increased liquidity and accessibility of assets that wrapped crypto can provide. By wrapping assets, users can participate in DeFi applications that operate on different blockchain networks, as well as access additional liquidity and borrowing power. This can lead to more efficient capital allocation and higher returns.</p>

<p>However, there are also potential risks associated with investing in wrapped crypto. One key risk is the possibility of a breakdown in the peg between the wrapped token and the underlying asset. While the custodian holding the underlying asset is supposed to maintain a 1:1 peg, there is always the possibility of a black swan event or other unforeseen circumstances that could lead to a breakdown in the peg.</p>

<p>Additionally, wrapped crypto is subject to the same risks as any cryptocurrency investment, including market volatility, hacking, and regulatory risk. It’s important for investors to conduct thorough research and due diligence before investing in wrapped crypto, and to consider their risk tolerance and investment goals.</p>

<p>In summary, investing in wrapped crypto can potentially offer higher returns and increased liquidity and accessibility of assets, but it also comes with additional risk. Investors should approach wrapped crypto as they would any investment and carefully consider the potential risks and rewards before investing.</p>

<h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2>

<p>To wrap-up this topic, Wrapped crypto plays an important role in decentralized finance (DeFi) by enabling cross-chain interoperability and increasing the liquidity of assets. Here are some specific utilities of wrapped crypto in DeFi:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Access to different blockchain networks: Wrapped crypto allows users to access the benefits of different blockchain networks without having to convert their cryptocurrencies into other tokens or currencies. This can be especially useful for users who want to participate in DeFi applications that operate on a different blockchain network than the one they hold their assets on.</li>
  <li>Liquidity provision: Wrapped crypto can be used as collateral for borrowing and lending on DeFi platforms. By wrapping their assets, users can access additional liquidity and borrowing power. This can lead to more efficient capital allocation and higher returns for users.</li>
  <li>Trading on decentralized exchanges (DEXs): Wrapped crypto can be traded on DEXs, which are decentralized platforms that allow users to trade assets without the need for a central authority. This can increase the liquidity and accessibility of assets, making it easier for users to buy and sell their assets.</li>
  <li>Staking and yield farming: Wrapped crypto can be used for staking and yield farming, which are processes that involve users locking up their assets to earn rewards. This can increase the returns that users earn on their assets and incentivize them to hold their assets for longer periods of time.</li>
</ol>

<p>Overall, wrapped crypto has become an important tool for increasing the liquidity and accessibility of assets in the DeFi space. By enabling cross-chain interoperability and increasing the number of use cases for assets, wrapped crypto is helping to drive the growth and adoption of decentralized finance.</p>

<p>There are many interesting projects in the world of wrapped crypto and DeFi. Here are a few notable examples:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Wrapped Bitcoin (WBTC): WBTC is an ERC-20 token that is backed 1:1 by Bitcoin. It was created to allow Bitcoin holders to access the DeFi ecosystem on the Ethereum network. WBTC is widely used in DeFi and is supported by many decentralized exchanges and lending platforms.</li>
  <li>Wrapped Ethereum (WETH): WETH is an ERC-20 token that represents Ether (ETH) on the Ethereum network. It was created to enable ETH holders to participate in DeFi activities such as trading and lending. WETH is widely used in DeFi and is often the preferred form of collateral for borrowing and lending on Ethereum-based platforms.</li>
  <li>RenVM: RenVM is a cross-chain liquidity protocol that allows users to wrap their assets and move them between different blockchain networks. It supports a variety of wrapped assets, including BTC, ZEC, BCH, and FIL, and allows users to access DeFi applications on multiple blockchain networks.</li>
  <li>Aave: Aave is a decentralized lending and borrowing platform that allows users to borrow and lend a variety of assets, including wrapped crypto. It supports a wide range of assets, including WBTC, WETH, and stablecoins, and allows users to earn interest on their deposits or borrow assets at variable or fixed rates.</li>
</ol>

<p>These are just a few examples of the many interesting projects in the world of wrapped crypto and DeFi. As the DeFi space continues to evolve, we can expect to see even more innovative projects emerge.</p>

<h2 id="beware-of-risks-and-fishy-projects">Beware of risks and fishy projects</h2>

<p>As with anything related to crypto, Decentralized Finance (DeFi) and Decentralized Exchange (DEX) projects that use wrapped cryptocurrencies can offer many benefits, such as cross-chain interoperability and access to a wider range of assets.</p>

<p>However, as with any new technology, there are risks involved, and it’s important to take steps to protect yourself when using DeFi/DEX projects with wrapped cryptocurrencies. Here are some tips on how to stay safe:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Research the project: Before investing in a DeFi/DEX project that uses wrapped cryptocurrencies, you should research the project thoroughly. Look at the team behind the project, its history and track record, and read reviews from other users.</li>
  <li>Use a reputable wallet: When using DeFi/DEX projects with wrapped cryptocurrencies, you should use a reputable wallet that is compatible with the project. MetaMask is a popular choice that is compatible with many DeFi/DEX projects.</li>
  <li>Be cautious when providing liquidity: Providing liquidity to liquidity pools on DeFi/DEX projects with wrapped cryptocurrencies can be a profitable strategy, but it’s important to be cautious. Make sure you understand the risks involved, such as impermanent loss, and only invest what you can afford to lose.</li>
  <li>Check the contract address: When adding a wrapped asset to your wallet, make sure you check the contract address to ensure that it is legitimate. Scammers may try to trick users into adding fake wrapped assets to their wallets.</li>
  <li>Keep your private keys safe: As with any cryptocurrency investment, it’s important to keep your private keys safe. Make sure you have a secure backup of your private keys and never share them with anyone.</li>
  <li>Be aware of scams: Scams are unfortunately common in the DeFi space. Be wary of any offers that sound too good to be true and always double-check the information before investing.</li>
</ol>

<p>By following these tips, you can reduce the risks involved when using DeFi/DEX projects with wrapped cryptocurrencies and stay safe while investing.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The process of wrapping crypto involves depositing the original cryptocurrency with a custodian who then mints an equivalent amount of wrapped tokens on the target blockchain. The wrapped tokens are pegged to the original cryptocurrency in a 1:1 ratio, meaning that each wrapped token represents the same value as the original cryptocurrency.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/wrapped/defi.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/wrapped/defi.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Sugar: The Heroine of 21st Century</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sugar-the-heroine-of-21st-century/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sugar: The Heroine of 21st Century" /><published>2023-04-08T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2023-04-08T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sugar-the-heroine-of-21st-century</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sugar-the-heroine-of-21st-century/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="todays-big-problem">Today’s big problem</h2>

<p>In the modern diet, sugar is a common element and it is difficult to avoid because it is in practically all processed meals, beverages, and snacks. Although many people are unaware of it, sugar has a dark side and is frequently referred to as the “heroin of the 21st century.”</p>

<p>Similar to heroin, sugar is highly addictive and, if ingested in excess, can have serious health consequences. According to studies, sugar stimulates the same pleasure centers in the brain as cocaine and other chemicals that are more addictive, causing cravings and an addiction cycle.</p>

<p>In reality, sugar addiction has become such a widespread problem for public health. The average American consumes roughly 77 grams of sugar daily, which is three times the daily recommended amount, according to the American Heart Association. Numerous health issues, such as type 2 diabetes, heart disease, cancer, and obesity have all been related to this excessive sugar consumption.</p>

<p>Perhaps the most well-known health issue linked to sugar consumption is obesity. The issue is that some of the “healthy” goods we use may contain significant levels of sugar.</p>

<h2 id="complex-vs-simple-carbs">Complex vs Simple Carbs</h2>

<p>If they are carbohydrates, why others are not as bad as sugar?</p>

<p>Indeed, Sugar and complex carbs are both types of carbohydrates, but they have different effects on our body.</p>

<p>Simple sugars, like glucose and fructose, are quickly digested and absorbed into the bloodstream, leading to a rapid increase in blood sugar levels. This can cause a spike in insulin production and can lead to a rapid drop in blood sugar levels, resulting in feelings of fatigue and hunger.</p>

<p>Complex carbohydrates, such as rice or pasta, on the other hand, are made up of long chains of sugars that take longer to break down and digest. This slower digestion results in a slower and more gradual release of glucose into the bloodstream, which helps to keep blood sugar levels stable and prevents spikes and crashes in insulin levels.</p>

<p>Additionally, complex carbohydrates are often a good source of fiber, which can help slow down the absorption of glucose into the bloodstream even further. Fiber also helps to promote feelings of fullness, which can help to regulate appetite and prevent overeating.</p>

<p>Choosing complex carbohydrates over simple sugars can have numerous health benefits, including better blood sugar control, improved insulin sensitivity, and improved weight management. Good sources of complex carbohydrates include whole grains, legumes, vegetables, and fruits. It’s important to balance carbohydrate intake with other macronutrients, like protein and healthy fats, to support overall health and wellbeing.</p>

<h2 id="pancreas-and-insulin">Pancreas and insulin</h2>

<p>But what is the scientific reason of these bad consequences of sugar? The reason may be in one of our organs, the pancreas. Our pancreas generates insulin, and this promotes the storage of fat in adipose tissue by inhibiting the breakdown of fat and promoting the synthesis of fat molecules. When insulin levels are high, as they are after a high-carbohydrate meal, the body is in a storage mode and will not use stored fat for energy. Instead, it will use the glucose from carbohydrates as its primary energy source.</p>

<p>Additionally, high levels of insulin can lead to insulin resistance, which can cause the body to store even more fat in adipose tissue. When the body becomes resistant to insulin, the pancreas must produce more insulin to maintain normal blood sugar levels. This excess insulin can lead to an increase in the storage of fat in adipose tissue, contributing to weight gain and obesity.</p>

<p>In contrast, when insulin levels are low, such as during periods of fasting or low-carbohydrate intake, the body can switch to using stored fat for energy. This is because low insulin levels allow the hormone glucagon to be released, which signals the body to break down stored glycogen and fat to use as energy.</p>

<p>In summary, insulin plays a significant role in the metabolism of fats in the body. High levels of insulin promote the storage of fat in adipose tissue, while low levels of insulin allow the body to use stored fat for energy. Maintaining a healthy insulin sensitivity through a balanced diet and regular exercise can help regulate the metabolism of fats and promote a healthy body weight.</p>

<p>The pancreas must work harder to produce more insulin to control blood sugar levels as insulin resistance develops. This may result in persistently elevated insulin levels in the blood, which may have harmful impacts on health such as inflammation, weight gain, and a raised chance of developing metabolic diseases like type 2 diabetes.</p>

<p>High sugar intake can also result in significant rises in blood sugar levels, which can trigger the overproduction of insulin. This may cause a sugar crash, which is a sharp reduction in blood sugar levels. Sugar crashes can result in sensations of exhaustion, hunger, and cravings, which can have a detrimental effect on how well you work out and function at work.</p>

<h2 id="problems-and-alternatives">Problems and alternatives</h2>

<p>In conclusion, sugar intake is directly correlated with insulin sensitivity and production. Over time, consuming excessive amounts of sugar might result in insulin resistance and raise your risk of developing metabolic diseases like type 2 diabetes. High sugar intake can also lead to insulin spikes and crashes, which can impair productivity at work and during physical activity. To maintain insulin sensitivity and efficiently control blood sugar levels, it’s critical to keep an eye on your sugar intake and make smart decisions.</p>

<p>Furthermore, high sugar intake has been linked to chronic inflammation in the body, which can contribute to the development of several health conditions, including cancer. Inflammation occurs as a response to injury or infection, but chronic inflammation can damage tissues and cells in the body, leading to the development of certain cancers.</p>

<p>It’s important to note that not all sugars are created equal. Natural sugars found in fruits and vegetables, for example, are accompanied by fiber, vitamins, and minerals that are essential for a healthy diet. However, added sugars found in processed foods and drinks offer no nutritional value and should be limited as much as possible.</p>

<p>To reduce sugar consumption, it’s worth to read food labels and look for hidden sources of added sugars in products. Choosing whole, natural foods and cooking at home can also help to reduce sugar intake. By being mindful of sugar consumption and making healthy choices, we can reduce the risk of developing chronic health conditions and improve overall health and wellbeing.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-solve-the-problem">How to solve the problem</h2>

<p>Starting with governments and policymakers, they can take steps to address the sugar addiction epidemic. This can include implementing taxes on sugary drinks and snacks, improving food labeling regulations, and promoting healthy eating habits through public health campaigns.</p>

<p>Individuals can also take steps to reduce their sugar consumption by incorporating more fruits and vegetables into their diets, choosing low-sugar snacks, and reducing their intake of sugary drinks. Small changes can add up over time and lead to a healthier lifestyle.</p>

<p>Overall, sugar addiction is a serious public health concern that requires action from individuals, communities, and governments alike. By raising awareness, promoting education, and making healthy choices, we can combat the sugar addiction epidemic and improve the health and wellbeing of ourselves and future generations.</p>

<p>This excess fat storage can lead to weight gain and obesity, which in turn can increase the risk of developing chronic health conditions such as heart disease, diabetes, and cancer. Therefore, reducing sugar consumption can help regulate insulin levels and prevent excess fat storage in the body.</p>

<p>By making small changes in our daily lives, such as reducing our consumption of sugary drinks and snacks and choosing whole, natural foods, we can take control of our health and reduce the risk of developing chronic health conditions.</p>

<p>Let’s work together to combat the sugar addiction epidemic and promote healthier lifestyles for ourselves and future generations.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The effects and negative consequences of sugar on our body, in a nutshell. How to avoid it and how to solve the problem.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/sugar/pyramids.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/sugar/pyramids.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Democratizing investment with tokenized assets</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/democratizing-investment-with-tokenized-assets/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Democratizing investment with tokenized assets" /><published>2023-04-01T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2023-04-01T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/democratizing-investment-with-tokenized-assets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/democratizing-investment-with-tokenized-assets/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="tokenized-assets">Tokenized assets</h1>

<p>Tokenization is transforming the investment landscape by making it possible for a wider range of individuals to invest in traditionally inaccessible assets. By converting these assets into digital tokens, investors can purchase fractional ownership and benefit from increased liquidity and reduced transaction costs.</p>

<p>This technology is democratizing investment by making it accessible to a wider range of individuals and providing them with more opportunities to diversify their portfolios. As tokenization continues to evolve, it has the potential to revolutionize the traditional financial industry and create new investment opportunities.</p>

<p>You may be wondering that this tokenized asset is and what is this all about? Here we describe how this process works, the benefits and of course, some topics to be considered.</p>

<p>Before I start, I had this article almost prepared for 1 year, but I did not have the time to finish it. Since I had to work on this topic in the past days, I have taken the chance to complete it now.</p>

<h2 id="tokenization">Tokenization</h2>

<p>Synthetic assets are an innovative way of leveraging tokenization technology to create new investment opportunities. Essentially, they are tokenized derivatives that allow investors to profit from price fluctuations of various assets without owning them. By creating a blockchain record for the relationship between the underlying asset and the purchaser, synthetic assets provide a transparent and secure way of trading these derivatives.</p>

<p>In traditional financial markets, derivatives are used to speculate on the price movements of various assets without owning them. For example, an investor may purchase a call option on a stock, allowing them to profit if the stock’s price increases without owning the stock. Synthetic assets take this concept one step further by adding the record for the derivative on the blockchain and creating a cryptocurrency token for it.</p>

<p>This technology has significant implications for the DeFi movement, allowing investors to access a wider range of investment opportunities and trade these derivatives in a more transparent and secure way. With the growth of the cryptocurrency market and the increasing demand for DeFi applications, synthetic assets are likely to become even more popular in the future.</p>

<p>Overall, tokenization and synthetic assets are transforming the traditional investment landscape by democratizing access to previously inaccessible assets and creating new investment opportunities. As the technology continues to evolve, it will be interesting to see how it is further leveraged to reshape the financial industry and create new possibilities for investors.</p>

<h2 id="asset-tokens-with-equity-rights">Asset tokens with equity rights</h2>

<p>Tokenization is revolutionizing the way corporations raise funds and issue equity securities. By converting these securities into digital tokens, corporations can streamline the fundraising process and potentially reduce costs associated with traditional methods of issuing securities. Asset tokens with equity rights are gaining popularity among corporations as they provide investors with access to fractional ownership of the underlying assets and can be traded in a more secure and transparent way.</p>

<p>Tokenization also offers other benefits for corporations, such as increased liquidity and the ability to reach a wider range of investors. By issuing tokens on a blockchain, corporations can potentially attract a global pool of investors and reduce the time and costs associated with traditional fundraising methods.</p>

<p>As tokenization continues to evolve, it is likely that we will see more corporations turning to this technology as a way of raising funds and issuing equity securities. However, it is important for investors to understand the potential risks associated with investing in these tokens, such as regulatory uncertainty and market volatility.</p>

<p>Overall, tokenization is transforming the traditional corporate finance landscape by providing more efficient and cost-effective ways of raising capital. With the potential to reduce costs and increase accessibility, it is likely that we will continue to see the use of asset tokens with equity rights and other types of tokenized securities grow in the coming years.</p>

<p>The process is like the one used in ICOs. Some of the similarities include the usage of blockchain technology and allowing investors to own a partial of the asset or the project/platform.</p>

<h2 id="equities-bonds-and-these-payments">Equities, bonds and these payments</h2>

<p>Income, such as dividends or interest payments, is a great component of assets and their performance. The idea in this case is that even the entity (exchange, asset manager, etc.) is the one owning the “real” asset, the payments that the broker will get are then distributed to the owners of the tokenized assets.</p>

<p>This may happen regularly in assets such as shares or ETFs, but you will find different cases where the same applies to other securities such as bonds.</p>

<p>Please note that in some cases the broker may charge some fees because of the forwarding/processing the different payments. This will depend on the terms and conditions of the entity.</p>

<p>For example, let’s imagine you own 100 tokenized Microsoft shares. The broker owns the real MSFT shares and will get 70 USD for those shares. You may get less than these 70 USD (e.g., 68 USD= because of the processing fee that different brokers may change. The fee will be also described in the prospectus.</p>

<p>Something similar may happen to bonds. In the case below you can see how the different payments are paid to the holders of the token-based bonds issued by Bitcoin Finance GMBH.</p>

<div class="container">
  <div class="card">
    <div class="card-header" style="font-size: 12px; font-weight: bold; text-align: center;">Token-based bonds</div>
    <div class="card-body" style="font-size: 11px; font-style: italic">
The token-based bonds bear interest at their nominal value at a fixed interest rate of 4.00 percent per annum (base rate). The interest periods for the base rate run from July 1 of each year to June 30 of each subsequent year (inclusive). 
The first interest period begins on July 1, 2019. In addition to the base rate, the token-based bonds are subject to annual variable interest (variable interest). The interest periods for the variable interest are the respective financial year of the Issuer (calendar year). 
The first interest period begins on January 1, 2019. The variable interest rate for an interest period is the percentage rate resulting from the fact that 60 percent of the – to the extent available – profit before tax (excluding the variable interest rate) for the financial year before the interest payment date for the variable interest period is divided by the total nominal value of the outstanding token-based bonds in accordance with the Issuer's approved and audited annual financial statements preceding the interest payment date for the variable interest period.. The Issuer shall calculate all interest (calculation agent). The base rate of an interest period is payable in four equal installments on October 1 of each year and on January 2, April 1 and July 1 of the following year (each an "interest payment date"). 
The first base rate payment is made on October 1, 2019. The base rate payment ends with the end of the term of the bond on June 30, 2029. The last base rate payment is made on July 1, 2029. If an interest payment date is not a business day, the interest payment will be made on the next following business day. The variable interest is payable retroactively as of and for the first time on July 31, 2020. The variable interest ends on December 31, 2027. The last variable interest payment will be made on July 31, 2028. If July 31 is not a business day in a particular year, the interest payment will be made on the next following working day. If the Issuer's annual financial statements for the preceding financial year have not been finally approved by July 31 in any given year, the variable interest will be payable seven business days after the annual financial statements are approved. 
If the Issuer does not redeem the token-based bonds at maturity, interest will be payable on the outstanding principal (nominal) amount of the bonds from the Maturity Date (inclusive) until the actual Redemption Date (exclusive) at the statutory default interest rate. If interest is calculated for a period of less than one year (e.g., in the event of default), it will be calculated to the day using the act/act method.
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>
</p>

<div class="container">
  <div class="card">
    <div class="card-header" style="font-size: 12px; font-weight: bold; text-align: center;">Payment procedure</div>
    <div class="card-body" style="font-size: 11px; font-style: italic">
Redemption and interest payments due during the term will be made exclusively in the cryptocurrency Stellar Lumens corresponding to the subscribed nominal amount of the bond. For this, the EUR value at 12:00 CET (Central European Time) corresponding to the due date of an interest payment or bond redemption will be converted into XLM using the EUR - XLM exchange rate displayed on the website www.cryptocompare.com (or a comparable platform selected by the Issuer as described in Section C.2 of this summary) and then immediately paid to the Stellar address of the holders of the BB1-Token. 
The Issuer will make payments to the person listed as the holder of the token in the register maintained on the Stellar Blockchain at 12:00 CET on the due date. Payments will be made to the blockchain address (wallet) specified in the respective register._
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>With the rise of bonds in 2023, like Eurobonds, and adding the component cryptocurrencies, investing in synthetic assets whose underlying are bonds may also help you with your investment in terms of:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Exposure to different fixed-income securities from foreign countries (emerging countries)</li>
  <li>Liquidity, since they are traded 24/7</li>
  <li>Lower transaction costs</li>
  <li>currency optimization</li>
  <li>currency hedging.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="other-asset-classes">Other asset classes</h2>

<p>Apart from equities and debt shown above, you can tokenize anything These are some of the asset classes you can also invest in easier the moment you have access to tokenized assets.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Real estate: Tokenized real estate allows investors to own a fraction of a property, with each token representing a percentage of ownership. This can make it easier for investors to gain exposure to real estate investments and potentially increase liquidity in the market.</li>
  <li>Commodities: Tokenized commodities allow investors to gain exposure to physical commodities, such as gold, silver, or oil, without needing to physically store or handle the underlying asset.</li>
  <li>Art: Tokenized art allows investors to own a fraction of a valuable piece of art, which can potentially increase liquidity in the art market and allow for easier trading of art investments.</li>
  <li>Alternative investments: Tokenization can also be used for other types of alternative investments, such as venture capital, private equity, and hedge funds. By tokenizing these investments, investors can potentially benefit from greater liquidity, lower fees, and more efficient trading.</li>
</ol>

<p>Some real examples of these tokenized assets are the ones below:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>mIAU is a tokenized stock of the iShares Gold Trust ETF, which tracks the price of gold.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The Mirrored iShares Silver Trust (mSLV) is a tokenized stock of the iShares Silver Trust ETF, which tracks the price of silver.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Mirrored United States Oil Fund (mUSD) is a tokenized stock of the United States Oil Fund ETF, which tracks the price of West Texas Intermediate crude oil.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Mirrored Invesco QQQ Trust (mQQQ) is a tokenized stock of the Invesco QQQ Trust ETF, which tracks the Nasdaq 100 Index.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Vanguard Real Estate Tokenized Stock Defichain (DVNQ) is a tokenized stock of the Vanguard Real Estate ETF <a href="https://finance.mrfreire.net/security_search/security_search_results/VNQ">VNQ</a>.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="wrapping-it">Wrapping it</h2>

<p>Having described these asset classes, we cannot forget about crypto itself.  You probably have Heard about Wrapped Bitcoin or any other Wrapped crypto.</p>

<p>Wrapped crypto tokens are an innovative solution to the problem of interoperability between different blockchains. Essentially, a wrapped token is a tokenized representation of a particular cryptocurrency that is operable on another blockchain. This means that you can take a cryptocurrency asset from one blockchain and wrap it in a token that can be used on a different blockchain.</p>

<p>The value of a wrapped token is the same as the original cryptocurrency asset, but it can be used on a different blockchain. This is particularly useful in the context of decentralized finance (DeFi), where different blockchain networks may have different DeFi applications and ecosystems.</p>

<p>By wrapping a cryptocurrency asset in a token, it becomes easier to transfer value across blockchains that otherwise lack interoperability. This enables a cross-chain DeFi ecosystem where users can access a wider range of DeFi applications and services.</p>

<p>Overall, wrapped crypto tokens are an exciting development in the world of blockchain and DeFi. By enabling interoperability between different blockchains, they are helping to create a more connected and efficient decentralized financial system. As the DeFi ecosystem continues to evolve, it’s likely that we will see more innovative solutions like wrapped tokens emerge to help overcome the challenges of interoperability and drive the growth of this exciting new field.</p>

<h2 id="performance-and-taxes">Performance and taxes</h2>

<p>When analyzing the performance of our asset, taxes also play an important role too. They will have a bigger impact than the fees we may have to pay.</p>

<p>Although in several countries, they will be treated as the underlying asset, depending on the country you live, there may be different ways on how they are taxed, and in consequence, the impact on your final return.</p>

<p>For example, a clear example would be Greece. in Greece capital gains on listed shares or UCITs funds will trigger a tax-exempt capital gain. On the other hand, if you invest in tokenized assets, these exemptions are lost, and you will have to add a penalty of 15% to your realized gain.</p>

<h2 id="risks">Risks</h2>

<p>Tokenization brings several benefits and allows investors around the world, mainly with no resources to access financial markets, to invest almost in anything. However, as you can guess, this has also several risks.</p>

<h3 id="liquidity-risk">Liquidity risk</h3>

<p>While tokenization can increase the liquidity of an asset, it does not guarantee liquidity. Tokenized assets may be illiquid, especially if they are newly issued, have a limited market, or if there is a lack of demand.</p>

<h3 id="counterparty-risk">Counterparty risk</h3>

<p>Tokenized assets rely on smart contracts to execute trades automatically, without the need for intermediaries such as banks or brokers. However, smart contracts can have vulnerabilities, and if they fail or are exploited, it can result in significant financial losses for investors.</p>

<h3 id="volatility-risk">Volatility risk</h3>

<p>Tokenized assets may be subject to high volatility, just like any other financial asset. The price of a tokenized asset may be influenced by market conditions, supply and demand, or other external factors, and may fluctuate rapidly, resulting in significant gains or losses for investors.</p>

<p>Not related to synthetic assets, but just think about the Grayscale Bitcoin Trust shares. For months, this fund has been on the news because of the discounted price is trading, comparing it with the value of the bitcoin it owns.</p>

<p>Of course, when it comes to crypto and the lack of regulation beware of any fishy projects, because they may become scams sooner or later.</p>

<h2 id="a-double-edge-sword">A double edge sword</h2>

<p>To sum up, tokenized assets are a powerful tool for investors seeking exposure to assets that may be difficult or impossible to access directly. By replicating the performance of underlying assets, these synthetic assets can provide investors with the ability to gain exposure to a wider range of assets, diversify their portfolio, and potentially benefit from market opportunities.</p>

<p>However, synthetic assets also carry their own unique risks. For example, counterparty risk refers to the risk that the party on the other side of the transaction may not fulfill their obligations. Market volatility can also impact the value of synthetic assets, as their value is based on the performance of underlying assets. Finally, liquidity risk refers to the risk that synthetic assets may not be readily tradeable, potentially limiting investors’ ability to exit their positions.</p>

<p>It’s important for investors to carefully consider the risks and potential benefits of these assets before investing. Investors should also be aware of the regulatory landscape surrounding synthetic assets, as regulations may vary depending on the jurisdiction.</p>

<p>Despite the risks, tokenized assets offer a powerful tool for investors seeking to gain exposure to a wider range of assets. As the financial industry continues to evolve, it’s likely that we will see continued growth and innovation around synthetic assets, providing investors with even more opportunities to diversify their portfolios and potentially benefit from market opportunities.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Finance" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tokenized assets are transforming the investment landscape by making it possible for a wider range of individuals to invest in traditionally inaccessible assets. By converting these assets into digital tokens, investors can purchase fractional ownership and benefit from increased liquidity and reduced transaction costs.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/tokenized/tiger.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/tokenized/tiger.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Starting and Benefits of Mountain Biking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/starting-and-benefits-of-mountain-biking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting and Benefits of Mountain Biking" /><published>2023-03-16T03:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2023-03-16T03:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/starting-and-benefits-of-mountain-biking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/starting-and-benefits-of-mountain-biking/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-rise-of-the-2-wheel-vehicle">The Rise of the 2 Wheel Vehicle</h2>

<p>Mountain biking, a thrilling adventure sport, is rapidly gaining popularity among fitness enthusiasts and adrenaline junkies alike. The reason for this? There are many but one of the aspects that probably helped push this sport was the Covid pandemic and the lockdowns that we suffered.</p>

<p>With its combination of physical and mental challenges, breathtaking scenery, and the rush of adrenaline, mountain biking is a unique and exciting way to explore the great outdoors. In this essay, we will delve deeper into the world of mountain biking, examining its history, benefits, and techniques, and explore why it is such a popular activity for people of all ages and fitness levels.</p>

<p>Whether you are a seasoned mountain biker or just starting out, this article will provide valuable insights into this exhilarating sport.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-start">How to start</h2>

<p>If you are new or haven’t touched a bike since you were a teenager, getting started in mountain biking can be an exciting and rewarding experience. Here are some steps to help you get started:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Choose the right bike</strong>: Selecting the right mountain bike is crucial. There are several types of bikes available, including full-suspension, hardtail, and rigid. Consider your skill level, terrain you will be riding, and budget when selecting a bike.</li>
  <li><strong>Safety first</strong>: Safety should be your top priority when mountain biking. Invest in a good helmet, gloves, knee and elbow pads, and appropriate shoes. The wrong usage of clothes and accessories can make your ride uncomfortable or in the worst-case scenario, cause you some injuries.</li>
  <li><strong>Explore trails</strong>: Check out local mountain biking trails in your area. Start with beginner trails and work your way up as your skills improve. There are excellent applications and user suggestions out there and I’m sure you will find several in your area.</li>
  <li><strong>Take a class</strong>: This may not be needed but consider taking a mountain biking class or clinic to learn the basics of the sport, including proper body position, braking techniques, bike handling or shifting gears.</li>
  <li><strong>Practice makes perfect</strong>: Practice makes perfect, so take time to ride regularly and work on improving your skills. If you have not done it for some time, consider choosing an easy route the first time, better if you know most of it.</li>
  <li><strong>Ride with others</strong>: Join a local mountain biking group or club to ride with others and learn from more experienced riders. This will not make your routes just more fun, but they will.</li>
  <li><strong>Just have fun</strong>: That’s it. Mountain biking is an exciting and enjoyable sport, so remember to have fun and enjoy the ride. Most people practicing this sport are not there to compete, but just to enjoy themselves and the benefits. Talking about benefits, what are these?</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="benefits">Benefits</h2>

<p>These are some advantages of this sport:</p>

<h3 id="cardiovascular-health">Cardiovascular health</h3>
<p>Mountain biking is an excellent form of cardiovascular exercise that can improve your heart and lung health, as well as your overall fitness level.</p>

<p>While other sports like running may be too harmful for some joins or bones, mountain biking makes avoid these negative consequences. Mountain biking is a low-impact exercise compared to running, which can be hard on your joints. MTB allows you to get a great cardio workout without putting excessive strain on your knees and other joints.</p>

<h3 id="strength-and-endurance">Strength and endurance</h3>

<p>Mountain biking is a great way to build strength and endurance, particularly in your lower body, including your legs, glutes, and core.</p>

<p>Compared to road cycling or jogging, MTB works many different muscles, including your quadriceps, hamstrings, calves, glutes, and core muscles. This can lead to increased muscle strength and tone, which can help improve your overall fitness. IF you notice the body type of mountain bikers, the body is more muscled. Please note that moving a 13/14 kg bike up and controlling while you descend puts of course your full body to work.
###</p>
<h3 id="weight-loss">Weight loss</h3>
<p>Regular mountain biking can help you burn calories and lose weight, especially if you combine it with a healthy diet. This can be a good exercise for people who don’t like cardio activities like jogging. Mountain biking makes the exercise not monotonous and lets you start progressively with no big effort. For example, you may just start with easy and almost flat routes. Thus, mountain biking offers endless opportunities to explore new trails and terrain. This can keep your workouts interesting and enjoyable.</p>
<h3 id="stress-relief">Stress relief</h3>
<p>A few months ago, we wrote an article regarding controlling stress. Mountain biking can be a great way to reduce stress and improve your mental well-being. Being out in nature and getting exercise can help you clear your mind and feel more relaxed. Therefore, this can be a great activity to disconnect. For example, longer routes in the weekends, and shorter routes during weekdays, in your lunch break.</p>

<h3 id="improved-balance-and-coordination">Improved balance and coordination</h3>
<p>Together with strength for your muscles Mountain biking requires a lot of balance and coordination, which can improve over time with regular practice. This is of course not just useful for cycling, but for other exercises that require great amount of coordination like swimming or dancing.</p>

<h3 id="social-connections">Social connections</h3>
<p>Mountain biking can be a social activity that allows you to connect with others who share your passion for the sport. It’s also a good activity to share past experiences, routes and tricks. Either in a group, with your work colleagues or with apps.</p>

<h3 id="nature-immersion">Nature immersion</h3>

<p>Mountain biking provides an opportunity to get out into nature and enjoy the beauty of natural landscapes, which can have a positive impact on your mood and overall well-being. As discussed, before it does not have benefit in your shape and physical benefit, but also helps you fight against one of the most growing diseases of the 21st century, stress.</p>

<p>If you like animals, it’s also fantastic to see different animals that you will never see close to urban areas.</p>

<h2 id="go-ahead-and-try-it">Go ahead and try it!</h2>

<p>In conclusion, mountain biking offers a wide range of benefits that make it an excellent choice for anyone looking for an exciting and challenging way to stay fit and explore the outdoors.</p>

<p>With its low-impact nature, ability to increase muscle strength and coordination, mental stimulation, variety, and opportunity to experience nature, it’s no wonder that mountain biking has become so popular in recent years.</p>

<p>Whether you’re looking for a solo adventure or a fun activity to share with friends and family, mountain biking is a thrilling and rewarding way to get outside and push your limits. So, grab your bike and hit the trails – you never know where this exhilarating sport might take you.</p>

<p>Of course, the rise of popularity had also some negative consequences. The most obvious one, skyrocketing prices for bikes and accessories and in several cases long queues when buying bikes. However, this is a point that we will discuss in the next article, including some tricks to look for alternative bikes and equipment.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Sports" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mountain biking, a thrilling adventure sport, is rapidly gaining popularity among fitness enthusiasts and adrenaline junkies alike. The reason for this? There are many but one of the aspects that probably helped push this sport was the Covid pandemic and the lockdowns that we suffered.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/mtb/mtb.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/mtb/mtb.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Avoiding Junk Food</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/avoiding-junk-food/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Avoiding Junk Food" /><published>2023-03-11T03:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2023-03-11T03:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/avoiding-junk-food</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/avoiding-junk-food/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-health-problem-of-our-century">The health problem of our century</h2>

<p>It’s understandable that after a long day of work, the temptation to indulge in some tasty but unhealthy junk food can be strong.</p>

<p>However, it’s also common knowledge, that giving in to these temptations can have negative effects on both your body and mind.</p>

<p>Consuming excessive amounts of junk food can lead to weight gain, increased risk of chronic diseases, and a host of other health problems. Additionally, the high levels of sugar, salt, and unhealthy fats found in junk food can contribute to mood swings, fatigue, and decreased mental clarity.</p>

<p>However, in our society and with an easier access to different products, avoiding falling in the trap of junk food may be difficult. Fortunately, there are strategies you can use to avoid falling into the trap of junk food. By making small changes to your eating habits and lifestyle, you can cultivate healthier habits and avoid the negative consequences of consuming junk food.</p>

<h2 id="tricks-to-incorporate-on-your-diet">Tricks to incorporate on your diet</h2>

<h3 id="1-plan-your-meals">1. Plan your meals</h3>

<p>Plan your meals ahead of time, so you know what you will eat and when. This will help you avoid the temptation to grab something quick and unhealthy.</p>

<p>How to do this? You can for example choose one day of the week and define what the meal be on each day. Of course, there may be some days you are not home for some of the planned meals due to plans in the last time. One of the best times may be Sunday evening when you plan other things for the start to the week.</p>

<p>Depending on your objective, you can select and play with different ingredients to build the best options for you. Rely on classics or try new things and exotic food. It’s completely up to you.</p>

<h3 id="2-make-healthy-snacks-readily-available">2. Make healthy snacks readily available</h3>

<p>Keep healthy snacks, like fresh fruit, vegetables, and nuts, readily available so you can reach for them instead of junk food when hunger strikes.</p>

<p>It may look easy, but it is not. However, one trick is to have healthy snacks at hand and don’t wait to take a bit regardless of your hungriness. Having several of them during the day, does not just speed up your metabolism but also adds to the sensation of “satiety”.</p>

<h3 id="3-avoid-keeping-junk-food-in-the-house">3. Avoid keeping junk food in the house</h3>

<p>If you don’t have junk food in the house, you won’t be tempted to eat it. Instead, stock up on healthy foods that you enjoy.</p>

<p>If you cannot see it and you don’t have access to it, it’s not possible to. If you buy it for “just in case” it is likely that you will use fall in temptation. Therefore, the tip here is just don’t buy food that is unhealth for a future occasion. You will probably eat it tonight.</p>

<h3 id="4-choose-healthier-options-when-eating-out">4. Choose healthier options when eating out</h3>

<p>When eating out, choose healthier options, like salads, grilled chicken, and steamed vegetables, instead of fast food or fried foods.</p>

<p>This may be more difficult to do when seeing the choice of your companion in the restaurant. However, don’t use an excuse. If the dish in front of you looks very tasty, go of it instead of just regretting it. On the other hand, you may also compensate with healthier side dishes like salad instead of French fries for instance.</p>

<h3 id="5--moderation">5.  Moderation</h3>

<p>Nobody is perfect, not even the modern man-It’s okay to indulge in junk food occasionally, but it’s important to practice moderation. Enjoy your favorite treats in small portions and limit how often you eat them.</p>

<h3 id="6-balanced-meals">6. balanced meals</h3>

<p>Eating balanced meals that include a variety of nutrients will help keep you full and satisfied, reducing the temptation to snack on junk food.</p>

<p>Carbs are not the devil, same as fat. Having a combination of nutrients and mix of proteins, healthy fats and carbs (complex carbs) will help you with this task.</p>

<h3 id="7-read-food-labels">7. Read food labels</h3>

<p>Read the labels of packaged foods to check for added sugars, saturated and trans fats, and other unhealthy ingredients. Choose foods with fewer of these ingredients.</p>

<p>First rule of thumb is doesn’t rely on the appearance or the “envelope”. I said that you should read the labels to know what you eat, but this is not true, and it does not need to be that complex. There are some cool applications such as Yuka. They will tell you the score based on the nutrients and additives.</p>

<p>It will be also better to go for products without any QR code, which means that they are 100% natural products.</p>

<h3 id="8-drink-plenty-of-water">8. Drink plenty of water</h3>

<p>Drinking water can help curb your appetite and prevent you from reaching for junk food.</p>

<p>Aim to drink at least 8 cups of water per day. In summer, the amount of water also should in general increase, especially if you work out regularly.</p>

<h3 id="9-find-healthy-substitutes">9. Find healthy substitutes</h3>

<p>Instead of reaching for junk food, find healthy substitutes for your favorite snacks. These are some examples.</p>

<h3 id="healthy-substitutes">Healthy substitutes</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Instead of potato chips, try baked sweet potato chips.</li>
  <li>Instead of ice cream, try frozen yogurt or a fruit smoothie.</li>
  <li>Instead of candy, try fresh fruit or a small handful of nuts.</li>
  <li>Instead of soda, try sparkling water with a splash of fruit juice or a herbal tea.</li>
  <li>Instead of crackers, try rice cakes or celery sticks with hummus.</li>
  <li>Instead of fried chicken, try grilled chicken breast or baked chicken nuggets.</li>
  <li>Instead of white bread, try whole grain bread or wraps.</li>
  <li>Instead of mayonnaise, try avocado or hummus as a spread.</li>
  <li>Instead of regular pasta, try zucchini noodles or spaghetti squash.</li>
  <li>Instead of sugary cereal, try oatmeal with fruit or a high-protein granola.</li>
  <li>Instead of popcorn, try air-popped popcorn or roasted chickpeas.</li>
  <li>Instead of French fries, try roasted sweet potato wedges or carrot fries.</li>
  <li>Instead of chocolate bars, try dark chocolate or chocolate-covered almonds.</li>
  <li>Instead of a bagel with cream cheese, try a whole grain English muffin with avocado or almond butter.</li>
  <li>Instead of a muffin, try a homemade oatmeal muffin or a protein bar.</li>
  <li>Instead of a sugary sports drink, try coconut water or infused water with fresh fruit.</li>
  <li>Instead of a milkshake, try a protein shake or a smoothie bowl.</li>
  <li>Instead of store-bought granola bars, try homemade granola bars or energy balls.</li>
  <li>Instead of fried chips, try baked beet chips or kale chips.</li>
  <li>Instead of a breakfast sandwich, try a veggie omelet with whole grain toast or a breakfast burrito with a whole grain tortilla.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="10-practice-mindful-eating">10. Practice mindful eating</h3>

<p>Pay attention to your hunger and fullness cues and eat slowly, savoring each bite. This can help prevent overeating and reduce cravings for unhealthy foods. This may be the most difficult of all the items in the list.</p>

<p>Before eating, take a few deep breaths to help you relax and become present in the moment. Don’t eat because of anxiety of boredom.</p>

<p>Notice your hunger level on a scale of 1-10. Aim to start eating when you are at a 3-4, and stop eating when you are at a 6-7.</p>

<p>Take small bites and chew your food slowly, savoring the taste, texture, and aroma of each bite.</p>

<p>Avoid distractions such as watching TV, using your phone, or working while you eat. Instead, focus on the experience of eating and the enjoyment of the food. This way, Put down your utensils or food between bites, and take a few moments to check in with your body and assess your hunger level. These steps Will make you conscious of the activity and eat just what you need.</p>

<h2 id="starting-it-progressively">Starting it progressively</h2>

<p>Probably some of these tricks are already known to you and you don’t need to start from scratch.</p>

<p>Starting gradually and making small changes over time is a great way to achieve long-term success with healthy eating habits. It’s important to remember that making healthy choices is a journey, not a destination, and it’s okay to start small and work your way up.</p>

<p>Don’t be discouraged if you slip up and indulge in unhealthy foods from time to time. Instead, focus on progress rather than perfection, and make a conscious effort to get back on track with your healthy eating habits as soon as possible.</p>

<p>By taking a gradual approach to healthy eating, you can make sustainable changes that will benefit your overall health and well-being. And remember, the benefits of healthy eating go beyond just physical health - feeling good about yourself can have a positive impact on all areas of your life, from work to relationships to daily activities.</p>

<p>Making lasting changes to your eating habits can take time and patience, but the benefits are well worth the effort. By starting small and gradually incorporating healthier choices into your diet, you can build momentum and create a sustainable healthy lifestyle.</p>

<p>It’s important to approach healthy eating as a journey, rather than a quick fix or a temporary diet. This mindset can help you stay motivated and committed to making long-term changes that will benefit your overall health and well-being.</p>

<p>Remember, healthy eating is not about deprivation or perfection. It’s about finding a balance that works for you and your body, and making conscious choices that support your health and happiness. So be kind to yourself, celebrate your progress, and keep moving forward towards a healthier, happier you.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The importance of making conscious, healthy choices in our daily lives. In a society where processed and unhealthy foods are readily available, it can be challenging to resist the temptation to indulge in junk food]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/junk-food/health-food.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/junk-food/health-food.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Ethereum: Next Stop Shanghai</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ethereum-shanghai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ethereum: Next Stop Shanghai" /><published>2023-02-22T03:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2023-02-22T03:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ethereum-shanghai</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ethereum-shanghai/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-merge-continuation">The Merge Continuation</h2>

<p>A few months ago, we discussed the most important changes that the Ethereum Merge would bring and in fact delivered to the users. With this change, as you know, the most significant change was that the “old” Proof of Work was replaced by the Proof of Stake Protocol.</p>

<p>These are basically the most important changes that are possible now thanks to the Merge.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Improved energy efficiency: PoS uses less energy compared to PoW, which is expected to significantly reduce Ethereum’s carbon footprint.</li>
  <li>Increased scalability: The merge made the Ethereum network more scalable, as PoS can process more transactions per second compared to PoW.</li>
  <li>Enhanced security: PoS is designed to prevent 51% attacks, which are a significant concern with PoW consensus mechanisms.</li>
  <li>Changes to the mining ecosystem: The merge eliminated the need for miners, as PoS relies on validators who stake their ETH to secure the network.</li>
  <li>EIP-1559 integration: The upgrade included integration of EIP-1559, which introduced a new fee structure for Ethereum transactions, making the network more user-friendly.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="from-london-to">From London to…</h2>

<p>However, these changed had not been possible without the fork that occurred the year before. Back in 2021, this network change, also known as the London upgrade, made the following modifications in the Ethereum network.</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>EIP-1559</strong>: This change introduced a new transaction pricing mechanism that aims to improve the predictability and transparency of Ethereum gas fees, which can often be unpredictable and volatile. It also burned a portion of the fees collected, which reduces the overall supply of Ethereum, potentially increasing its value.</li>
  <li><strong>EIP-3198</strong>: This change reduces the gas cost of certain types of transactions, making them cheaper for users.</li>
  <li><strong>EIP-3529</strong>: This change increased the difficulty of certain types of DDOS attacks that can slow down or crash the Ethereum network.</li>
  <li><strong>EIP-3541</strong>: This change prepared the network for the upcoming Ethereum 2.0 upgrade, seen above, by removing certain features that will no longer be needed.</li>
</ol>

<p>These implementations caused them to make the network more energy-efficient, secure, and scalable, while also changing the mining ecosystem and introducing new fee structures. However, as also announced in the Merge, this is not over, and the Ethereum Foundation never stops with the continuous improvements.</p>

<p>Having listed it several EIP, it may seem that there are no enhancements left for do in the Ethereum. Nonetheless, this is quite far from reality and if you to the Ethereum Improvement Proposals website you will see more and more suggestions.</p>

<h2 id="shanghai">Shanghai</h2>

<p>So now, with all the background and knowing the most important changes occurred in the last 2 years explained, let’s focus on the Shanghai upgrade.</p>

<h2 id="5-new-eip-coming">5 New EIP Coming</h2>

<p>Even if the Merge was the big upgrade, there are 5 EIP expected to come in a few weeks from now. When? It’s expected that these changes may pop up around mid-March. However, based on the experience with previous integrations, it will not be surprising that this fork in the network is slightly delayed.</p>

<p>The upgrade of Ethereum, also known as the Ethereum Shanghai fork, will implement five Ethereum Improvement Proposals (EIPs), and compared to the previous forks, there are several changes related to the fees.</p>

<h3 id="eip-4895">EIP-4895</h3>

<p>Out of these five proposals, EIP-4895 is expected to receive the most attention. The upgrade will allow Ethereum investors to withdraw their staked ETH for the first time since December 2020. This lock was needed in order to use this as validation mechanism and protect the network.</p>

<p>Some of the fears that this had raised is that there may be a lot of withdrawals when this change becomes effective. However, because of some withdrawal caps and other rewards- higher staking -, it’s unlikely that we will see massive withdrawals.</p>

<p><strong>Link</strong>: <a href="https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-4895">https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-4895</a></p>

<h3 id="eip-3855">EIP-3855</h3>

<p>At the moment, the EVM does not have a PUSH0 instruction, and the goal will be to reduce the gas consumption by introduction this instruction in the virtual machine.</p>

<p><strong>Link</strong>: <a href="https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-3855">https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-3855</a></p>

<h2 id="eip-3860">EIP-3860</h2>

<p>EIP-3860 is an extension of the old EIP-170 and seeks to lower transaction costs for developers when interacting with smart contracts.</p>

<p><strong>Link</strong>: <a href="https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-3860">https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-3860</a></p>

<h3 id="eip-3651">EIP-3651</h3>

<p>To execute transactions in the network, it is necessary to interact with the Coinbase machine – nothing to do with the Exchange - several times. The initial interaction requires a higher fee as the software needs to “warm up,” but as interactions increase, fees decrease.</p>

<p>This proposal will ensure that the Coinbase software remains “warm”, resulting in a reduced gas fee to access it.</p>

<p><strong>Link</strong>: <a href="https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-3651">https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-3651</a></p>

<h3 id="eip-6049">EIP-6049</h3>

<p>EIP-6049 is a notification mechanism to developers regarding code known as “SELFDESTRUCT that aims to reduce gas fees.</p>

<p><strong>Link</strong>: <a href="https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-6049">https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-6049</a></p>

<h2 id="what-after-shanghai">What after Shanghai?</h2>

<p>These upgrades should improve network usage in DeFi and NFTs. Even the initiator of them, some detractors complained that high gas fees and slow transactions affected some of these ecosystems.</p>

<p>With these improvements, old and new projects may consider Ethereum more favorably, which was losing momentum to newer and chains with lower fees.</p>

<p>Greater flexibility in staking, better performance, and an increase in stakeholders could amplify the resulting network effect sand benefit all stakeholders (users, investors, etc.) in the long run.</p>

<p>The objective of these changes is not just to continue improving the Ethereum performance, but also try to reduce the churn of some DeFi or NFT projects to more affordable networks such as Polygon or Solana, like we have seen in marketplaces like OpenSea or other applications in the last years.</p>

<p>As consequences of part Blockchain Trilemma, Ethereum has been plagued with sluggish transactions and high fees, which became more evident during the decentralized finance boom a few years ago.</p>

<p>Furthermore, the popularity of non-fungible tokens (NFTs) and the trend of minting them in 2021 and early 2022 added to poor user experiences and high gas fees. These EIPs are mainly focused on this topic. Their aim to help mitigate these problems and convince users that Ethereum is the best network for the different projects and dApps.</p>

<p>As we have seen, this will not be the end, and this is just the follow-up to get a more scalable network. This will be achieved when features such sharding are included in the chain in a few months from now.</p>

<p>Achieving sharding will be crucial for enhancing transaction throughput on the chain by enabling “parallel processing.” The implementation of sharding is expected to occur in two stages in 2023 and 2024.</p>

<p>Although small change compared to the PoW – PoS migration occurred in 2022, this upgrade makes sure that Ethereum, one of the oldest blockchains, keeps up good progress and for sure will convince old and new users of the chain.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After London, and the Merge, the Ethereum network is preparing for the next big upgrade. This time, the Shanghai fork will bring 5 new EIP to the network.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/ethereum-shanghai/shanghai.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/ethereum-shanghai/shanghai.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Top Blockchain Courses</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/top-blockchain-courses/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top Blockchain Courses" /><published>2023-02-14T03:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2023-02-14T03:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/top-blockchain-courses</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/top-blockchain-courses/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="always-into-something-new">Always into something new</h2>
<div class="text-article">

Today in the afternoon, I received an email from INSEAD announcing that they are offering a new specialization called Web3 and Blockchain in Global Commerce Specialization. I received this message in my mailbox, I guess because I took several courses from INSEAD related to Blockchain in the past.



</div>

<p>I did not have the chance to go in detail about this specialization, but it sounds interesting to learn new concepts and refresh the ones I learned a few years ago. I also thought that it could be relevant to other people sharing my experience with other courses.</p>

<p>This post is not about this specialization and I will describe more about it when I complete it. Nonetheless, this purpose of this article is to show the readers that even if it’s sometimes not easy to start into the Blockchain world and industries, there are several resources out there that can help you in this mission. We already saw of these resources in another post, so this post will talk mainly about more traditional courses that I enjoyed.</p>

<h2 id="blockchain-revolution">Blockchain Revolution</h2>

<h3 id="organization-insead">Organization: INSEAD</h3>

<p>The Blockchain Revolution course on Coursera is an in-depth exploration of the concepts, applications, and implications of blockchain technology. The course is taught by Don Tapscott and Alex Tapscott in collaboration with INSEAD. Both both well-known experts in the field of blockchain and the course is now several years old. The new specialization of the introduction is also taught by the father and his son.</p>

<p>The course is divided into several modules, each of which covers a different aspect of blockchain technology. The first module introduces the basic concepts of blockchain and provides an overview of how it works.</p>

<p>The second one delves deeper into the technical aspects of blockchain, including the various types of consensus algorithms and the role of cryptography in securing blockchain networks.</p>

<p>The third module explores the various applications of blockchain technology, including its potential use in finance, supply chain management, and digital identity verification. The fourth module looks at the potential societal impact of blockchain, including its potential to disrupt traditional power structures and create new economic opportunities.</p>

<p>The fifth module focuses on the practical aspects of building and deploying blockchain solutions, including how to design a blockchain network, select the right consensus algorithm, and ensure security and scalability.</p>

<p>The final module of the course explores the future of blockchain technology, including emerging trends and the potential impact of blockchain on various industries. It’s here where the student can put all the learned lessons to work and create a project that will need to submit.</p>

<p>In these courses, the instructors use real-world examples and case studies to illustrate the potential of blockchain technology. By the end of the course, students should have a solid understanding of how blockchain works, its potential applications, and the implications of this technology for businesses, governments, and society as a whole.</p>

<p>If this course was not enough, there is a similar specialization also taught by the Tapscott family and INSEAD. This one comes next in our list.</p>

<p><strong>Link</strong>: <a href="https://www.coursera.org/specializations/blockchain-revolution-enterprise">Blockchain Revolution</a></p>

<h2 id="blockchain-revolution-in-financial-services">Blockchain Revolution in Financial Services</h2>

<h3 id="organization-insead-1">Organization: INSEAD</h3>

<p>The Blockchain Revolution in Financial Services Specialization on Coursera is a series of four courses that explore the potential of blockchain technology to transform the financial industry. They explain the basics like in the first course, but they will go deeper topics related to blockchain in finance.</p>

<p>The first course provides an introduction to blockchain technology and explores its potential to disrupt traditional financial systems. Students learn about the various types of blockchain networks, consensus algorithms, and cryptographic techniques that are used to secure blockchain transactions.</p>

<p>The second course focuses on the applications of blockchain in finance, including digital currencies, smart contracts, and asset tokenization. Students learn about the various use cases of blockchain technology in the financial industry, including cross-border payments, trade finance, and securities trading.</p>

<p>The third course delves deeper into the technical aspects of blockchain in finance, including the development of dAppsand the use of smart contracts. Students learn how to build and deploy dApps on blockchain networks and explore the architecture of various blockchain applications in finance.</p>

<p>The final course explores the regulatory and legal considerations of blockchain in finance. Students learn about the challenges of integrating blockchain into existing regulatory frameworks and explore the potential impact of blockchain on financial markets and systems.</p>

<p>From the description and names, you may say some overlaps with the first course. Therefore, it may be a better idea to take this course as a refresher of the initial course.</p>

<p><strong>Link</strong>: <a href="https://www.coursera.org/specializations/blockchain-financial-services">Blockchain Revolution in Financial Services</a></p>

<h1 id="the-decentralized-finance-defi-the-future-of-finance">The Decentralized Finance (DeFi): The Future of Finance</h1>

<h3 id="organization-duke-university">Organization: Duke University</h3>

<p>The Decentralized Finance (DeFi): The Future of Finance Specialization on Coursera is a series of four courses that provide a comprehensive overview of the emerging field of decentralized finance. The courses are taught by Cam Harvey, who is a professor at Duke University and has written several topics about Decentralized Finance.</p>

<p>The first course provides an introduction to DeFi and explores its potential to disrupt traditional finance. Students learn about the key concepts and components of DeFi, including smart contracts, decentralized exchanges, and stablecoins.</p>

<p>The second course focuses on decentralized applications (dApps) and how they are built on blockchain platforms. Students will learn how to develop and deploy smart contracts using the Solidity programming language and explore the architecture of various DeFi applications.</p>

<p>The third course delves deeper into the technical aspects of DeFi and explores the different types of decentralized finance protocols. Students learn about lending and borrowing platforms, decentralized exchanges, and prediction markets.</p>

<p>The final course explores the economic and regulatory implications of DeFi. Students learn about the challenges of integrating DeFi into existing financial systems and explore the potential impact of DeFi on global finance and economic systems.</p>

<p>By the end of the specialization, students should have a solid understanding of the key concepts, technologies, and applications of DeFi and be well-positioned to explore the future of finance in this rapidly evolving field.</p>

<p><strong>Link</strong>: <a href="https://www.coursera.org/specializations/decentralized-finance-duke">The Decentralized Finance (DeFi): The Future of Finance</a></p>

<h2 id="other-options">Other options</h2>

<p>Although these are the courses that I find most complete and interesting, there are other ones that you may want to have a look at.</p>

<h3 id="blockchain-specialization">Blockchain Specialization</h3>

<h4 id="organization-buffalo-university">Organization: Buffalo University</h4>

<p>The first one of this honorable mentions is the Blockchain Specialization. Similar to the ones from INSEAD, students will have the chance to finalize the 3 courses with an applied learning project.</p>

<p>The Blockchain Specialization by Buffalo University on Coursera is a four-course program that covers a comprehensive range of topics related to blockchain technology. The specialization is designed for learners who want to gain practical skills in blockchain development and explore the potential use cases of blockchain in various industries.</p>

<p>The last one included in this article is from Princeton University and more technical than the other ones described in this article.</p>

<p><strong>Link</strong>: <a href="https://www.coursera.org/specializations/blockchain?">Blockchain Specialization</a></p>

<h3 id="bitcoin-and-cryptocurrency-technologies">Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency Technologies</h3>

<h4 id="organization-princeton">Organization: Princeton</h4>

<p>The first module provides an introduction to Bitcoin and its underlying technology, including the basics of cryptography and distributed systems.</p>

<p>The following modules delve deeper into the technical aspects of Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies, including the mechanics of the Bitcoin network, mining and consensus algorithms, and the role of cryptography in securing blockchain networks.</p>

<p>The course also covers the economics of cryptocurrencies, including market dynamics, pricing, and trading. Students learn about the various types of cryptocurrencies and tokens, including stablecoins, security tokens, and utility tokens.</p>

<p>The course also explores the legal and regulatory considerations of cryptocurrency, including the challenges of integrating cryptocurrencies into existing regulatory frameworks and the potential impact of cryptocurrency on financial systems and markets.</p>

<p><strong>Link</strong>: <a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/cryptocurrency?">Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency Technologies</a></p>

<h2 id="more-to-come">More to come</h2>

<p>In this article, I have shared my experience a brief description of all the Blockchain and DeFi courses I have taken.</p>

<p>After summarizing several blockchain and cryptocurrency courses on Coursera, in my opinion these courses offer a comprehensive overview of blockchain technology and its potential applications. These courses cover a wide range of topics, from the technical aspects of blockchain development to the potential use cases of blockchain in various industries.</p>

<p>What is especially notable is the hands-on approach that many of these courses take. Students have the opportunity to apply their knowledge through a series of assignments and projects, which allows them to gain practical experience in blockchain development.</p>

<p>In general, these courses provide an excellent foundation for anyone looking to explore the world of blockchain and cryptocurrency. Whether you are interested in the technical aspects of blockchain development or the potential applications of blockchain in various industries, these courses offer a wealth of knowledge and practical skills that will prepare you for the future of this rapidly-evolving field.
I will also update you on the Web3 and Blockchain in Global Commerce Specialization and it could be that this is an additional course that we should include in this list. 
By the way, the link is included here: <a href="https://www.coursera.org/specializations/web3-blockchain-global-commerce">Web3 and Blockchain in Global Commerce</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Education" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Different blockchain courses from prestigious universities that can be a trigger point in your professional future]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/courses-blockchain/courses_blockchain.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/courses-blockchain/courses_blockchain.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Emerging Markets 2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/emerging-markets-2025/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Emerging Markets 2025" /><published>2023-02-04T03:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2023-02-04T03:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/emerging-markets-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/emerging-markets-2025/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="outlook-2023">Outlook 2023</h2>

<div class="text-article">
Despite facing numerous obstacles in 2022, emerging market equities began to show signs of recovery in the last quarter of 2022. This trend is expected to continue during 2023 due to factors such as robust growth, declining inflation, a softening US dollar, and favorable fundamentals.

</div>

<p>In light of the widespread decline in equity markets during 2022, emerging market equities are believed to be one of the most undervalued asset classes, offering attractive valuations compared to historical norms. Just have a look at some metrics such as the Price Earnings Ratio and it is one of the most attractive ones in recent years.</p>

<p>When it comes to bonds, the outlook for emerging market debt, which faced a difficult landscape in 2022, is now considered to be more positive. The combination of high yields, favorable valuations, and a supportive global environment, including the potential for growth in China, creates the opportunity for equity-like returns in the mid-teens over the next year in both hard and local currency debt.</p>

<h2 id="what-happened-recently">What happened recently?</h2>

<p>But before we start, what happened when back in 2020, we expected emerging markets such as China to be the clear winners of the COVID pandemic?</p>

<p>In 2022, the MSCI EM Index experienced a decline of around 20%. When all the spotlights were on China, they heavily disappointed last year. Other BRIC countries such as Russia did not help either. Korea – although just considered as Emerging for the MSCI index and not in the FTSE index -</p>

<p>This focus on innovation and growth trends can have a significant impact on investment performance. In 2021, the MSCI EM ex-China Index outperformed the MSCI China Index by a margin of 32 percentage points, showcasing the benefits of<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"> actively </code>targeting emerging market equities. Regions such as Argentina, India, or Turkey had something to do with this performance.</p>

<p>However, as said, we have seen some signs of improvements in the last weeks. In the last quarter of the year, the asset class saw a resurgence, rising by nearly 10% as a result of China’s efforts to reopen its economy and support for the real estate sector to reignite economic growth. In terms of sector performance, communication services performed the best, followed by health care, materials, and real estate. Furthermore, there were some indices such as the Turkish or Argentinian ones that achieved<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"> excellent </code>results, even if their local currency devaluated even more.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, energy, utilities, and consumer staples lagged behind the index during the quarter. The strong recovery seen in the fourth quarter of 2022 bodes well for the future of emerging market equities in 2023. Let’s take a closer look at some of the<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"> key </code>factors that will drive growth in the coming year.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/emerging_markets_2025/machu.jpeg" alt="Hidden secrets" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Some Latin American countries can be the next hidden gem, considering that they have been reviled for some time </span>
</p>

<p>Despite facing difficulties in 2021 and 2022, such as slow vaccine distribution and the emergence of the Delta variant, there is potential for a rebound in emerging market (EM) economies. However, risks still persist. A potential catalyst for recovery could be a rise in interest rates, which is expected to bring developed-market GDP back to its trend line.</p>

<p>An<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"> active </code>strategy in emerging market (EM) equities has the potential to outperform a US equity strategy in the next decade, as populations in EM countries grow and innovation continues to expand. The equity valuations in EM markets are relatively attractive, and earnings growth is currently at a decade-high. The region is home to many of the world’s top-performing companies, but these firms may not be included in standard benchmarks, which tend to heavily weight state-owned enterprises and industries that rely on exports. An<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"> active </code>investment approach can provide investors with greater exposure to companies that are experiencing growth driven by secular trends.</p>

<h2 id="long-term-vision">Long-term vision</h2>

<p>Emerging markets are set to play a significant role in the global economy not just until 2025, but in the next decade. Despite facing challenges such as economic instability, political unrest, and the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic, these markets have shown remarkable resilience and are poised for growth in the coming years.</p>

<p>One of the<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"> key </code>drivers of growth in emerging markets is their rapidly growing populations, which provide a large pool of consumers for both local and foreign businesses.</p>

<p>This, combined with increasing urbanization, rising incomes, and growing middle classes, creates a favourable environment for investment.</p>

<p>Another factor contributing to the growth of emerging markets is technological advancements, particularly in the areas of digital infrastructure, e-commerce, and fintech. This is providing new opportunities for businesses to reach customers and drive innovation in these markets.</p>

<p>In 2023 and 2024, some of the top emerging markets to watch include China, India, Brazil, Russia, and South Africa. These countries offer a diverse range of investment opportunities across various industries, including technology, healthcare, and infrastructure. The astonishing returns that occurred in the Turkish and Argentinian indices are not expected to continue in 2023.</p>

<p>China, with its large and growing middle class, is expected to continue to drive growth in Asia, while India is poised to become a major player in the global economy, thanks to its large and youthful population. In South America, the 2 big players, Brazil and Argentina, are set to benefit from a rebound in commodities prices and increased investment in infrastructure.</p>

<p>Russia, meanwhile, is poised to benefit from a recovering oil market, while South Africa is expected to see growth driven by its mineral resources, including gold and platinum.</p>

<p>You may have a look at some of these countries in this <a href="https://mrfreire.net/top-emerging-countries-2022/">article</a></p>

<h2 id="beware-of-the-risks">Beware of the risks</h2>

<p>However, while emerging markets offer significant opportunities, they also come with risks. Political and economic instability, currency fluctuations, and regulatory challenges are among the risks that investors must consider when investing in these markets.</p>

<p>Despite these challenges, emerging markets are expected to continue to play an increasingly important role in the global economy over the next two years. With the right investment strategy, they offer the potential for high returns, while also helping to diversify portfolios and mitigate risk.</p>

<p>In conclusion, the next years are set to be exciting years for emerging markets, with opportunities for growth and investment in a range of industries. The prices we see are very attractive as entry level.</p>

<h2 id="research-and-where-to-start">Research and where to start</h2>

<p>As always, careful research and a well-considered investment strategy will be<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"> key </code>to realizing the full potential of these dynamic and rapidly growing markets. However, instead of cherry-picking stocks, the best solution for most of us would be and index in order to collect returns from all countries.</p>

<p>Just to give you some options, some of these index funds can include below seen here. Those with low PER have been selected:</p>

<div>

<table class="table table-responsive">
<thead>
<th style="font-size: 10px;">Ticker</th> <th style="font-size: 10px;">Name</th> <th style="font-size: 10px;">Isin</th> <th style="font-size: 10px;">Expenses</th> <th style="font-size: 10px;">Morningstar</th>
</thead>

<tr> 
<td style="font-size: 10px;"><a href="https:F//finance.mrfreire.net/security_search/security_search_results/VWO">VWO</a></td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">Vanguard Emerging Markets Stock Index Fund
</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">US9220428588</td><td style="font-size: 10px;">0.08%</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">4</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td style="font-size: 10px;"><a href="https://finance.mrfreire.net/security_search/security_search_results/HYEM">HYEM</a></td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">VanEck Emerging Markets High Yield Bond ETF
</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">US9220428588</td><td style="font-size: 10px;">0.08%</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">5</td>
</tr>

<tbody> <tr> 
<td style="font-size: 10px;"><a href="https://finance.mrfreire.net/security_search/security_search_results/AEEM.PA">AEEM.PA</a></td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">Amundi MSCI Emerging Markets</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">LU1681045370</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">0.10%</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">4</td></tr> 
<tr> 
<td style="font-size: 10px;">
<a href="https://finance.mrfreire.net/security_search/security_search_results/AUEM.L">AUEM.L</a></td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">Amundi MSCI Emerging Markets</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">LU099617713</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">0.10%</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">4</td>
</tr> 
<tr> 
<td style="font-size: 10px;"><a href="https://finance.mrfreire.net/security_search/security_search_results/AUEM.PA">AUEM.PA</a></td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">Amundi MSCI Emerging Markets</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">LU1681045453</td><td style="font-size: 10px;">0.10%</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">4</td>
</tr>

<tr> 
<td style="font-size: 10px;"><a href="https://finance.mrfreire.net/security_search/security_search_results/VFEM.AS">VFEM.AS</a></td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">Vanguard FTSE Emerging Markets UCITS ETF
</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">IE00B3VVMM84</td><td style="font-size: 10px;">0.22%</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">4</td>
</tr>


<tr> 
<td style="font-size: 10px;"><a href="https://finance.mrfreire.net/security_search/security_search_results/EEMS">EEMS</a></td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">iShares MSCI Emerging Markets Min Vol Factor ETF
</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">US4642864759</td><td style="font-size: 10px;">0.25%</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">4</td>
</tr>

<tr> 
<td style="font-size: 10px;"><a href="https://finance.mrfreire.net/security_search/security_search_results/VDEA.L">VDEA.L</a></td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">Vanguard USD Emerging Markets Government Bond UCITS ETF
</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">IE00BZ163L3</td><td style="font-size: 10px;">0.25%</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">4</td>
</tr>

<tr> 
<td style="font-size: 10px;"><a href="https://finance.mrfreire.net/security_search/security_search_results/FLTW">FLTW</a></td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">Franklin FTSE Taiwan ETF
</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">US35473P686</td><td style="font-size: 10px;">0.19%</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">5</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td style="font-size: 10px;"><a href="https://finance.mrfreire.net/security_search/security_search_results/EWT">EWT</a></td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">iShares MSCI Taiwan ETF
</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">US46434G7723</td><td style="font-size: 10px;">0.57%</td> <td style="font-size: 10px;">5</td>
</tr>

</tbody>
</table>

</div>

<p>If you want to see all Emerging Market funds and all the statistics and comparison against peers, you may visit the sections for different regions <a href="https://finance.mrfreire.net/funds/funds_region">Funds per Region</a>.</p>

<p>And if you are not sure which shares constituting the index, you can use the following site <a href="https://finance.mrfreire.net/security_search/constituents">Index Constituents</a> to analyze all the shares one-by-one.</p>

<p>Now that you have the tools, you can start your research and find the best investment for you. Good luck!</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Investing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the current economic situation, the emerging markets are becoming more and more attractive for investors. In this article, we will discuss the potential and attractiveness of emerging markets for the years 2023 and 2024.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/emerging_markets_2025/china.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/emerging_markets_2025/china.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>