<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-19T00:03:04+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Life of a Modern Man</title><subtitle>Advising in Lifestyle and Finance</subtitle><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">The Ethereum Merge Explained</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-ethereum-merge-explained/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ethereum Merge Explained" /><published>2022-09-18T14:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-18T14:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-ethereum-merge-explained</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-ethereum-merge-explained/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
In the last weeks we have seen a lot of excitement coming from different places in regards to  what’s called the event of the year in crypto world. I’m
referring to Ethereum and what is not a gamechanger just for Ethereum itself for the whole crypto industry as as result of the big changes that this fork carries.
</div>

<p>The Ethereum Merge has been one of the most ambitious and awaited changes in the network. Long-awaited because there
first plans about this software upgrade data back to 2014, and the upgrade occurred on 15 September 2022, almost 10
years later. The fork also opens new opportunities for the usage of blockchain in different components and standards,
due to the problems and inefficiency that the new consensus mechanism brings.</p>

<p>Furthermore, although Ethereum is the already network with more utilities and business cases, this can boost the
commerciality of this network and push it to thew next level with the entry of new players.</p>

<p>Besides, this event can be the one that turn the tables in order to recover the lost trust and see that there are
different projects trying to enhance the utilities of the different chains</p>

<p>Nonetheless, even if some sources said that this Merge will fix some of the known issues in the Ethereum network, they
don’t have any impact on them. We will need to see additional upgrades in order to see if these topics are modified.</p>

<p>This is basically the points that this network upgrade entails and what, in order to avoid misunderstandings, problems
that are not tackled with this modification in this software change.</p>

<h2 id="what-are-the-main-changes">What are the main changes?</h2>

<h3 id="1-energy">1. Energy</h3>

<p>Switching from the Proof of Work to Proof Stake protocols means that the energy consumption will decline approximated by
99%.</p>

<p>Energy waste and efficiency has been one of the topics that some crypto detractors such as regulators have included as
one of the disadvantages of the growth of blockchain.</p>

<p>Several have criticized some of the PoW blockchains such as Bitcoin or Ethereum because of the negative environmental
impact they had and the excessive usage of energy to validate the transactions in the network.</p>

<p>Some of the most known - and controversial - usages of Ethereum is the minting of NFTs using ERC-721. This change will
have a much better impact on the volatile market of the NFTs because of the drop of the energy usage to mint them,
enabling the growth of this business.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/ethereum/sustainable.jpeg" alt="Thinking about the future" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Regardless of the other technical details, it is a great milestone to reduce the energy usage on around 99% thanks to the Merge
</span>
</p>

<h3 id="2-more-democratic-rewards">2. More democratic rewards</h3>

<p>Apart from the change in the energy efficiency, the switch to Proof of Work also means that via this mechanism, the
staking rewards for validating and securing the network that were reserved for those with powerful computers is over.</p>

<p>Please note you will need at least 32 ETH (around 48,000 USD at the time of writing) plus the computer to perform
staking on your own. However, there are more used options such as liquidity staking, using ERC-20, where you may
allocate part of your ETH tokens to a pool (in order to reach the minimum of 32 ETH).</p>

<p>In case you are not happy with none of these options, despite not being that popular, another possibility in order to
receive staking rewards for your share are staking them via a centralized exchange.</p>

<p>As with all these cases, please do your own research before delegating your tokens.</p>

<h3 id="3-price-and-value">3. Price and value</h3>

<p>Price and value must not be understood in the wrong way. This is also not a good or bad thing coming from the Merge.</p>

<p>Although the Merge has been waited for years, the truth is that Ether has lost around 60% of its market value during 2022.
However, if we use the CMC 200 index as reference, the price drop is also aligned with the drop in the CMC 200
index.</p>

<p>On the other hand, for instance, it had an increase of 100%, when the prices went in August from 1,000 USD to 2,000 USD.</p>

<p>As discussed in other topics, there has not been a drastic change – upwards or downwards- in Ethereum’s price on the
date the fork was completed. As with other assets, the price is already discounted when these big events occur. As you
may have noticed, there were a surge on the price in the months prior to the Merge.</p>

<p>In the future, Ethereum will be transition to a deflationary asset. Before the Merge and with the PoW, 13,000 new Ether
tokens were issued on a daily basis. The change changes this and from 13,000 we will see around 1,600 Ether tokens per
day.</p>

<p>The less tokens there are, the higher the price should be for Ether tokens, being an alternative deflationary asset.</p>

<h2 id="aspects-that-remain-unchanged">Aspects that remain unchanged</h2>

<p>Probably some of the most common topics when it comes to Ethereum are fees. The bad news is that the logic for these remains unchanged.
These are other problems that Ethereum Merge does not solve or haven’t been modified with the Merge.</p>

<h3 id="1-fees">1. Fees</h3>

<p>“The fork will definitely make the gas fees cheaper.” This is wrong and the changes that occurred in the network did not
have any consequences on the fees that must be paid on each blockchain transaction to reward the validators of the
transactions occurring in the chain. The last change in the network that affected how the Wei that must be paid per
transaction was the London Upgrade in 2021.</p>

<h3 id="2-speed">2. Speed</h3>

<p>Related to the blockchain dilemma, the Merge does not make the speed faster neither increases that number of
transactions that can be processed per minute. There may be a slight improvement in the speed, but it will be
unnoticeable for users. For the speed changes, we will have to wait in case this modification arrives one day.</p>

<h2 id="key-takeaways">Key takeaways</h2>

<p>There has been a lot of hype because of this Merge milestone, and it has been waited for some time now. Due to all the
news surrounding this topic for the last year, these are the main facts that we can say in order to conclude and see how
this topic evolves.</p>

<h3 id="environmental-impact">Environmental impact</h3>

<p>This is definitely the biggest changes and main advantage of the software upgrade. Not just related to the current energy crisis, this is a huge step in order to protect our
planet with a more sensible and responsible usage of electricity. This can be a key milestone for a reaching
sustainability in the crypto industry (although for example there are no plans for example for Bitcoin and switching
from PoW to PoS in this case) because of the new possibilities on the different networks and standards that enables.</p>

<h3 id="staking-for-all-users">Staking for all users</h3>

<p>While validating and securing the network was an action reserved for those with more computing power, hence the rewards
were just for them, the change to PoS means that all of us can take part securing the transactions and getting rewarded
for the Ether tokens we use to achieve that.</p>

<h3 id="commercial-impact">Commercial impact</h3>

<p>Having reduced the energy usage and improving the energy efficiency has also opened new ideas to Ethereum, which already had many apps
around this ecosystem. Furthermore, this is not just important to Ethereum, but other chains, and it also means that the
evolution of the different blockchains will lead to a better experience for the users and more business ideas that some
years ago were unthinkable because of sustainable issues.</p>

<hr />

<p>Having explained the most important changes and having also denied things that the Merge does not change, it’s true that some of these changes can boost Ethereum and the crypto sector. 
At the same time, it cannot be denied that some users have been disappointed because they were expecting much more. Time will tell.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The changes that the Ethereum Merge, including the impact they create and what aspects are not modified with this fork in the network]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/ethereum/ether.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/ethereum/ether.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="es"><title type="html">El Ethereum Merge Explicado</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/el-ethereum-merge-explicado/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="El Ethereum Merge Explicado" /><published>2022-09-18T14:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-18T14:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/el-ethereum-merge-explicado</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/el-ethereum-merge-explicado/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
En las últimas semanas hemos visto mucho entusiasmo proveniente de diferentes lugares con respecto a lo que se llama el evento del año en el mundo crypto. 
Me refiero a Ethereum y lo que no es un cambio de juego solo para Ethereum en sí mismo para toda la industria crypto como resultado de los grandes cambios que conlleva esta bifurcación.
</div>

<p>El Ethereum Merge ha sido uno de los cambios más ambiciosos y esperados en la red. Muy esperado porque los primeros
planes sobre los datos de actualización de este software se remontan a 2014, y la actualización se produjo el 15 de
septiembre de 2022, casi 10 años después. El fork también abre nuevas oportunidades para el uso de blockchain en
diferentes componentes y estándares, debido a los problemas y la ineficiencia que trae consigo el nuevo mecanismo de
consenso.</p>

<p>Además, aunque Ethereum ya es la red con más utilidades y casos de negocios, esto puede impulsar la comercialidad de
esta red y llevarla al siguiente nivel con la entrada de nuevos jugadores.</p>

<p>Sin ir más lejos, este evento puede ser también el que cambie las tornas para recuperar la confianza perdida y ver que hay
diferentes proyectos intentando potenciar las utilidades de las distintas cadenas.</p>

<p>No obstante, incluso si algunas fuentes dijeron que esta fusión solucionará algunos de los problemas conocidos en la red
Ethereum, no tienen ningún impacto en ellos. Tendremos que ver actualizaciones adicionales para ver si estos temas se
modifican.</p>

<p>Estos son básicamente los puntos que conlleva esta actualización de red y cuáles, para evitar malentendidos, problemas
que no se abordan con esta modificación en este cambio de software.</p>

<h2 id="cuáles-son-los-principales-cambios">¿Cuáles son los principales cambios?</h2>

<h3 id="1-energía">1. Energía</h3>

<p>Cambiar de los protocolos de Proof of Work a Proof of Stake significa que el consumo de energía se reducirá
aproximadamente en un 99 %.</p>

<p>El derroche y la eficiencia energética ha sido uno de los temas que algunos criptodetractores como los reguladores han
incluido como una de las desventajas del crecimiento de blockchain.</p>

<p>Varios han criticado algunas de las cadenas de bloques PoW como Bitcoin o Ethereum por el impacto ambiental negativo que
tenían y el uso excesivo de energía para validar las transacciones en la red.</p>

<p>Algunos de los usos más conocidos y controvertidos de Ethereum son la acuñación de NFT utilizando ERC-721. Este cambio
tendrá un impacto mucho mayor en el mercado volátil de los NFT debido a la caída del uso de energía para acuñarlos, lo
que permitirá el crecimiento de este negocio.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/ethereum/sustainable.jpeg" alt="Thinking about the future" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Independientemente de los otros detalles técnicos, es un gran hito reducir el uso de energía en alrededor del 99 % gracias a Merge.
</span>
</p>

<h3 id="2-recompensas-más-democráticas">2. Recompensas más democráticas</h3>

<p>Además del cambio en la eficiencia energética, el cambio a la Proof of Stake también significa que, a través de este
mecanismo, se terminaron las recompensas por validar y asegurar la red que estaban reservadas para aquellos con
computadoras potentes.</p>

<p>Hay que tener en cuenta que se necesita al menos 32 ETH (alrededor de 48 000 USD al momento de escribir este artículo) más la
computadora para realizar el staking por su cuenta. Sin embargo, existen opciones más utilizadas, como el liquidity staking,
utilizando ERC-20, donde puede asignar parte de sus tokens ETH a un grupo (para alcanzar el mínimo de 32 ETH).</p>

<p>En caso de que no esté satisfecho con ninguna de estas opciones, a pesar de no ser tan popular, otra posibilidad para
recibir recompensas de apuesta por su parte es apostarlas a través de un intercambio centralizado.</p>

<p>Al igual que con todos estos casos, investiga por tu cuenta antes de delegar tus tokens.</p>

<h3 id="3-precio-y-valor">3. Precio y valor</h3>

<p>El orecio y valor de  un activo no deben entenderse de forma equivocada. Esto tampoco es algo bueno o malo proveniente del Merge</p>

<p>Aunque el Merge se ha esperado durante años, lo cierto es que Ether ha perdido alrededor del 60% de su valor de mercado
durante 2022. Sin embargo, si tomamos como referencia el índice CMC 200, la caída del precio también está alineada con
la caída de este.</p>

<p>En cambio, por ejemplo, Ethereum tuvo un incremento del 100%, cuando los precios en agosto pasaron de 1.000 USD a 2.000 USD.</p>

<p>Como se discutió en otros temas, no ha habido un cambio drástico, al alza o a la baja, en el precio de Ethereum en la
fecha en que se completó la bifurcación. Al igual que con otros activos, el precio ya está descontado cuando ocurren
estos grandes eventos. Como habrás notado, hubo un aumento en el precio en los meses previos a la Fusión.</p>

<p>En el futuro, Ethereum pasará a ser un activo deflacionario. Antes de la fusión y con el PoW, se emitían diariamente 13
000 nuevos tokens de Ether. El cambio cambia esto y de 13.000 veremos alrededor de 1.600 tokens de Ether por día.</p>

<p>Cuantos menos tokens haya, mayor debería ser el precio de los tokens Ether, siendo un activo deflacionario alternativo.</p>

<h2 id="aspects-that-remain-unchanged">Aspects that remain unchanged</h2>

<p>Probablemente, algunos de los temas más comunes cuando se trata de Ethereum son las tarifas. La mala noticia es que la
lógica de estos permanece sin cambios. Estos son otros problemas que Ethereum Merge no resuelve o no se han modificado
con Merge.</p>

<h3 id="1-tarifas">1. Tarifas</h3>

<p>“La bifurcación definitivamente hará que las tarifas del gas sean más baratas”. Esto es erróneo y los cambios que
ocurrieron en la red no tuvieron ninguna consecuencia en las tarifas que se deben pagar en cada transacción de
blockchain para recompensar a los validadores de las transacciones que ocurren en la cadena. El último cambio en la red
que afectó cómo se debe pagar el Wei por transacción fue el London Upgrade en 2021.</p>

<h3 id="2-velocidad">2. Velocidad</h3>

<p>Relacionado con el dilema de blockchain, el Merge no aumenta la velocidad ni aumenta la cantidad de transacciones que se
pueden procesar por minuto. Puede haber una ligera mejora en la velocidad, pero será imperceptible para los usuarios.
Para los cambios de velocidad habrá que esperar por si algún día llega esta modificación.</p>

<h2 id="conclusiones-clave">Conclusiones clave</h2>

<p>Ha habido mucha expectación debido a este hito del Merge, y se ha esperado durante algún tiempo. Debido a todas las
noticias en torno a este tema durante el último año, estos son los principales datos que podemos decir para concluir y
ver cómo evoluciona este tema.</p>

<h3 id="impacto-medioambiental">Impacto medioambiental</h3>

<p>Este es definitivamente el mayor cambio y la principal ventaja de la actualización del software. No solo relacionado con
la crisis energética actual, este es un gran paso para proteger nuestro planeta con un uso más sensato y responsable de
la electricidad. Esto puede ser un hito clave para alcanzar la sostenibilidad en la industria crypto (aunque, por
ejemplo, no hay planes, por ejemplo, para Bitcoin y cambiar de PoW a PoS en este caso) debido a las nuevas posibilidades
en las diferentes redes y estándares que permite.</p>

<h3 id="staking-para-todos">Staking para todos</h3>

<p>Si bien validar y asegurar la red era una acción reservada para aquellos con más poder de cómputo, por lo que las
recompensas eran solo para ellos, el cambio a PoS significa que todos podemos participar asegurando las transacciones y
siendo recompensados ​​por los tokens de Ether que usamos para lograr eso</p>

<h3 id="impacto-comercial">Impacto comercial</h3>

<p>Haber reducido el uso de energía y mejorar la eficiencia energética también ha abierto nuevas ideas para Ethereum, que
ya tenía muchas aplicaciones en este ecosistema. Además, esto no solo es importante para Ethereum, sino para otras
cadenas, y también significa que la evolución de las diferentes cadenas de bloques conducirá a una mejor experiencia
para los usuarios y a más ideas de negocios que hace algunos años eran impensables por cuestiones de sostenibilidad.</p>

<hr />

<p>Habiendo explicado los cambios más importantes y también negado cosas que el Merge no cambia, es cierto que algunos de
estos cambios pueden impulsar a Ethereum y al sector de las criptomonedas. Al mismo tiempo, no se puede negar que
algunos usuarios se han decepcionado porque esperaban mucho más. El tiempo dirá.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Los cambios que el Ethereum Merge, incluyendo el impacto que crean y qué aspectos no se modifican con este fork en la red]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/ethereum/ether.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/ethereum/ether.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="enn"><title type="html">10 Benefits of HIIT</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/09/11/benefits_10_hiit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 Benefits of HIIT" /><published>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/09/11/benefits_10_hiit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/09/11/benefits_10_hiit/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        In the past years, there is being a surge on sport and health topics. We
        look more and more for some alternatives or variations of the most classic
        sports that keep evolving throughout years. One of the activities that has
        been quite trendy in the last years it’s HIIT.
    </p>
</div>

<p>
    In this post we will discuss how HIIT - High Intensity Interval Training
    works and how it may help you in your day-to-day life.
</p>
<p>
    The different advantages that HIIT has goes from mere performance
    improvement to health improvements. However, there is more than this and
    HIIT also includes some advantages to our well-being and the enjoyment of
    our activities.
</p>
<p>
    But before we start describing, in case you don’t know, what’s HITT and how
    it works?
</p>
<p>
    In simple terms, HIIT is the combination of both:
</p>
<ul>
    - High intensity intervals
</ul>
<ul>
    - Low intensity intervals that are used to recover from the high intensity
</ul>
<p>
    By high intensity intervals, it’s meant by those intervals where the heart
    rate capacity is equal to at least 80% of the maximum heart rate.
</p>
<p>
    The frequency of the high and low intensity may vary, and it can go from to
    2:1 or 1:2
</p>
<p>
    An example may be clearer if we add some numbers.
</p>
<p>
    Let’s imagine runner who performs the following steps:
</p>
<ul>
    1. 60-seconds sprint
</ul>
<ul>
    2. 120-second Low intensity jogging
</ul>
<ul>
    3. 60-seconds sprint
</ul>
<ul>
    4. 120-second Low intensity jogging
</ul>
</li>
<p>
    And like that you can play with different variations. For example, sprints
    of 60 seconds and rest 60 seconds, etc.
</p>
<p>
    The goal of the HIIT session is to give everything and end exhausted at the
    end of it.
</p>
<p>
    Starting with HIIT means also getting out of your comfort zone and it may
    be challenging for you at the beginning. Nevertheless, being progressive
    and reading the following benefits will for sure help you go to the next
    level.
</p>
<h3>
    1. Lack of time
</h3>
<p>
    We would like to have days of 48 hours, but this is not possible. With HIIT
    you can reduce your sessions to more than half of it. From a 60-minute
    low-intensity session, you can switch it to a 15/20-minute HIIT session.
</p>
<p>
    A 20-minute session will be enough to complete your daily activity and
    objectives.
</p>
<p>
    In other words, the usual 45 minutes sessions you have can be to just
    20-minute session. The minutes you don’t use can be used for any other
    thing.
</p>
<p>
    Even if shorter duration, you will with a higher sensation of completeness
    and job well done because of the work that your body does after the work.
</p>
<p>
    Further, there is no need to do these sessions every day. Since in every
    session, a lot of stress is added to your organs and muscles, 3 or 4 HITT
    sessions will be more than enough for you and your body. We will later see
    the post-process.
</p>
<p>
    This benefit is a good argument to tell people who complain that they don’t
    do any exercise because they have too many things to do and no time. Most
    of us should be able to take 20 minutes from other daily tasks.
</p>
<h3>
    2. Get fit
</h3>
<p>
    As we have described above, if you have been without performing sport for
    some time, you should start slowly with HIIT. At the same time, this is a
    great technique to get in shape quite quickly compared to low-intensity
    trainings. Therefore, it may be a good idea in case you have joined a race
    in a few months, and you should prepare it beforehand.
</p>
<h3>
    3. Multiple variations
</h3>
<p>
    Although HIIT is more associated to jogging, many sports and activities can
    be applied to this technique. This means that you can enrich your portfolio
    of exercises and increase the fun.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/diverse_hiit.jpg" alt="Cientos de maneras">
    <span class="caption text-muted">El HIIT no es exclusivo de trotar, y puedes experimentarlo de muchas maneras
</span>
</p>
<p>
    Some of the most important activies are:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Swimming
    </li>
    <li>
        Cycling
    </li>
    <li>
        Weight training
    </li>
    <li>
        Rope jumping
    </li>
    <li>
        Rowing
    </li>
    <li>
        Burpees
    </li>
    <li>
        Dancing
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
</p>
<p>
    As it occurs with nutrition, having a diversified set of exercises will
    help you not get bored and opening your mind to practice new ones.
</p>
<h3>
    4. Muscular mass
</h3>
<p>
    For professionals who compete, you may have heard different opinions about
    the different exercises and planning. Some argue that with running, they
    may lose part of their muscular mass that they have gained.
</p>
<p>
    The benefit of HIIT, linked also to the duration is that you can achieve
    the following:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Reduce the body fat
    </li>
    <li>
        Maintain the muscular mass
    </li>
    <li>
        Increase the muscular mass in the legs
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Another example is if in the Olympics or you have a look at the bodies of
    different sports.
</p>
<p>
    If you have a look at the bodies of marathon runners or long-distance
    cyclists you may see very thin athletes with low fat, but also low muscular
    mass except for the legs. The reason is that when performing these long-duration activities, the
    glucogen reserves are empty and the body starts taking energy from: fat and
    lipids.
</p>
<p>
    For that reason, HIIT is a clear win-win solution and the reason for being
    the preferred choice for many athletes.
</p>
<h3>
    5. Metabolism
</h3>
<p>
    High Intense Interval Training is also called metabolic booster. The reason is that practicing HIIT
    produces a considerable acceleration in the metabolism of our body. But why
    is that? Due to the work that is performed, our body is pushed to the next
    level. Our body is clever enough and demands a bigger amount of oxygen to
    provide to our organs: heart, lungs, etc. However, it is not that the only
    reason only.
</p>
<p>
    Apart from that, some components that were broken in the exercise must be
    restored and the energy that must be used to recover these proteins,
    tendons, etc., in the recovery phase is why our body keeps working even if
    we are in our sofa.
</p>
<p>
    This process last around 48 hours and that’s why during this time, our body
    keeps burning calories. This is another reason for just having to perform
    this activity 3-4 times per week.
</p>
<h3>
    6. Better performance
</h3>
<p>
    Depending on the activity, some parts of our body will be development.
    However, HIIT has a great impact in the performance, and you may see
    improvements in the following factors:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Speed
    </li>
    <li>
        Agility
    </li>
    <li>
        Power
    </li>
    <li>
        Resistance
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    If you practice HIIT you may have noticed that your performance in other
    sports such as swimming or cycling has also improved.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/cycling.jpg" alt="Useful for other sports">
    <span class="caption text-muted">HIIT can boost your VO2 Max levels that can be very beneficial for sports such as cycling</span>
</p>
<p>
    One common thin with these sports is the VO2 max effectiveness. VO2 max
    measures the efficiency that your body uses the oxygen while performing
    your activity. Higher VO2 Max higher performance. There is a story back to
    the times of when triathlons were created in 1970 and who would win?
    Runners, swimmers, or cyclists? Some said that cyclists would be the
    winners because back then Eddy Merckx had the highest VO2 levels.
</p>
<h2>
    7. Heart
</h2>
<p>
    Not everything must be fun and performance. One of the most important
    characteristics is related to our health. If you suffer from health issues
    such as high pressure, you will be happy to hear that runners that practice
    HIIT benefit from a much better heart health.
</p>
<p>
    Further, HIIT increases the amount of blood that the heart can pump.
</p>
<p>
    Of course, if you have some health issues, another piece of advice would be
    having some medical checks before starting practicing this technique.
</p>
<h3>
    8. Cost
</h3>
<p>
    Starting with other sports and activities means increasing the fun.
    Nonetheless, in most cases to invest in different articles (bicycle,
    dumbbells, skis, goggles, etc.) If you are already jogging, there is
    nothing that you would have to buy.
</p>
<p>
    This one is obvious, but with HIIT, you will be able to reuse the equipment
    you already have, and this will not mean an extra cost.
</p>
<h3>
    9. Kill the monotony
</h3>
<p>
    Coming back to the duration, being running at the same pace for 45 or 60
    minutes may not be the most exciting activity. If you live in a big city, you
    will not find many tracks close to your place with 45/60 minutes routes.
</p>
<p>
    Since the duration for HIIT is much shorter, this also gives you many more
    possibilities when combining the different routes.
</p>

<p>
    Related to the variations and the monotony, there are also many other
    variations that we may say in other articles. For example, you may practice
    HIIT while doing some trail or as we have seen in other sports.
</p>
<h2>
    10 Risk of injuries
</h2>
<p>
    Finalizing with another health topic, being running for 60 minutes every
    day on the road or any other hard surface may not be the most convenient
    way to keep your knees.
</p>
<p>
    I remember this was my main reason for switching to HIIT some 5-6 years
    ago.
</p>
<p>
    After 20-30 minutes low-intensity running, I had a strong pain in the left
    knee, and I had to stop running. After 3-4 times, I decided I had to reduce
    the duration of these exercises or just stop. I decided to continue but
    compensating the lower duration with a more active and high interval
    trainings. That’s how I started and ever since I did not have any problem.
</p>
<p>
    Every time we run our knees and other articulations may be subject to
    prolonged times of and a wrong way of running may lead to injuries. By
    reducing the duration of our training, we also reduce the risk of injuries
    and conserve intact our articulations.
</p>
<h2>
    What’s next
</h2>
<p>
    In conclusion, you have seen different advantages of practicing HIIT. It
    may sound challenging for you at the beginning, but I can assure you that
    this will not deceive you and will push your body to the next level.
</p>
<p>
    We have found what the different benefits in terms of time, fun, health, and
    performance are. As discussed in one of the points, trying is free, and you may start with a just 10-minute session
    to give it a
    try.
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[From performance to health, what HIIT can add to your daily routines]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">10 Benefits of HIIT</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/10-benefits-hiit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 Benefits of HIIT" /><published>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/10-benefits-hiit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/10-benefits-hiit/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        In the past years, there is being a surge on sport and health topics. We
        look more and more for some alternatives or variations of the most classic
        sports that keep evolving throughout years. One of the activities that has
        been quite trendy in the last years it’s HIIT.
    </p>
</div>

<p>
    In this post we will discuss how HIIT - High Intensity Interval Training
    works and how it may help you in your day-to-day life.
</p>
<p>
    The different advantages that HIIT has goes from mere performance
    improvement to health improvements. However, there is more than this and
    HIIT also includes some advantages to our well-being and the enjoyment of
    our activities.
</p>
<p>
    But before we start describing, in case you don’t know, what’s HITT and how
    it works?
</p>
<p>
    In simple terms, HIIT is the combination of both:
</p>
<ul>
    - High intensity intervals
</ul>
<ul>
    - Low intensity intervals that are used to recover from the high intensity
</ul>
<p>
    By high intensity intervals, it’s meant by those intervals where the heart
    rate capacity is equal to at least 80% of the maximum heart rate.
</p>
<p>
    The frequency of the high and low intensity may vary, and it can go from to
    2:1 or 1:2
</p>
<p>
    An example may be clearer if we add some numbers.
</p>
<p>
    Let’s imagine runner who performs the following steps:
</p>
<ul>
    1. 60-seconds sprint
</ul>
<ul>
    2. 120-second Low intensity jogging
</ul>
<ul>
    3. 60-seconds sprint
</ul>
<ul>
    4. 120-second Low intensity jogging
</ul>
</li>
<p>
    And like that you can play with different variations. For example, sprints
    of 60 seconds and rest 60 seconds, etc.
</p>
<p>
    The goal of the HIIT session is to give everything and end exhausted at the
    end of it.
</p>
<p>
    Starting with HIIT means also getting out of your comfort zone and it may
    be challenging for you at the beginning. Nevertheless, being progressive
    and reading the following benefits will for sure help you go to the next
    level.
</p>
<h3>
    1. Lack of time
</h3>
<p>
    We would like to have days of 48 hours, but this is not possible. With HIIT
    you can reduce your sessions to more than half of it. From a 60-minute
    low-intensity session, you can switch it to a 15/20-minute HIIT session.
</p>
<p>
    A 20-minute session will be enough to complete your daily activity and
    objectives.
</p>
<p>
    In other words, the usual 45 minutes sessions you have can be to just
    20-minute session. The minutes you don’t use can be used for any other
    thing.
</p>
<p>
    Even if shorter duration, you will with a higher sensation of completeness
    and job well done because of the work that your body does after the work.
</p>
<p>
    Further, there is no need to do these sessions every day. Since in every
    session, a lot of stress is added to your organs and muscles, 3 or 4 HITT
    sessions will be more than enough for you and your body. We will later see
    the post-process.
</p>
<p>
    This benefit is a good argument to tell people who complain that they don’t
    do any exercise because they have too many things to do and no time. Most
    of us should be able to take 20 minutes from other daily tasks.
</p>
<h3>
    2. Get fit
</h3>
<p>
    As we have described above, if you have been without performing sport for
    some time, you should start slowly with HIIT. At the same time, this is a
    great technique to get in shape quite quickly compared to low-intensity
    trainings. Therefore, it may be a good idea in case you have joined a race
    in a few months, and you should prepare it beforehand.
</p>
<h3>
    3. Multiple variations
</h3>
<p>
    Although HIIT is more associated to jogging, many sports and activities can
    be applied to this technique. This means that you can enrich your portfolio
    of exercises and increase the fun.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/diverse_hiit.jpg" alt="Cientos de maneras">
    <span class="caption text-muted">El HIIT no es exclusivo de trotar, y puedes experimentarlo de muchas maneras
</span>
</p>
<p>
    Some of the most important activies are:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Swimming
    </li>
    <li>
        Cycling
    </li>
    <li>
        Weight training
    </li>
    <li>
        Rope jumping
    </li>
    <li>
        Rowing
    </li>
    <li>
        Burpees
    </li>
    <li>
        Dancing
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
</p>
<p>
    As it occurs with nutrition, having a diversified set of exercises will
    help you not get bored and opening your mind to practice new ones.
</p>
<h3>
    4. Muscular mass
</h3>
<p>
    For professionals who compete, you may have heard different opinions about
    the different exercises and planning. Some argue that with running, they
    may lose part of their muscular mass that they have gained.
</p>
<p>
    The benefit of HIIT, linked also to the duration is that you can achieve
    the following:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Reduce the body fat
    </li>
    <li>
        Maintain the muscular mass
    </li>
    <li>
        Increase the muscular mass in the legs
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Another example is if in the Olympics or you have a look at the bodies of
    different sports.
</p>
<p>
    If you have a look at the bodies of marathon runners or long-distance
    cyclists you may see very thin athletes with low fat, but also low muscular
    mass except for the legs. The reason is that when performing these long-duration activities, the
    glucogen reserves are empty and the body starts taking energy from: fat and
    lipids.
</p>
<p>
    For that reason, HIIT is a clear win-win solution and the reason for being
    the preferred choice for many athletes.
</p>
<h3>
    5. Metabolism
</h3>
<p>
    High Intense Interval Training is also called metabolic booster. The reason is that practicing HIIT
    produces a considerable acceleration in the metabolism of our body. But why
    is that? Due to the work that is performed, our body is pushed to the next
    level. Our body is clever enough and demands a bigger amount of oxygen to
    provide to our organs: heart, lungs, etc. However, it is not that the only
    reason only.
</p>
<p>
    Apart from that, some components that were broken in the exercise must be
    restored and the energy that must be used to recover these proteins,
    tendons, etc., in the recovery phase is why our body keeps working even if
    we are in our sofa.
</p>
<p>
    This process last around 48 hours and that’s why during this time, our body
    keeps burning calories. This is another reason for just having to perform
    this activity 3-4 times per week.
</p>
<h3>
    6. Better performance
</h3>
<p>
    Depending on the activity, some parts of our body will be development.
    However, HIIT has a great impact in the performance, and you may see
    improvements in the following factors:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Speed
    </li>
    <li>
        Agility
    </li>
    <li>
        Power
    </li>
    <li>
        Resistance
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    If you practice HIIT you may have noticed that your performance in other
    sports such as swimming or cycling has also improved.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/cycling.jpg" alt="Useful for other sports">
    <span class="caption text-muted">HIIT can boost your VO2 Max levels that can be very beneficial for sports such as cycling</span>
</p>
<p>
    One common thin with these sports is the VO2 max effectiveness. VO2 max
    measures the efficiency that your body uses the oxygen while performing
    your activity. Higher VO2 Max higher performance. There is a story back to
    the times of when triathlons were created in 1970 and who would win?
    Runners, swimmers, or cyclists? Some said that cyclists would be the
    winners because back then Eddy Merckx had the highest VO2 levels.
</p>
<h2>
    7. Heart
</h2>
<p>
    Not everything must be fun and performance. One of the most important
    characteristics is related to our health. If you suffer from health issues
    such as high pressure, you will be happy to hear that runners that practice
    HIIT benefit from a much better heart health.
</p>
<p>
    Further, HIIT increases the amount of blood that the heart can pump.
</p>
<p>
    Of course, if you have some health issues, another piece of advice would be
    having some medical checks before starting practicing this technique.
</p>
<h3>
    8. Cost
</h3>
<p>
    Starting with other sports and activities means increasing the fun.
    Nonetheless, in most cases to invest in different articles (bicycle,
    dumbbells, skis, goggles, etc.) If you are already jogging, there is
    nothing that you would have to buy.
</p>
<p>
    This one is obvious, but with HIIT, you will be able to reuse the equipment
    you already have, and this will not mean an extra cost.
</p>
<h3>
    9. Kill the monotony
</h3>
<p>
    Coming back to the duration, being running at the same pace for 45 or 60
    minutes may not be the most exciting activity. If you live in a big city, you
    will not find many tracks close to your place with 45/60 minutes routes.
</p>
<p>
    Since the duration for HIIT is much shorter, this also gives you many more
    possibilities when combining the different routes.
</p>

<p>
    Related to the variations and the monotony, there are also many other
    variations that we may say in other articles. For example, you may practice
    HIIT while doing some trail or as we have seen in other sports.
</p>
<h2>
    10 Risk of injuries
</h2>
<p>
    Finalizing with another health topic, being running for 60 minutes every
    day on the road or any other hard surface may not be the most convenient
    way to keep your knees.
</p>
<p>
    I remember this was my main reason for switching to HIIT some 5-6 years
    ago.
</p>
<p>
    After 20-30 minutes low-intensity running, I had a strong pain in the left
    knee, and I had to stop running. After 3-4 times, I decided I had to reduce
    the duration of these exercises or just stop. I decided to continue but
    compensating the lower duration with a more active and high interval
    trainings. That’s how I started and ever since I did not have any problem.
</p>
<p>
    Every time we run our knees and other articulations may be subject to
    prolonged times of and a wrong way of running may lead to injuries. By
    reducing the duration of our training, we also reduce the risk of injuries
    and conserve intact our articulations.
</p>
<h2>
    What’s next
</h2>
<p>
    In conclusion, you have seen different advantages of practicing HIIT. It
    may sound challenging for you at the beginning, but I can assure you that
    this will not deceive you and will push your body to the next level.
</p>
<p>
    We have found what the different benefits in terms of time, fun, health, and
    performance are. As discussed in one of the points, trying is free, and you may start with a just 10-minute session
    to give it a
    try.
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[From performance to health, what HIIT can add to your daily routines]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="es"><title type="html">10 Beneficios del HIIT</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/10_beneficios_hiit" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 Beneficios del HIIT" /><published>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/10-beneficios-hiit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/10_beneficios_hiit"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introducción
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        En los últimos años, ha habido un auge en temas de deporte y salud. Cada vez buscamos más algunas alternativas o
        variaciones de los deportes más clásicos que van evolucionando a lo largo de los años. Una de las actividades
        que ha estado bastante de moda en los últimos años es el HIIT.
    </p>
</div>

<p>
    En este post hablaremos de cómo funciona el HIIT (High Intensity Interval Training) - Entrenamiento Interválico de Alta Intensidad y cómo puede
    ayudarte en tu día a día.
</p>
<p>
    Las diferentes ventajas que tiene el HIIT van desde la mera mejora del rendimiento hasta la mejora de la salud. Sin
    embargo, hay más que esto y el HIIT también incluye algunas ventajas para nuestro bienestar y el disfrute de
    nuestras actividades.


</p>
<p>
    Pero antes de comenzar a describir, en caso de que no lo sepas, ¿qué es el HITT y cómo funciona?


</p>
<p>
    En términos simples, HIIT es la combinación de lo siguiente
</p>
<ul>
    - Intervalos de alta intensidad
</ul>
<ul>
    - Intervalos de baja intensidad que se utilizan para recuperarse de la alta intensidad
</ul>
<p>
    Por intervalos de alta intensidad se entiende aquellos intervalos en los que la capacidad de frecuencia cardiaca es
    igual al menos al 80% de la frecuencia cardiaca máxima.
</p>
<p>
    La frecuencia de la intensidad alta y baja puede variar, y puede ir desde relaciones 2:1 o 1:2.
</p>
<p>
    Un ejemplo puede ser más claro si agregamos algunos números.
</p>
<p>
    Imaginemos un corredor que realiza los siguientes pasos:

</p>
<ul>
    1. Sprint de 60 segundos
</ul>
<ul>
    2. Trote de baja intensidad de 120 segundos
</ul>
<ul>
    3. Sprint de 60 segundos
</ul>
<ul>
    4. Trote de baja intensidad de 120 segundos
</ul>
</li>
<p>
    Y así puedes jugar con diferentes variaciones. Por ejemplo, sprints de 60 segundos y descanso de 60 segundos, etc.

</p>
<p>
    El objetivo de la sesión de HIIT es darlo todo y acabar agotado al final de la misma.

</p>
<p>
    Comenzar con HIIT también significa salir de tu zona de confort y puede ser un desafío para ti al principio. Sin
    embargo, ser progresista y leer los siguientes beneficios seguramente lo ayudará a pasar al siguiente nivel.


</p>
<h3>
    1. Falta de tiempo
</h3>
<p>
    Nos gustaría tener días de 48 horas, pero esto no es posible. Con HIIT puedes reducir tus sesiones a más de la
    mitad. De una sesión de baja intensidad de 60 minutos, puedes pasar a una sesión de HIIT de 15/20 minutos.


</p>
<p>
    Una sesión de 20 minutos será suficiente para completar tu actividad y objetivos diarios.


</p>
<p>
    En otras palabras, las sesiones habituales de 45 minutos que tienes pueden ser de solo 20 minutos. Los minutos que
    no uses los puedes usar para cualquier otra cosa.


</p>
<p>
    Aunque sea de menor duración, lo harás con una mayor sensación de plenitud y trabajo bien hecho por el trabajo que
    realiza tu cuerpo después del trabajo.


</p>
<p>
    Además, no hay necesidad de hacer estas sesiones todos los días. Como en cada sesión se añade mucho estrés a tus
    órganos y músculos, 3 o 4 sesiones de HITT serán más que suficientes para ti y tu cuerpo. Más adelante veremos el
    post-proceso.


</p>
<p>
    Este beneficio es un buen argumento para decirle a la gente que se queja de que no hace nada de ejercicio porque
    tiene demasiadas cosas que hacer y no tiene tiempo. La mayoría de nosotros debería poder tomar 20 minutos de otras
    tareas diarias.


</p>
<h3>
    2. Ponte en forma
</h3>
<p>
    Aunque el HIIT está más asociado al jogging, a esta técnica se le pueden aplicar muchos deportes y actividades. Esto
    significa que puede enriquecer su cartera de ejercicios y aumentar la diversión.


</p>
<h3>
    3. Multiples combinaciones
</h3>
<p>
    Aunque el HIIT está más asociado a correr, a esta técnica se le pueden aplicar muchos deportes y actividades. Esto
    significa que puede enriquecer su cartera de ejercicios y aumentar la diversión.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/diverse_hiit.jpg" alt="Cientos de maneras">
    <span class="caption text-muted">El HIIT no es exclusivo de trotar, y puedes experimentarlo de muchas maneras
</span>
</p>
<p>
    Algunas de las actividades más populares son:
</p>

<ul>
    <li>
        Natación
    </li>
    <li>
        Ciclismo
    </li>
    <li>
        Entrenamiento con pesast training
    </li>
    <li>
        Saltar a la comba
    </li>
    <li>
        Remo
    </li>
    <li>
        Burpees
    </li>
    <li>
        Bailar
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
</p>
<p>
    Al igual que ocurre con la nutrición, tener un conjunto diversificado de ejercicios te ayudará a no aburrirte y a
    abrir tu mente para practicar nuevos.


</p>
<h3>
    4. Masa muscular
</h3>
<p>
    Para los profesionales que compiten, es posible que haya escuchado diferentes opiniones sobre los diferentes
    ejercicios y la planificación. Algunos argumentan que al correr pueden perder parte de la masa muscular que han
    ganado.


</p>
<p>
    El beneficio del HIIT, ligado también a la duración, es que puedes conseguir lo siguiente:


</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Reducir la grasa corporal
    </li>
    <li>
        Mantener la masa muscular

    </li>
    <li>
        Aumentar la masa muscular en las piernas.

    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Otro ejemplo es si en las Olimpiadas o si echas un vistazo a los cuerpos de diferentes deportes.


</p>
<p>
    Si observas los cuerpos de los corredores de maratón o ciclistas de larga distancia, es posible que vea atletas muy
    delgados con poca grasa, pero también poca masa muscular, excepto en las piernas. La razón es que mientras se
    practican estos deportes de larga duración, las reservas de glucógeno se vacían y el cuerpo empieza a tomar energía
    de: grasas y lípidos.


</p>
<p>
    Por esa razón, HIIT es una solución win-win y la razón de ser la opción preferida por muchos atletas.


</p>
<h3>
    5. Metabolismo
</h3>
<p>
    El entrenamiento de intervalos de alta intensidad también se denomina refuerzo metabólico. El motivo es que
    practicar HIIT produce una aceleración considerable en el metabolismo de nuestro cuerpo. Pero ¿por qué es eso?
    Debido al trabajo que se realiza, nuestro cuerpo es empujado al siguiente nivel. Nuestro cuerpo es lo
    suficientemente inteligente y exige una mayor cantidad de oxígeno para proporcionar a nuestros órganos: corazón,
    pulmones, etc. Sin embargo, no es esa la única razón.


</p>
<p>
    Aparte de eso, hay que reponer algunos componentes que se rompieron en el ejercicio y la energía que hay que emplear
    para recuperar estas proteínas, tendones, etc., en la fase de recuperación es por lo que nuestro cuerpo sigue
    funcionando aunque estemos en el sofá.


</p>
<p>
    Este proceso dura alrededor de 48 horas y es por eso que durante este tiempo, nuestro cuerpo sigue quemando
    calorías. Esta es otra razón para tener que realizar esta actividad 3 o 4 veces por semana.


</p>
<h3>
    6. Mejor rendimiento
</h3>
<p>
    Dependiendo de la actividad, algunas partes de nuestro cuerpo se desarrollarán. Sin embargo, HIIT tiene un gran
    impacto en el rendimiento y es posible que vea mejoras en los siguientes factores:


</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Velocidad
    </li>
    <li>
        Agilidad
    </li>
    <li>
        Potencia y Energía
    </li>
    <li>
        Resistencia
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Si practicas HIIT habrás notado que tu rendimiento en otros deportes como la natación o el ciclismo también ha
    mejorado.


</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/cycling.jpg" alt="Useful for other sports">
    <span class="caption text-muted">El HIIT puede aumentar sus niveles de VO2 Max, lo que puede ser muy beneficioso para deportes como el ciclismo.
</span>
</p>
<p>
    Una característica común de estos deportes es la efectividad máxima del VO2. VO2 max mide la eficiencia con la que
    tu cuerpo utiliza el oxígeno mientras realizas tu actividad. Mayor VO2 Max mayor rendimiento. Hay una historia que
    se remonta a los tiempos en que se crearon los triatlones en 1970 y ¿quién ganaría? ¿Corredores, nadadores o
    ciclistas? Algunos dijeron que los ciclistas serían los ganadores porque en ese entonces Eddy Merckx tenía los
    niveles más altos de VO2.


</p>
<h2>
    7. Corazón
</h2>
<p>
    No todo debe ser diversión y rendimiento. Una de las características más importantes está relacionada con nuestra
    salud. Si sufres problemas de salud como presión alta, te alegrará saber que los corredores que practican HIIT se
    benefician de una salud cardíaca mucho mejor.


</p>
<p>
    Además, HIIT aumenta la cantidad de sangre que el corazón puede bombear.


</p>
<p>
    Por supuesto, si tienes algún problema de salud, otro consejo sería hacerte unos controles médicos antes de empezar
    a practicar esta técnica.


</p>
<h3>
    8. Coste
</h3>
<p>
    Comenzar con otros deportes y actividades significa aumentar la diversión. No obstante, en la mayoría de los casos
    invertir en diferentes artículos (bicicleta, mancuernas, esquís, gafas, etc.) Si ya estás haciendo jogging, no hay
    nada que tengas que comprar.


</p>
<p>
    Esto es obvio, pero con HIIT podrás reutilizar el equipo que ya tienes, y esto no supondrá un coste extra.


</p>
<h3>
    9. Mata la monotonía
</h3>
<p>
    Volviendo a la duración, correr al mismo ritmo durante 45 o 60 minutos puede no ser la actividad más emocionante. Si
    vives en una gran ciudad, no encontrarás muchas pistas cerca de tu casa con rutas de 45/60 minutos.


</p>
<p>
    Dado que la duración del HIIT es mucho más corta, esto también te da muchas más posibilidades a la hora de combinar
    las diferentes rutas.


</p>
<p>
    Relacionado con las variaciones y la monotonía, también hay muchas otras variaciones que podemos decir en otros
    artículos. Por ejemplo, puedes practicar HIIT mientras haces algún trail o como hemos visto en otros deportes.


</p>
<h2>
    10 Riesgo de lesiones
</h2>
<p>
    Finalizando con otro tema de salud, estar corriendo 60 minutos todos los días en la carretera o cualquier otra
    superficie dura puede no ser la forma más conveniente de mantener las rodillas.


</p>
<p>
    Recuerdo que esta fue mi razón principal para cambiarme a HIIT hace unos 5 o 6 años.


</p>
<p>
    Después de 20-30 minutos de carrera a baja intensidad, tuve un fuerte dolor en la rodilla izquierda y tuve que dejar
    de correr. Después de 3 o 4 veces, decidí que tenía que reducir la duración de estos ejercicios o simplemente parar.
    Decidí continuar pero compensando la menor duración con entrenamientos más activos e interválicos. Así empecé y
    desde entonces no he tenido ningún problema.


</p>
<p>
    Cada vez que corremos nuestras rodillas y otras articulaciones pueden estar sujetas a tiempos prolongados y una
    forma incorrecta de correr puede derivar en lesiones. Al reducir la duración de nuestro entrenamiento, también
    reducimos el riesgo de lesiones y conservamos intactas nuestras articulaciones.


</p>
<h2>
    ¿Qué viene ahora?
</h2>
<p>
    Para concluir, has visto diferentes ventajas de practicar HIIT. Puede sonar desafiante para ti al
    principio, pero puedo asegurarte que esto no te engañará y llevará tu cuerpo al siguiente nivel.

</p>
<p>
    Hemos observado diferentes beneficios en términos de tiempo, diversión, salud y rendimiento. Como se discutió en uno
    de
    los puntos, probar es gratis y puede comenzar con una sesión de solo 10 minutos para intentarlo.


</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Desde rendimiento a salud, que puede el HIIT añadir a tus rutinas]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="enn"><title type="html">Learn and Earn Crypto</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/28/learn_and_earn_crypto/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learn and Earn Crypto" /><published>2022-08-28T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-08-28T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/08/28/learn_and_earn_crypto</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/28/learn_and_earn_crypto/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        Some centuries ago, different organizations across Europe and Asia were
        accused of conspiracies and polemics. Mostly these accusations were
        provoked by the information that these sects or groups kept for themselves.
        or Myth or reality, what cannot be denied is that in the Middle Ages,
        knowledge was something considered hermetic and exclusive to certain groups
        that wisdom for them and the exclusive members of their circle.
    </p>
</div>
<p>
    Fortunately, things have changed in the last decades and in this era of
    information, we have more access to things we could not have imagined a few
    years ago. On the other hand, it may be shocking and paradoxical that in
    this era, we are less cultivated and informed.
</p>
<br>
<p align="center">
    <em>
        "If money is your hope for independence you will never have it. The only
        real security that a man will have in this world is a reserve of
        knowledge, experience, and ability."
    </em> -
    <strong>
        Henry Ford    </strong>

</p>
<br>
<p>
    Knowledge is enough motivation for most of us to learn about new topics,
    but apart what if I tell you that apart from learning interesting topics
    and state of the art technologies you can also get rewarded?
</p>
<p>
    As discussed in previous articles, the best investment you can make is
    learning. It’s undeniable the benefits that the continuous learning brings
    in the long term.
</p>
<p>
    Although, learning by itself is already a rewarding and motivating
    activity, some of use will also appreciate additional bonuses. Keeping us updated is important in the competitive world we all live in.
    Not just for now, but for future years.
    By reward, I don’t mean just the new information or benefits you get, but
    new tokens, coins, or discounts you may get.
</p>
<p>
    This post is not merely about getting free coins, but also new skills that
    you can get and apply in your professional world. Let’s dig deeper to see
    what these options are.
</p>
<br>
<h2>
    Learn to Earn Programs
</h2>
<p>
    The first group of this article is related to those programs where you
    learn the theory, or the basic concepts of a given blockchain or token. In
    the subsections below, you don’t just learn something new, but you also
    have the chance of getting rewarded with crypto currencies.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/learn_earn/coinbase.jpg" alt="Pioneer">
    <span class="caption text-muted">In the Learning Rewards Section you can see different articles, courses and quizzes</span>
</p>
<p>
    These are some of the most famous Learn to Earn programs out there, where
    you learn interesting new topics and you are rewarded in different manners.
</p>
<p>
    Please bear in mind that these courses do not have any requirements such as
    “deposit 10 to earn 20, etc.”. Apart from learning and reading/watching the
    information, the only other requirement is that in some cases you may need
    to verify and pass the KYC checks.
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Coinbase
</h3>
<p>
    Coinbase is sometimes criticized for different reasons such as
    business-related topics (dismissal of employees, business plan) or the
    trading fees. However, since they started in 2018, they have promoted
    different initiatives in the crypto community. One of the most famous ones
    is the Learning Rewards program, where users can earn different tokens. The
    process is quite easy and just watching a short video and answering some
    questions you can get some free tokens.
</p>
<p>
    There is no surprise here and you can exchange as soon as you receive. The
    rewards are not a big amount, but, lately, they tend to occur quite often.
    Regardless of the rewards, videos are nice to watch and very well done. In
    addition to these videos, you may also see different articles.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Coinbase Information</h5>
            One of the first ones to start with this initiative, Coinbase keeps offering these courses from time to time<br>
            <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/learn/tips-and-tutorials/how-to-earn-crypto-rewards">Coinbase Learning Rewards</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Binance
</h3>
<p>
    Binance is without any doubt, the largest crypto exchange in the world. In
    my opinion, the initially based Chinese exchange may be quite annoying with
    several daily notifications, but Changpeng Zhao’s organization have also
    several nice initiatives for their customers.
</p>
<p>
    Since 2022, they have followed what Coinbase started and offer some small
    rewards for watching some videos and answering different questions. There
    are several courses, and the rewards are quite small. However, it is nice
    to understand and be aware of new projects, and in addition to learning and
    getting new ideas, being rewarded for so.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Binance Information</h5>
            Binance offers several short courses about new altcoins and tradings<br>
            <a href="https://academy.binance.com/en/learn-and-earn">Binance Learn and Earn</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Cake DeFi
</h3>
<p>
    Cake DeFi is a quite new player in the Decentralized Finance sector and now
    quite known for many people. However, with their current solutions, it is
    likely that you will get hear from them more and more. They are a company
    based in Singapore specialized in passive income, being the main pillars of
    these platform the following s
</p>
<p>
    1. Liquidity mining: as opposed to centralized exchanges, in a DEX, liquidity
    is needed in order to enable trades between the different pairs. With
    liquidity mining you provide your crypto assets so other can use these to
    trade.
</p>
<p>
    2. Staking: Via the Proof of Stake protocol, you lock your tokens to protect
    the network., and you get rewarded with additional tokens
</p>
<p>
    3. Lending: The last strategy one is income generated from lending your coins
    to other DeFi participants.
</p>
<p>
    With the available courses, you can at the moment earn the following
    tokens.
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        DFI (DeFiChain) tokens
    </li>
    <li>
        BTC-DFI Tokens
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Both of them are allocated to Staking and Liquidity mining, but after you
    unfreeze them you can do whatever you want with the coins you got in the
    courses plus the ones you got from the freeze period.
</p>
<p>
    There is also a course coming soon related to Ethereum, where you will also
    learn something new and get rewarded.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Cake DeFi Information</h5>
            With short quizzes you can learn different Decentralized Finance and crypto topics while you have fun<br>
            <a href="https://app.cakedefi.com/learn">Cake DeFi Learn</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Revolut
</h3>
<p>
    Revolut is very good for many aspects such as banking, currency conversion,
    travelling and the super cool features of the app such as virtual cards or
    instant transfers. However, when it comes to their investment features such
    as purchasing stock or crypto, there are still some aspects that should be
    improved.
</p>
<p>
    That’s probably why in order to take off, Revolut has launched a Learn
    &amp; Earn Program related to Polkadot. Compared to other courses, the
    lessons are related to one of the most important blockchains and the
    amounts are also higher.
</p>
<p>
    In addition to the videos, you have also the option to see the glossary,
    where some important crypto and blockchain terms are explained.
</p>
<p>
    There is no referral program here and you will get those tokens for you.
    You decide if you want to sell them for fiat or exchange them the moment
    you receive them.

<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Revolut Information</h5>
            The purpose of the program is to learn about a specific cryptocurrency and familiarise with the world of crypto.
            <br>
            <a href="https://www.revolut.com/legal/crypto-learn-and-earn/">Revolut Learn & Earn Site</a>            <br>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h2>
    Technical Courses & Sites
</h2>
<p>
    Although the previous courses will reward you with direct tokens and the
    ones below will not, given the lack of technical skills that we will see in
    the future, the courses below may have a more relevant reward in upcoming
    years.
</p>
<p>
    Once we have focused described the most important courses related to
    business and blockchains, we can also get more technical and in this
    matter, there are also very good courses to add new skills.
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Uniswap
</h3>
<p>
    Uniswap, named as the name of the company that created it, is one of the most famous decentralized exchanges. Apart from the
    exchange and being an example of governance, Uniswap explains clearly very
    important topics related to DeFi.
</p>
<p>
    They offer some projects located in GitHub and the open-source interface
    for their protocol is available in GitHub.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/learn_earn/uniswap.jpg" alt="Building a great community of developers">
    <span class="Regardless of the background, you may find many resources for different topics"></span>
</p>
<p>
    On top of these resources and what you may swap or earn in the exchange,
    you can also build different apps that integrate with the protocol and get
    paid from their grant program.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Uniswap Information</h5>
            With the detailed documentation, you can learn about different topics and contribute to UniSwap in infinite ways.
            <br>
            <a href="https://uniswap.org/">Uniswap Site</a>            <br>
            <a href="https://docs.uniswap.org/">Documentation Uniswap</a>
            <br>
            <a href="https://github.com/Uniswap/interface">
                Uniswap Interface
            </a>

        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Ethernaut
</h3>
<p>
    Probably you have been hearing recently about the Ethereum Merge and the
    consequences that the fork may have not just for the Ethereum network but
    the whole crypto scene. Ethernaut is a war game played in an Ethereum
    Virtual Machine. developed by the OpenZeppelin, Ethernaut is a Web3
    application developed with Solidity, where you can also learn this
    programming language.
</p>
<p>
    The purpose of the game is both having fun and learning about Ethereum with
    different coding exercises at the same time you assimilate understand the
    Ethereum concepts with some practice.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Ethernaut Information</h5>
            Inpspired by other game             <a
                href="https://overthewire.org/"
        >
            overthewire.org
        </a>, each level of Ethernaut is a Smart Contract that you must hack to pass the level.<br>
            <a
                    href="https://ethernaut.openzeppelin.com/"
            >
                Visit Ethernaut
            </a><br>
            <a href="https://github.com/OpenZeppelin/ethernaut">
                Visit GitHub Ethernaut
            </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Crypto Zombies
</h3>
<p>
    Similar to Ethernaut, Crypto Zombies is a game where you can build a Zombie
    Factory to build your personal army composed of unique zombies.
</p>
<p>
    Once you have created the zombies, the fun is not over. It’s now where you
    can fight other learners’ armies. Furthermore, you also get unique
    collectibles like other games. As with Ethernaut, you will also learn
    blockchain specific topics such as ERC721, Web3 or zkSync, making this
    website quite complete in order to have basic knowledge about dApp
    creation.
</p>

<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Crypto Zombies Information</h5>
            With Crypto Zombies, the player can learn every aspect of how blockchains works while having fun.
        <br>
            <a href="https://cryptozombies.io/">
            Visit Crypto Zombies
        </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>
    As with many things in life, the best learning is practicing. Therefore,
    simple, or complex, why don’t start creating your own project once you know
    the basics? We are privileged to live in an era where information is
    accessible for everyone with infinite level of resources.
</p>
<p>
    As you may see from the links, the technical courses may require more time,
    so it would be better to start learning the basic concepts from the first websites.
</p>
<p>
    With new technologies and the expected growth, these technologies will
    eliminate several jobs, but there will a job shortage and companies not
    able to hire new talent because there are too few professionals with the
    required skills. One of them may be blockchain and everything that
    surrounds this industry.
</p>
<br>
<p align="center">

    <em>
        "Live as if you were to die tomorrow. Learn as if you were to live
        forever.”
    </em>
    — <strong>Mahatma Gandhi</strong>
</p>
<br>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn about crypto and get rewarded for your knowledge]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/learn_earn/learn_earn.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/learn_earn/learn_earn.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Learn and Earn Crypto</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/learn-and-earn-crypto/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learn and Earn Crypto" /><published>2022-08-28T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-08-28T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/learn-and-earn-crypto</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/learn-and-earn-crypto/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        Some centuries ago, different organizations across Europe and Asia were
        accused of conspiracies and polemics. Mostly these accusations were
        provoked by the information that these sects or groups kept for themselves.
        or Myth or reality, what cannot be denied is that in the Middle Ages,
        knowledge was something considered hermetic and exclusive to certain groups
        that wisdom for them and the exclusive members of their circle.
    </p>
</div>
<p>
    Fortunately, things have changed in the last decades and in this era of
    information, we have more access to things we could not have imagined a few
    years ago. On the other hand, it may be shocking and paradoxical that in
    this era, we are less cultivated and informed.
</p>
<br>
<p align="center">
    <em>
        "If money is your hope for independence you will never have it. The only
        real security that a man will have in this world is a reserve of
        knowledge, experience, and ability."
    </em> -
    <strong>
        Henry Ford    </strong>

</p>
<br>
<p>
    Knowledge is enough motivation for most of us to learn about new topics,
    but apart what if I tell you that apart from learning interesting topics
    and state of the art technologies you can also get rewarded?
</p>
<p>
    As discussed in previous articles, the best investment you can make is
    learning. It’s undeniable the benefits that the continuous learning brings
    in the long term.
</p>
<p>
    Although, learning by itself is already a rewarding and motivating
    activity, some of use will also appreciate additional bonuses. Keeping us updated is important in the competitive world we all live in.
    Not just for now, but for future years.
    By reward, I don’t mean just the new information or benefits you get, but
    new tokens, coins, or discounts you may get.
</p>
<p>
    This post is not merely about getting free coins, but also new skills that
    you can get and apply in your professional world. Let’s dig deeper to see
    what these options are.
</p>
<br>
<h2>
    Learn to Earn Programs
</h2>
<p>
    The first group of this article is related to those programs where you
    learn the theory, or the basic concepts of a given blockchain or token. In
    the subsections below, you don’t just learn something new, but you also
    have the chance of getting rewarded with crypto currencies.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/learn_earn/coinbase.jpg" alt="Pioneer">
    <span class="caption text-muted">In the Learning Rewards Section you can see different articles, courses and quizzes</span>
</p>
<p>
    These are some of the most famous Learn to Earn programs out there, where
    you learn interesting new topics and you are rewarded in different manners.
</p>
<p>
    Please bear in mind that these courses do not have any requirements such as
    “deposit 10 to earn 20, etc.”. Apart from learning and reading/watching the
    information, the only other requirement is that in some cases you may need
    to verify and pass the KYC checks.
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Coinbase
</h3>
<p>
    Coinbase is sometimes criticized for different reasons such as
    business-related topics (dismissal of employees, business plan) or the
    trading fees. However, since they started in 2018, they have promoted
    different initiatives in the crypto community. One of the most famous ones
    is the Learning Rewards program, where users can earn different tokens. The
    process is quite easy and just watching a short video and answering some
    questions you can get some free tokens.
</p>
<p>
    There is no surprise here and you can exchange as soon as you receive. The
    rewards are not a big amount, but, lately, they tend to occur quite often.
    Regardless of the rewards, videos are nice to watch and very well done. In
    addition to these videos, you may also see different articles.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Coinbase Information</h5>
            One of the first ones to start with this initiative, Coinbase keeps offering these courses from time to time<br>
            <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/learn/tips-and-tutorials/how-to-earn-crypto-rewards">Coinbase Learning Rewards</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Binance
</h3>
<p>
    Binance is without any doubt, the largest crypto exchange in the world. In
    my opinion, the initially based Chinese exchange may be quite annoying with
    several daily notifications, but Changpeng Zhao’s organization have also
    several nice initiatives for their customers.
</p>
<p>
    Since 2022, they have followed what Coinbase started and offer some small
    rewards for watching some videos and answering different questions. There
    are several courses, and the rewards are quite small. However, it is nice
    to understand and be aware of new projects, and in addition to learning and
    getting new ideas, being rewarded for so.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Binance Information</h5>
            Binance offers several short courses about new altcoins and tradings<br>
            <a href="https://academy.binance.com/en/learn-and-earn">Binance Learn and Earn</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Cake DeFi
</h3>
<p>
    Cake DeFi is a quite new player in the Decentralized Finance sector and now
    quite known for many people. However, with their current solutions, it is
    likely that you will get hear from them more and more. They are a company
    based in Singapore specialized in passive income, being the main pillars of
    these platform the following s
</p>
<p>
    1. Liquidity mining: as opposed to centralized exchanges, in a DEX, liquidity
    is needed in order to enable trades between the different pairs. With
    liquidity mining you provide your crypto assets so other can use these to
    trade.
</p>
<p>
    2. Staking: Via the Proof of Stake protocol, you lock your tokens to protect
    the network., and you get rewarded with additional tokens
</p>
<p>
    3. Lending: The last strategy one is income generated from lending your coins
    to other DeFi participants.
</p>
<p>
    With the available courses, you can at the moment earn the following
    tokens.
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        DFI (DeFiChain) tokens
    </li>
    <li>
        BTC-DFI Tokens
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Both of them are allocated to Staking and Liquidity mining, but after you
    unfreeze them you can do whatever you want with the coins you got in the
    courses plus the ones you got from the freeze period.
</p>
<p>
    There is also a course coming soon related to Ethereum, where you will also
    learn something new and get rewarded.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Cake DeFi Information</h5>
            With short quizzes you can learn different Decentralized Finance and crypto topics while you have fun<br>
            <a href="https://app.cakedefi.com/learn">Cake DeFi Learn</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Revolut
</h3>
<p>
    Revolut is very good for many aspects such as banking, currency conversion,
    travelling and the super cool features of the app such as virtual cards or
    instant transfers. However, when it comes to their investment features such
    as purchasing stock or crypto, there are still some aspects that should be
    improved.
</p>
<p>
    That’s probably why in order to take off, Revolut has launched a Learn
    &amp; Earn Program related to Polkadot. Compared to other courses, the
    lessons are related to one of the most important blockchains and the
    amounts are also higher.
</p>
<p>
    In addition to the videos, you have also the option to see the glossary,
    where some important crypto and blockchain terms are explained.
</p>
<p>
    There is no referral program here and you will get those tokens for you.
    You decide if you want to sell them for fiat or exchange them the moment
    you receive them.

<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Revolut Information</h5>
            The purpose of the program is to learn about a specific cryptocurrency and familiarise with the world of crypto.
            <br>
            <a href="https://www.revolut.com/legal/crypto-learn-and-earn/">Revolut Learn & Earn Site</a>            <br>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h2>
    Technical Courses & Sites
</h2>
<p>
    Although the previous courses will reward you with direct tokens and the
    ones below will not, given the lack of technical skills that we will see in
    the future, the courses below may have a more relevant reward in upcoming
    years.
</p>
<p>
    Once we have focused described the most important courses related to
    business and blockchains, we can also get more technical and in this
    matter, there are also very good courses to add new skills.
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Uniswap
</h3>
<p>
    Uniswap, named as the name of the company that created it, is one of the most famous decentralized exchanges. Apart from the
    exchange and being an example of governance, Uniswap explains clearly very
    important topics related to DeFi.
</p>
<p>
    They offer some projects located in GitHub and the open-source interface
    for their protocol is available in GitHub.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/learn_earn/uniswap.jpg" alt="Building a great community of developers">
    <span class="Regardless of the background, you may find many resources for different topics"></span>
</p>
<p>
    On top of these resources and what you may swap or earn in the exchange,
    you can also build different apps that integrate with the protocol and get
    paid from their grant program.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Uniswap Information</h5>
            With the detailed documentation, you can learn about different topics and contribute to UniSwap in infinite ways.
            <br>
            <a href="https://uniswap.org/">Uniswap Site</a>            <br>
            <a href="https://docs.uniswap.org/">Documentation Uniswap</a>
            <br>
            <a href="https://github.com/Uniswap/interface">
                Uniswap Interface
            </a>

        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Ethernaut
</h3>
<p>
    Probably you have been hearing recently about the Ethereum Merge and the
    consequences that the fork may have not just for the Ethereum network but
    the whole crypto scene. Ethernaut is a war game played in an Ethereum
    Virtual Machine. developed by the OpenZeppelin, Ethernaut is a Web3
    application developed with Solidity, where you can also learn this
    programming language.
</p>
<p>
    The purpose of the game is both having fun and learning about Ethereum with
    different coding exercises at the same time you assimilate understand the
    Ethereum concepts with some practice.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Ethernaut Information</h5>
            Inpspired by other game             <a
                href="https://overthewire.org/"
        >
            overthewire.org
        </a>, each level of Ethernaut is a Smart Contract that you must hack to pass the level.<br>
            <a
                    href="https://ethernaut.openzeppelin.com/"
            >
                Visit Ethernaut
            </a><br>
            <a href="https://github.com/OpenZeppelin/ethernaut">
                Visit GitHub Ethernaut
            </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Crypto Zombies
</h3>
<p>
    Similar to Ethernaut, Crypto Zombies is a game where you can build a Zombie
    Factory to build your personal army composed of unique zombies.
</p>
<p>
    Once you have created the zombies, the fun is not over. It’s now where you
    can fight other learners’ armies. Furthermore, you also get unique
    collectibles like other games. As with Ethernaut, you will also learn
    blockchain specific topics such as ERC721, Web3 or zkSync, making this
    website quite complete in order to have basic knowledge about dApp
    creation.
</p>

<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Crypto Zombies Information</h5>
            With Crypto Zombies, the player can learn every aspect of how blockchains works while having fun.
        <br>
            <a href="https://cryptozombies.io/">
            Visit Crypto Zombies
        </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>
    As with many things in life, the best learning is practicing. Therefore,
    simple, or complex, why don’t start creating your own project once you know
    the basics? We are privileged to live in an era where information is
    accessible for everyone with infinite level of resources.
</p>
<p>
    As you may see from the links, the technical courses may require more time,
    so it would be better to start learning the basic concepts from the first websites.
</p>
<p>
    With new technologies and the expected growth, these technologies will
    eliminate several jobs, but there will a job shortage and companies not
    able to hire new talent because there are too few professionals with the
    required skills. One of them may be blockchain and everything that
    surrounds this industry.
</p>
<br>
<p align="center">

    <em>
        "Live as if you were to die tomorrow. Learn as if you were to live
        forever.”
    </em>
    — <strong>Mahatma Gandhi</strong>
</p>
<br>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some fun ways to learn about crypto and blockchain while you get nice rewards]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/learn_earn/learn_earn.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/learn_earn/learn_earn.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="es"><title type="html">Aprende y Gana Crypto</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/aprende-gana-crypto/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aprende y Gana Crypto" /><published>2022-08-28T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-08-28T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/aprende-gana-crypto</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/aprende-gana-crypto/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introducción
</h2>
<div class="texto-artículo">
    <p>
        Hace algunos siglos, diferentes organizaciones en Europa y Asia fueron
        acusadas de conspiraciones y polémicas. La mayoría de estas acusaciones fueron
        provocados por la información que estas sectas o grupos guardaban para sí mismos.
        Mito o realidad, lo que no se puede negar es que en la Edad Media,
        el conocimiento era algo considerado hermético y exclusivo de ciertos grupos
        y esa sabiduría estaba restringida a ellos y los miembros exclusivos de su círculo.
    </p>
</div>
<p>
    Afortunadamente, las cosas han cambiado en las últimas décadas y en esta era de
    información, tenemos más acceso a cosas que no podríamos haber imaginado unos pocos
    hace años que. Por otro lado, puede resultar chocante y paradójico que en
    esta era, somos menos cultos e informados.
</p>
<br>
<p align="centro">
    <em>
        “Si el dinero es tu esperanza de independencia nunca lo conseguirás. La única seguridad que un hombre puede
        tener en este mundo es una reserva de conocimiento, experiencia y habilidad”
    </em> -
    <strong>
        Henry Ford</strong>

</p>
<br>
<p>
    El conocimiento es una motivación suficiente para que la mayoría de nosotros aprendamos sobre nuevos temas y nos
    formemos,
    pero aparte de esto ¿qué pensarías si además de aprender temas interesantes
    y nuevas tecnologías, también puede ser recompensado por ello?
</p>
<p>
    Como se expuso en artículos anteriores, la mejor inversión que puede hacer es
    aprendizaje. Es innegable los beneficios para el ser humano que trae el aprendizaje continuo
    a largo plazo
</p>
<p>
    Aunque el aprendizaje por sí mismo ya es una experiencia gratificante y motivadora, algunas personas también pueden
    valorar beneficios adicionales. Mantenernos actualizados es imprescindible
    en el mundo competitivo en el que todos vivimos.
    No solo por ahora, sino para los próximos años.
    Por otro lado, oor recompensa, no me refiero solo a la nueva información o los beneficios que obtiene, sino
    nuevos tokens, monedas, descuentos u otro tipo de beneficios que se pueden obtener.
</p>
<p>
    Esta publicación no se trata solo de obtener monedas gratis, sino también de nuevas habilidades que
    puedes obtener y aplicar en tu mundo profesional. Profundicemos para ver
    cuáles son estas opciones.
</p>
<br>
<h2>
    Programas Learn to Earn
</h2>
<p>
    El primer grupo de este artículo está relacionado con aquellos programas en los que
    aprenda la teoría o los conceptos básicos de una cadena de bloques o token determinado. En
    las subsecciones a continuación, no solo aprende algo nuevo, sino que también
    tenga la oportunidad de ser recompensado con criptomonedas.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/learn_earn/coinbase.jpg" alt="Pioneer">
    <span class="caption text-muted">En la sección Learning Rewards puedes ver diferentes artículos, cursos y cuestionarios</span>
</p>
<p>
    Estos son algunos de los programas Learn to Earn más famosos que existen, donde
    aprendes nuevos temas interesantes y eres recompensado de diferentes maneras.
</p>
<p>
    Hay que tener en cuenta que estos cursos no tienen ningún requisito como
    “deposita 10 para ganar 20, etc.”. Aparte de aprender y leer/ver el curso y responder a las preguntas, el único otro
    requisito es que en algunos casos puede necesitar
    para verificar y pasar los controles KYC.
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Coinbase
</h3>
<p>
    Coinbase a veces es criticado por diferentes razones, como
    temas relacionados con el negocio (despido de empleados, plan de negocios) o la
    tarifas comerciales. Sin embargo, desde que comenzaron en 2018, han impulsado
    diferentes iniciativas en la comunidad crypto. Uno de los más famosos
    es el programa Learning Rewards, donde los usuarios pueden ganar diferentes tokens. los
    El proceso es bastante fácil y solo ver un video corto y responder algunas
    preguntas puede obtener algunos tokens gratis.
</p>
<p>
    No hay sorpresas aquí y puedes cambiar tan pronto como lo recibas. los
    las recompensas no son una gran cantidad, pero, últimamente, tienden a ocurrir con bastante frecuencia.
    Independientemente de las recompensas, los videos son agradables de ver y están muy bien hechos.
    Además de estos videos, también podrá ver diferentes artículos.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Coinbase Detalles</h5>
            Uno de los primeros en comenzar con esta iniciativa, Coinbase, sigue ofreciendo estos cursos de vez en
            cuando.<br>
            <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/learn/tips-and-tutorials/how-to-earn-crypto-rewards">Coinbase Learning
                Rewards</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Binance
</h3>
<p>
    Binance es, sin duda, el intercambio de criptomonedas más grande del mundo.
    En mi opinión, el exchange chino basado inicialmente puede ser bastante molesto con
    varias notificaciones diarias, pero la organización de Changpeng Zhao también promueve
    varias iniciativas agradables y valiosas para sus clientes.
</p>
<p>
    Desde 2022, han seguido lo que comenzó Coinbase y ofrecen algunos pequeños
    recompensas por ver algunos videos y responder diferentes preguntas. Ahí
    Son varios cursos, y las recompensas son bastante pequeñas. Sin embargo, es útil y beneficioso
    para entender y conocer nuevos proyectos, y además de aprender y
    obtener nuevas ideas, ser recompensado por ello.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Binance Detalles</h5>
            Binance ofrece varios cursos cortos sobre nuevas altcoins y operaciones de trading<br>
            <a href="https://academy.binance.com/en/learn-and-earn">Binance Learn and Earn</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Cake DeFi
</h3>
<p>
    Cake DeFi es un jugador bastante nuevo en el sector de las finanzas descentralizadas y ahora
    bastante conocido para muchas personas. Sin embargo, con sus soluciones actuales, es probable que escuches de ellos
    cada vez más. Cake DeFi son una empresa
    DeFi con sede en Singapur especializada en ingresos pasivos, siendo los principales pilares de
    estas plataformas las siguientes:
</p>
<p>
    1. Liquidity Mining: a diferencia de los exchanges centralizados, en un DEX, la líquidez
    es necesario para permitir intercambios entre los diferentes pares. Con
    minería de liquidez que proporciona sus activos criptográficos para que otros puedan usarlos para
    comercio.
</p>
<p>
    2. Staking: a través del protocolo Proof of Stake, bloquea sus tokens para proteger
    la red., y obtienes recompensas con tokens adicionales
</p>
<p>
    3. Lending: la última estrategia es el ingreso generado al prestar sus monedas
    a otros participantes de DeFi.
</p>
<p>
    Con los cursos disponibles, en este momento puedes ganar los siguientes
    tokens
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Tokens DFI (DeFiChain)
    </li>
    <li>
        Tokens BTC-DFI
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Ambos están asignados a la Staking y Liquidity Mining, pero después de haber hecho "unfreeze" se puedes hacer lo que
    se desee con las monedas que tienes ese obtuvieron en el curso más los que obtuvo del período de congelación.
</p>
<p>
    Próximamente también habrá un curso relacionado con Ethereum, en el que también
    aprender algo nuevo y ser recompensado.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Cake DeFi Detalles</h5>
            Con cuestionarios cortos, puede aprender diferentes temas de criptomonedas y finanzas descentralizadas
            mientras se divierte<br>
            <a href="https://app.cakedefi.com/learn">Cake DeFi Learn</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Revolut
</h3>
<p>
    Revolut es muy bueno para muchos aspectos, como banca, conversión de moneda,
    viajar y las características geniales de la aplicación, como tarjetas virtuales o
    transferencias instantáneas. Sin embargo, cuando se trata de sus características de inversión tales
    como la compra de acciones o criptomonedas, todavía hay algunos aspectos que deben ser
    mejorados.
</p>
<p>
    Probablemente por eso, para despegar, Revolut ha lanzado Learn
    &amp; Gana Programa relacionado con Polkadot. En comparación con otros cursos, las lecciones están relacionadas con
    una de las blockchains más importantes y la
    las cantidades también son más altas.
</p>
<p>
    Además de los vídeos, también tienes la opción de ver el glosario, donde se explican algunos términos importantes de
    criptografía y blockchain.
</p>
<p>
    No hay un programa de referencia aquí y obtendrá esos tokens por usted.
    Tú decides si los quieres vender por fiat o cambiarlos en el momento que los recibes.

<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Revolut Detalles</h5>
            El propósito del programa es aprender sobre una criptomoneda específica y familiarizarse con el mundo de las
            criptomonedas..
            <br>
            <a href="https://www.revolut.com/legal/crypto-learn-and-earn/">Revolut Learn & Earn Site</a> <br>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h2>
    Cursos Técnicos y Sitios
</h2>
<p>
    Aunque los cursos anteriores te recompensarán con tokens directos y
    los de abajo no lo harán, dada la falta de habilidades técnicas que veremos en el futuro, los cursos a continuación
    pueden tener una recompensa más relevante en los próximos
    años.
</p>
<p>
    Una vez que nos hemos centrado en describir los cursos más importantes relacionados con
    negocios y blockchains, también podemos ser más técnicos y en este tema, también hay muy buenos cursos para sumar
    nuevas habilidades.
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Uniswap
</h3>
<p>
    Uniswap, llamado así por el nombre de la empresa que lo creó, es uno de los exchanges descentralizados más famosos.
    Aparte del exchange y siendo un ejemplo de gobernanza, Uniswap explica claramente muy
    temas importantes relacionados con DeFi.
</p>
<p>
    Ofrecen algunos proyectos ubicados en GitHub y la interfaz de código abierto para su protocolo está por ejemplo
    disponible en GitHub.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/learn_earn/uniswap.jpg" alt="Building a great community of developers">
    <span class="Regardless of the background, you may find many resources for different topics"></span>
</p>
<p>
    Además de estos recursos y lo que puede intercambiar o ganar en el exchange,
    también puede crear diferentes aplicaciones que se integran con el protocolo y obtener
    pagados de su programa de "grants".
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Uniswap Detalles</h5>
            Con la documentación detallada, se puede aprender sobre diferentes temas y contribuir a UniSwap de infinitas
            maneras.
            <br>
            <a href="https://uniswap.org/">Uniswap Sitio</a> <br>
            <a href="https://docs.uniswap.org/">Documentación Uniswap</a>
            <br>
            <a href="https://github.com/Uniswap/interface">
                Uniswap Interfaz
            </a>

        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Ethernaut
</h3>
<p>
    Probablemente haya escuchado recientemente sobre la fusión de Ethereum y las
    consecuencias que la bifurcación puede tener no solo para la red Ethereum sino
    toda la escena criptográfica. Ethernaut es un juego de guerra que se juega en un Ethereum
    Máquina virtual y desarrollado por OpenZeppelin, Ethernaut es una
    aplicación Web3 desarrollada con Solidity, donde también puedes aprender este
    lenguaje de programación de una manera amena e interactiva.
</p>
<p>
    El propósito del juego es divertirse y aprender sobre Ethereum con
    diferentes ejercicios de codificación al mismo tiempo que asimilas entender los
    conceptos de Ethereum con algo de práctica.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Ethernaut Detalles</h5>
            Inspirado en otro juego <a
                href="https://overthewire.org/"
        >
            overthewire.org
        </a>, cada nivel de Ethernaut es un smart contract que debes hackear para pasar el nivel.<br>
            <a
                    href="https://ethernaut.openzeppelin.com/"
            >
                Visita Ethernaut
            </a><br>
            <a href="https://github.com/OpenZeppelin/ethernaut">
                Visita GitHub Ethernaut
            </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Crypto Zombies
</h3>
<p>
    Similar a Ethernaut, Crypto Zombies es un juego en el que puedes construir una fábrica de Zombies
    para construir tu ejército personal compuesto por soldados únicos.
</p>
<p>
    Una vez que haya creado los zombies, la diversión no ha terminado. Ahora es donde
    puedes luchar contra los ejércitos de otros estudiantes. Además, también obtienes
    coleccionables como otros juegos. Al igual que con Ethernaut, también puedes aprender
    temas específicos de blockchain como ERC721, Web3 o zkSync, lo que hace que esto
    sitio web bastante completo para tener conocimientos básicos sobre dApp
    creación.
</p>

<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Crypto Zombies Detalles</h5>
            Con Crypto Zombies, el jugador puede aprender todos los aspectos de cómo funcionan las cadenas de bloques
            mientras se divierte.
            <br>
            <a href="https://cryptozombies.io/">
                Visita Crypto Zombies
            </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>Conclusión</h3>
<p>
    Como ocurre con muchas cosas en la vida, el mejor aprendizaje es la práctica. Por lo tanto,
    simple o complejo, ¿por qué no comienza a crear su propio proyecto una vez que sepa
    los conceptos básicos? Tenemos el privilegio de vivir en una era donde la información es
    accesible para todos con un nivel infinito de recursos.
</p>
<p>
    Como se puede ver en los enlaces, los cursos técnicos pueden requerir más tiempo,
    por lo que sería mejor comenzar a aprender los conceptos básicos de los primeros sitios web.
</p>
<p>
    Con las nuevas tecnologías y el crecimiento esperado, estas tecnologías
    eliminar varios puestos de trabajo, pero habrá escasez de empleo y las empresas no
    capaz de contratar nuevos talentos porque hay muy pocos profesionales con la
    habilidades requeridas. Uno de ellos puede ser blockchain y todo lo que
    rodea esta industria.
</p>
<br>
<p align="center">

    <em>
        “Vive como si fueras a morir mañana. Aprende como si fueras a vivir para siempre.”
    </em>
    — <strong>Mahatma Gandhi</strong>
</p>
<br>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aprende sobre crypto y sea recompensado por tu conocimiento]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/learn_earn/learn_earn.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/learn_earn/learn_earn.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="enn"><title type="html">Benefits of Traveling and How To Get Cheap Flights</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/18/benefits_traveling_how_to_get_cheap_flights/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Benefits of Traveling and How To Get Cheap Flights" /><published>2022-08-18T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-08-18T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/08/18/benefits_traveling_how_to_get_cheap_flights</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/18/benefits_traveling_how_to_get_cheap_flights/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        We are in this time of the season where airports are packed and there is a
        peak of flights when everybody is taking one or more flights to go to the
        planned destination some weeks before. Despite the petrol price, different
        strikes, and other inconveniences, after two years of the COVID pandemic,
        the flight levels are back to 2019 levels and the predictions for the next
        years are quite optimistic.
    </p>
</div>

<p>
    This can be explained by the benefits that flying brings and the
    limitations and restrictions. we had in the last 2 years. The freedom that
    was taken from us made us value more the possibility of having now the
    possibility to choose where to go.
</p>
<p>
    Related to this, the first thing we know is that experiences are better
    than possessions. With the millennials, we have been an increasing
    prioritization of these experiences over possessions such as houses or
    cars.
</p>
<p>
    The trip of our dreams is something that we look forward to and our goals
    is how to fly more and how to find good deals when looking for these trips.
    It’s something we include in the wishes for the next year.
</p>
<p>
    Although some useless governments are now with the idea of reducing the
    number of flights or other nonsense regulations, who cares about what they
    say? Although topics such as pollution or energy management are constant
    problems, maybe they should be the first ones to apply these rules and
    avoid their usual useless trips.
</p>
<p>
    Therefore, why not benefit from more and affordable trips during the year?
    In order to achieve this, there are some steps that we need to consider.
</p>
<p>
    They are not complex at all, but these are some tricks in order to help you
    with your next trip.
</p>
<h2>
    Planning
</h2>
<p>
    The first phase is the initial planning phase. It does not require a big
    effort but leaving everything unplanned or for the last minute will
    generate unnecessary stress that may ruin our trip. If planned accordingly,
    this will solve different situations and will get you a better price,
    flight and stay. In this case, one suggestion would be to start looking for
    flights some months before the trip. This will ensure that you can analyze
    the different options and mitigate possible risks.
</p>
<p>
    One of the most heard questions is whether is better to spend 1 month in a
    location or have 3 trips in different locations.
</p>
<p>
    Although I prefer in general quality over quality, when it comes to trips
    it is just the opposite. I’m in favor of having more than one. This can be
    achieved by carefully selecting affordable options. Picking 3 flights of
    300 instead of 1 of 1,000 will in my opinion a better choice.
</p>
<p>
    However, this opinion is not based on the price aspect, but also on
    diversification. For example, if you go to one destination for 1 month and
    for whatever reason you don’t like it, the weather is very bad, etc. the
    single trip for the year is ruined. With more options, you diversify more
    and if you travel 3 or 4 times per year, it’s not likely that all of them
    will be a bad choice.
</p>
<h2>
    Adapt to the options
</h2>
<p>
    If you are looking for an exact destination and you suddenly come with a
    super cheap price, It may look the best thing in the world. However, this
    will not be always the case.
</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/cheap_flights/google_flights.jpg" alt="Essential application">
    <span class="caption text-muted">As we can see in the list of tools, having additional technological support is a must for our search</span>
</p>
<p>
    Despite this may be what we are aiming to achieve, ff you try to hit in the
    middle of the bullseye, you may be a lifetime waiting for it. Flexibility
    is the currency that you may use to get more trips with better prices.
</p>
<p>
    It’s just the opposite. The piece of advice here should be starting to look
    for cheap affordable locations. From that list, you will probably find
    several destinations that may be attractive to you.
</p>
<p>
    You may start by selecting different price ranges within your budget. Out
    of all destinations, you may select the ones with the lowest prices and
    from there you can start selecting which destinations may fit more. Even if
    some of them may not be very attractive, this can be a good opportunity to
    discover the next gem.
</p>
<p>
    It’s often where we see that people go to the same destinations: Paris,
    Madrid, London, etc. These places are normally overcrowded, and it’s likely
    that you have already visited. Why not looking something less mainstream?
</p>
<p>
    As said before, being flexible is the attribute that will open more doors
    and get you better deals. First: direct flights may be more
    expensive. In this case, there are different options such as different
    flights, companies, dates or even alternative transport methods.
</p>
<p>
    When it comes to short flights, one alternative could be going by
    car/train/bus to a close airport. You may have the option of the parking,
    staying at some friend’s place or even visiting another city before the
    flight.
</p>
<p>
    In some countries, the train will be quite cheap if booked in advance and,
    if you are looking for an international flight, another possibility would
    be to use 2 companies and go first to the connection point. There, you can
    visit the city (1 day trip). Normally, these cities have many inhabitants,
    and you may know someone who you can visit or even he may let you stay for
    the night.
</p>
<p>
    The trick in these cases is to have a good margin between the first and
    second flight. If for some reason, there is no time left to leave the
    airport for a short visit to the city, another advice is to get some
    accessories that will make your trip much easier:
</p>
<p>
    Battery charger, eBook or book, and headphones. Another trick is that
    without or bad connection to use the laptop to work on work or personal
    project. If you don’t have Internet connection, you will not get disturbed
    by constants notifications.
</p>
<p>
    In the last 21 days, prices will skyrocket. You may have seen too many The
    Simpsons episodes (e.g., when they go to Japan), but it is unlikely that
    you will get a last-minute deal. These prices are high because are more
    focused on business travelers who don’t have any other alternative and they
    (the company) will pay the ticket fare.
</p>
<h2>
    Some tools
</h2>
<p>
    When it comes to additional help, there are hundreds of tools on the
    Internet that can be used to keep track the different offers. For example:
    Kayak, Skyscanner, Google Trips or your own tools.
</p>
<p>
    For example, in my case using Python and MongoDB I have created a tool that
    checks flights with multiple destination and dates combinations and will
    store the best option (duration and price) for each combination on each
    day. The cheapest option on each day is stored and the moment the price
    goes down, it sends you an alert. Playing with alerts on the service you
    may use is off the essence.
</p>
<p>
    Since we were discussing the flexibility, I have found that Google Flights
    allows including many origin and destination airports on the same search.
    With this useful feature, you can get the best deals with one single
    search. You can also add notifications. The disadvantage with Google
    Flights is that some flights may not appear.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/cheap_flights/mongodb.jpg" alt="Basic but working">
    <span class="caption text-muted">This is the basic application that just collects the flight information such as the price, duration, destination and origin. Once there is a decrease in the price, it sends an email to inform about the change.</span>
</p>
<p>
    Another trick is to book on those airline companies that offer free
    cancellation. This way you make sure that the highest price you will pay in
    your search will be the one you already had and everything you get below
    that is your gain.
</p>
<h2>
    Other tricks
</h2>
<p>
    Saving in flights means that your budget for doing other trips,
    restaurants. Instead of going to a 4-start restaurant, you may end up in a
    5-star hotel and go to Michelin-starred restaurants. Therefore, you should
    invest in planning and flexibility because this way you can spend the money
    in more important things.
</p>
<p>
    Although it may sound strange to you with the recent surge in travel
    tickets due to inflation, strikes and gas prices, prices are each year
    lower. This is due to big competition in the airline industry. It’s a
    regulated sector with several years of history and since World War II
    prices have been decreasing – after adjusting the price considering
    inflations –
</p>
<p>
    Then, how do airlines make money? While flying was a premium some years
    ago, luckily it has been accessible to more and more people. The revenue
    sources have changed too. As opposed to some decades ago, we that revenues
    do not come mainly from the ticket, but from other extras such as baggage
    fees, seat fees, other products, bundles, business trips, etc.
</p>
<p>
    Another question you may have seen is on which day to book the flight. How
    does this algorithm work?
</p>
<p>
    There is no specific day or hour when you may find the best price.
    Although you may have heard different opinions based on different sources,
    there is no specific time when you will get the best price.
</p>
<p>
    However, one thing is to consider. Mondays and Fridays are normally the
    most expensive days because these are the days when business trips take
    place. People will get on the plane to a specific destination and come back
    on Friday. For short trips, this is also the best time in order to spend
    the whole weekend abroad.
</p>
<p>
    Excluding these days, the best days are Tuesday, Wednesday, and Saturday.
    Again, this does not mean that they will be always the cheapest flights.
</p>
<p>
    When it comes to months, August is traditionally the most expensive month
    (some people don’t have any choice for holidays) and Christmas. Therefore,
    selecting the correct dates may also be a relevant factor.
</p>
<p>
    TABLE OF DAYS
</p>
<table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0">
    <tbody>
    <tr>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                <strong>Factor</strong>
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                <strong>Probability of Expensive Flights</strong>
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                <strong>Probability of Affordable Flights</strong>
            </p>
        </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Day of the week
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Monday, Friday
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Tuesday, Wednesday, Saturday
            </p>
        </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Duration
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Less than 7 days
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                More than 7 days
            </p>
        </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Season
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Summer, Christmas, Easter
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Other than the ones in the left
            </p>
        </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Booking
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                21 days or less before departure
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Months before departure
            </p>
        </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                One-way flights
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Yes
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                No
            </p>
        </td>
    </tr>
    </tbody>
</table>
<p>
    The rules above are quite general and there is no written rule. It may be
    that one day a flight ticket from Net York to Amsterdam is 600 and the day
    after is 300 EUR. For this reason, it’s important to benefit from
    technology and your favorite tool and get noticed as soon as this change
    occurs.
</p>
<h2>
    Key takeaways
</h2>
<h3>
    Plan and plan
</h3>
<p>
    Don’t leave things for the last minute. Have a good planning will have
    benefits on both the stress and the price you will end paying for the
    tickets or any other service you may need.
</p>
<p>
    Start looking in advance is also key. Depending on the type of flight, you
    should start looking between 2 and 8 months in advance.
</p>
<p>
    Booking at the earliest date does not always mean the cheapest price but
    waiting for the last minute will always mean a high price.
</p>
<h3>
    Flexibility
</h3>
<p>
    If you want to travel as much as possible during the year, be flexible.
    Don’t start looking for one single destination. Open your mind and look for
    affordable places you may not even know they exist. Learn about them. As
    mentioned above, it’s key to plan accordingly. Once you have investigated
    if you would like to go to one of the placed that popped up, see if this is
    the place where you would like to stay. In many cases, because of the low
    expectations, these can be a total surprise, and you may want to come the
    year after again.
</p>
<h3>
    Tools
</h3>
<p>
    Use technology with some many tools available, we can really benefit of
    instant notifications when we find a good deal. In some cases, it may be
    difficult to configure some alerts, but it's something we will learn the more we use this feature.
</p>
<h3>
    Practice
</h3>
<p>
    What’s I the right price? How should I risk? When should I pull the
    trigger? These questions require practice and knowing the different routes
    or companies. Even if I have no plans to fly, what I normally do is also
    setting up some alerts where I can see the different prices and the price
    evolution. Remember that time is against you, so the moment you find a good
    deal after having performed the different steps, just go for it.
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Lifestyle" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Benefits of Traveling and How To Get Cheap Flights]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/cheap_flights/cheap_flights.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/cheap_flights/cheap_flights.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Benefits of Traveling and How To Get Cheap Flights</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/benefits-traveling-how-to-get-cheap-flights/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Benefits of Traveling and How To Get Cheap Flights" /><published>2022-08-18T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-08-18T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/benefits-traveling-how-to-get-cheap-flights</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/benefits-traveling-how-to-get-cheap-flights/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        We are in this time of the season where airports are packed and there is a
        peak of flights when everybody is taking one or more flights to go to the
        planned destination some weeks before. Despite the petrol price, different
        strikes, and other inconveniences, after two years of the COVID pandemic,
        the flight levels are back to 2019 levels and the predictions for the next
        years are quite optimistic.
    </p>
</div>

<p>
    This can be explained by the benefits that flying brings and the
    limitations and restrictions. we had in the last 2 years. The freedom that
    was taken from us made us value more the possibility of having now the
    possibility to choose where to go.
</p>
<p>
    Related to this, the first thing we know is that experiences are better
    than possessions. With the millennials, we have been an increasing
    prioritization of these experiences over possessions such as houses or
    cars.
</p>
<p>
    The trip of our dreams is something that we look forward to and our goals
    is how to fly more and how to find good deals when looking for these trips.
    It’s something we include in the wishes for the next year.
</p>
<p>
    Although some useless governments are now with the idea of reducing the
    number of flights or other nonsense regulations, who cares about what they
    say? Although topics such as pollution or energy management are constant
    problems, maybe they should be the first ones to apply these rules and
    avoid their usual useless trips.
</p>
<p>
    Therefore, why not benefit from more and affordable trips during the year?
    In order to achieve this, there are some steps that we need to consider.
</p>
<p>
    They are not complex at all, but these are some tricks in order to help you
    with your next trip.
</p>
<h2>
    Planning
</h2>
<p>
    The first phase is the initial planning phase. It does not require a big
    effort but leaving everything unplanned or for the last minute will
    generate unnecessary stress that may ruin our trip. If planned accordingly,
    this will solve different situations and will get you a better price,
    flight and stay. In this case, one suggestion would be to start looking for
    flights some months before the trip. This will ensure that you can analyze
    the different options and mitigate possible risks.
</p>
<p>
    One of the most heard questions is whether is better to spend 1 month in a
    location or have 3 trips in different locations.
</p>
<p>
    Although I prefer in general quality over quality, when it comes to trips
    it is just the opposite. I’m in favor of having more than one. This can be
    achieved by carefully selecting affordable options. Picking 3 flights of
    300 instead of 1 of 1,000 will in my opinion a better choice.
</p>
<p>
    However, this opinion is not based on the price aspect, but also on
    diversification. For example, if you go to one destination for 1 month and
    for whatever reason you don’t like it, the weather is very bad, etc. the
    single trip for the year is ruined. With more options, you diversify more
    and if you travel 3 or 4 times per year, it’s not likely that all of them
    will be a bad choice.
</p>
<h2>
    Adapt to the options
</h2>
<p>
    If you are looking for an exact destination and you suddenly come with a
    super cheap price, It may look the best thing in the world. However, this
    will not be always the case.
</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/cheap_flights/google_flights.jpg" alt="Essential application">
    <span class="caption text-muted">As we can see in the list of tools, having additional technological support is a must for our search</span>
</p>
<p>
    Despite this may be what we are aiming to achieve, ff you try to hit in the
    middle of the bullseye, you may be a lifetime waiting for it. Flexibility
    is the currency that you may use to get more trips with better prices.
</p>
<p>
    It’s just the opposite. The piece of advice here should be starting to look
    for cheap affordable locations. From that list, you will probably find
    several destinations that may be attractive to you.
</p>
<p>
    You may start by selecting different price ranges within your budget. Out
    of all destinations, you may select the ones with the lowest prices and
    from there you can start selecting which destinations may fit more. Even if
    some of them may not be very attractive, this can be a good opportunity to
    discover the next gem.
</p>
<p>
    It’s often where we see that people go to the same destinations: Paris,
    Madrid, London, etc. These places are normally overcrowded, and it’s likely
    that you have already visited. Why not looking something less mainstream?
</p>
<p>
    As said before, being flexible is the attribute that will open more doors
    and get you better deals. First: direct flights may be more
    expensive. In this case, there are different options such as different
    flights, companies, dates or even alternative transport methods.
</p>
<p>
    When it comes to short flights, one alternative could be going by
    car/train/bus to a close airport. You may have the option of the parking,
    staying at some friend’s place or even visiting another city before the
    flight.
</p>
<p>
    In some countries, the train will be quite cheap if booked in advance and,
    if you are looking for an international flight, another possibility would
    be to use 2 companies and go first to the connection point. There, you can
    visit the city (1 day trip). Normally, these cities have many inhabitants,
    and you may know someone who you can visit or even he may let you stay for
    the night.
</p>
<p>
    The trick in these cases is to have a good margin between the first and
    second flight. If for some reason, there is no time left to leave the
    airport for a short visit to the city, another advice is to get some
    accessories that will make your trip much easier:
</p>
<p>
    Battery charger, eBook or book, and headphones. Another trick is that
    without or bad connection to use the laptop to work on work or personal
    project. If you don’t have Internet connection, you will not get disturbed
    by constants notifications.
</p>
<p>
    In the last 21 days, prices will skyrocket. You may have seen too many The
    Simpsons episodes (e.g., when they go to Japan), but it is unlikely that
    you will get a last-minute deal. These prices are high because are more
    focused on business travelers who don’t have any other alternative and they
    (the company) will pay the ticket fare.
</p>
<h2>
    Some tools
</h2>
<p>
    When it comes to additional help, there are hundreds of tools on the
    Internet that can be used to keep track the different offers. For example:
    Kayak, Skyscanner, Google Trips or your own tools.
</p>
<p>
    For example, in my case using Python and MongoDB I have created a tool that
    checks flights with multiple destination and dates combinations and will
    store the best option (duration and price) for each combination on each
    day. The cheapest option on each day is stored and the moment the price
    goes down, it sends you an alert. Playing with alerts on the service you
    may use is off the essence.
</p>
<p>
    Since we were discussing the flexibility, I have found that Google Flights
    allows including many origin and destination airports on the same search.
    With this useful feature, you can get the best deals with one single
    search. You can also add notifications. The disadvantage with Google
    Flights is that some flights may not appear.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/cheap_flights/mongodb.jpg" alt="Basic but working">
    <span class="caption text-muted">This is the basic application that just collects the flight information such as the price, duration, destination and origin. Once there is a decrease in the price, it sends an email to inform about the change.</span>
</p>
<p>
    Another trick is to book on those airline companies that offer free
    cancellation. This way you make sure that the highest price you will pay in
    your search will be the one you already had and everything you get below
    that is your gain.
</p>
<h2>
    Other tricks
</h2>
<p>
    Saving in flights means that your budget for doing other trips,
    restaurants. Instead of going to a 4-start restaurant, you may end up in a
    5-star hotel and go to Michelin-starred restaurants. Therefore, you should
    invest in planning and flexibility because this way you can spend the money
    in more important things.
</p>
<p>
    Although it may sound strange to you with the recent surge in travel
    tickets due to inflation, strikes and gas prices, prices are each year
    lower. This is due to big competition in the airline industry. It’s a
    regulated sector with several years of history and since World War II
    prices have been decreasing – after adjusting the price considering
    inflations –
</p>
<p>
    Then, how do airlines make money? While flying was a premium some years
    ago, luckily it has been accessible to more and more people. The revenue
    sources have changed too. As opposed to some decades ago, we that revenues
    do not come mainly from the ticket, but from other extras such as baggage
    fees, seat fees, other products, bundles, business trips, etc.
</p>
<p>
    Another question you may have seen is on which day to book the flight. How
    does this algorithm work?
</p>
<p>
    There is no specific day or hour when you may find the best price.
    Although you may have heard different opinions based on different sources,
    there is no specific time when you will get the best price.
</p>
<p>
    However, one thing is to consider. Mondays and Fridays are normally the
    most expensive days because these are the days when business trips take
    place. People will get on the plane to a specific destination and come back
    on Friday. For short trips, this is also the best time in order to spend
    the whole weekend abroad.
</p>
<p>
    Excluding these days, the best days are Tuesday, Wednesday, and Saturday.
    Again, this does not mean that they will be always the cheapest flights.
</p>
<p>
    When it comes to months, August is traditionally the most expensive month
    (some people don’t have any choice for holidays) and Christmas. Therefore,
    selecting the correct dates may also be a relevant factor.
</p>
<p>
    TABLE OF DAYS
</p>
<table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0">
    <tbody>
    <tr>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                <strong>Factor</strong>
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                <strong>Probability of Expensive Flights</strong>
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                <strong>Probability of Affordable Flights</strong>
            </p>
        </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Day of the week
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Monday, Friday
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Tuesday, Wednesday, Saturday
            </p>
        </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Duration
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Less than 7 days
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                More than 7 days
            </p>
        </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Season
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Summer, Christmas, Easter
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Other than the ones in the left
            </p>
        </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Booking
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                21 days or less before departure
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Months before departure
            </p>
        </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                One-way flights
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                Yes
            </p>
        </td>
        <td width="200" valign="top">
            <p>
                No
            </p>
        </td>
    </tr>
    </tbody>
</table>
<p>
    The rules above are quite general and there is no written rule. It may be
    that one day a flight ticket from Net York to Amsterdam is 600 and the day
    after is 300 EUR. For this reason, it’s important to benefit from
    technology and your favorite tool and get noticed as soon as this change
    occurs.
</p>
<h2>
    Key takeaways
</h2>
<h3>
    Plan and plan
</h3>
<p>
    Don’t leave things for the last minute. Have a good planning will have
    benefits on both the stress and the price you will end paying for the
    tickets or any other service you may need.
</p>
<p>
    Start looking in advance is also key. Depending on the type of flight, you
    should start looking between 2 and 8 months in advance.
</p>
<p>
    Booking at the earliest date does not always mean the cheapest price but
    waiting for the last minute will always mean a high price.
</p>
<h3>
    Flexibility
</h3>
<p>
    If you want to travel as much as possible during the year, be flexible.
    Don’t start looking for one single destination. Open your mind and look for
    affordable places you may not even know they exist. Learn about them. As
    mentioned above, it’s key to plan accordingly. Once you have investigated
    if you would like to go to one of the placed that popped up, see if this is
    the place where you would like to stay. In many cases, because of the low
    expectations, these can be a total surprise, and you may want to come the
    year after again.
</p>
<h3>
    Tools
</h3>
<p>
    Use technology with some many tools available, we can really benefit of
    instant notifications when we find a good deal. In some cases, it may be
    difficult to configure some alerts, but it's something we will learn the more we use this feature.
</p>
<h3>
    Practice
</h3>
<p>
    What’s I the right price? How should I risk? When should I pull the
    trigger? These questions require practice and knowing the different routes
    or companies. Even if I have no plans to fly, what I normally do is also
    setting up some alerts where I can see the different prices and the price
    evolution. Remember that time is against you, so the moment you find a good
    deal after having performed the different steps, just go for it.
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Lifestyle" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The benefits of flying and travelling can be immense. Therefore, why not doing more and see some hacks to make this done?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/cheap_flights/cheap_flights.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/cheap_flights/cheap_flights.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>