<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-11-06T02:14:22+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Life of a Modern Man</title><subtitle>Advising in Lifestyle and Finance</subtitle><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">How Nutrition Is Impacting Your Life</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/how-nutrition-is-impacting-your-life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Nutrition Is Impacting Your Life" /><published>2022-11-04T13:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2022-11-04T13:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/how-nutrition-is-impacting-your-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/how-nutrition-is-impacting-your-life/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
Eating is one of the pleasures of life and apart from that a way of being able to meet with family and friends. However, although we are not conscious of it, eating well or bad plays an important role in our life (mood, work, sport, etc.). Although it was probably today when we have more access to information, it is also the era where producers try to include in the market products with ingredients that can be harmful for us. It’s quite also understandable that more and more people have obesity problems. Although governments are trying to put a remedy to this trend or even “modern disease”, instead of rules, what we should do is educate people and let them know about all consequences.
</div>

<p>I, as probably you, love eating and probably you are also trying to taste new flavors or discover new restaurants.
However, I’m also telling you nothing new when I say that this exercise in excess can have very bad consequences, that
will slowly hurt your body.</p>

<p>It’s strange, but true, we are what we eat. Whoever said this sentence for the first time, he knew what he was doing.</p>

<p>It’s strange, but true, we are what we eat. Whoever said this sentence for the first time, he knew what he was doing.</p>

<h2 id="problems">Problems</h2>

<p>Although it may seem that eating just negative consequences in few aspects (our physical body and the shape), it
probably has even worse consequences in other aspects of our life, which are of course more important than keeping a
flat belly. You will see for example people who eat poor quality food, they remain thin, but you will see other aspects
that are indicative of their diet. These symptoms are more severe than the look of their silhouette.</p>

<h3 id="fatigue">Fatigue</h3>

<p>When you eat heavy food, with a lot of calories, our organs need to switch to “hard-work” mode, and they consume more
energy in order to be able to digest them. Simply mathematics, our organs need to allocate more energy to this task, and
there will be less energy in order to do the remaining tasks, leading to feeling tired and without desired to do
anything.</p>

<p>Some examples of unhealthy nutrients having a considerable impact in this point are those containing too much sugar,
salt, or flour. They can be an instant boost of energy, but this effect is lost some minutes later, leading to the
opposite results.</p>

<h3 id="mood">Mood</h3>

<p>We have more and more advances and breakthroughs in different aspects, making our life easier. The problem is that
despite these improvements, why with better conditions there are more and more burnouts, depressions, and even people
committing suicide? Of course, there are other reasons, but one of the factors is related to the food. One of the
reasons, is that eating products high in trans-fat, they have a direct impact into our stress hormones. This causes us
to be more aggressive, irritable, and making our mood and motivation drop to the bottom.</p>

<h3 id="focus">Focus</h3>

<p>Related to our intellectual activity, try to study, or work, and you will also see that having a bad diet will cause
problems with your lucidity and agility. You can see this for example when focusing on a complex task or memorizing
topics, or even a single number.</p>

<h3 id="long-term-diseases">Long-term diseases</h3>
<p>It is not surprise that countries with healthy diets have a higher expected life. Furthermore, there are several studies
that link the effects of eating unhealthy food to different diseases. This of course is not applicable to food, but
other products we drink or inhale. The solution is easy: If you want to live longer, start taking care of what your body
is using as fuel.</p>

<h3 id="recovery">Recovery</h3>

<p>Nutrition has an important role in both, mental and physical. Try to practice sport with a good diet and a bad diet and
you will note the difference and how much it some activities cost or how you are tired after the workout.</p>

<p>As we have seen for concentration, we need to take care of what we provide to our brain, so it is possible to</p>

<h2 id="how-to-fix-this">How to fix this</h2>

<p>Having seen what is causing problems to our health, there should be something we can do about it. These are some tricks
in order to help us with a perfect nutrition aimed to achieve the best performance.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/nutrition/fruit.jpg" alt="Fruits and Vegetables" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Eating seasons vegetables and fruits is an excellent way to discover new and tasty combinations
</span>
</p>

<h3 id="plan">Plan</h3>

<p>When it comes to food, as in many other aspects in life, you cannot improvise. Have an empty fridge and go to the last
minute to the supermarket, and I can assure you that you will probably end up with post processed food and low-quality
nutrients. This is definitely not the way. Another benefit is that with this technique you can avoid unnecessary
products in the supermarket and save a considerable amount of money.</p>

<h3 id="be-constant">Be constant</h3>

<p>This one may be also quite evident, but it is usual that a lot of people start with their diet very motivated. In this
case being constant is of course much more important than the intensity. Define realistic and feasible goals. Otherwise,
in 1 week you will get back where you started.</p>

<h3 id="variety">Variety</h3>
<p>Changing what you eat, while innovating makes sure that you are not bored of the monotony. With this in mind, you can
create multiple combinations and have fun avoiding already prepared post processed foods.</p>

<p>You may be thinking that having to think about what you need to each every day may sound a bit annoying at first sight.
However, this will give you a better organization of what to prepare. Furthermore, one of the tricks is also to take
benefit of the seasonal products and enjoy the flavor of these products.</p>

<h3 id="time-to-break-the-rules-sometimes">Time to break the rules (sometimes)</h3>

<p>Although this seems the opposite of what’s included above, you could have your cheat day, e.g., on the weekend. However,
even if in the beginning you will be probably yearning for this day to arrive, you may realize about the following. The
day after you go for this special day, you will feel heavier and not as healthy as the previous days. Our body is
intelligent enough to warn us about something they did not like and it’s causing our body to suffer.</p>

<p>With time, you will see that this cheat day is probably causing more problems to your body, and you will not ask for it
anymore. And your mind and body will thank you for this.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why you should start taking care of what you eat and why the food may be slowly killing you]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/nutrition/fr.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/nutrition/fr.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="es"><title type="html">Como La Nutrición Está Impactando Tu Vida</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/como-la-nutricion-esta-impactando-tu-vida/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Como La Nutrición Está Impactando Tu Vida" /><published>2022-11-04T13:01:13+01:00</published><updated>2022-11-04T13:01:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/como-la-nutricion-esta-impactando-tu-vida</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/como-la-nutricion-esta-impactando-tu-vida/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introducción">Introducción</h2>

<div class="texto-artículo">
Comer es uno de los placeres de la vida y además una forma de poder reunirse con familiares y amigos. Sin embargo, aunque no seamos conscientes de ello, comer bien o mal juega un papel importante en nuestra vida (anímico, laboral, deportivo, etc.). Aunque probablemente sea hoy cuando tengamos más acceso a la información, también es la época en la que los productores intentan incluir en el mercado productos con ingredientes que pueden ser perjudiciales para nosotros. También es comprensible que cada vez más personas tengan problemas de obesidad. Aunque los gobiernos están tratando de poner remedio a esta tendencia o incluso “enfermedad moderna”, en lugar de reglas, lo que debemos hacer es educar a la gente y hacerle saber sobre todas las consecuencias.
</div>

<p>A mí, como probablemente a ti, me encanta comer y probablemente también estés intentando probar nuevos sabores o
descubrir nuevos restaurantes.
Sin embargo, tampoco te digo nada nuevo cuando digo que este ejercicio en exceso puede tener muy malas consecuencias,
que
poco a poco lastimará tu cuerpo.</p>

<p>Es extraño, pero cierto, somos lo que comemos. Quien dijo esta frase por primera vez, sabía lo que estaba haciendo.</p>

<p>Es extraño, pero cierto, somos lo que comemos. Quien dijo esta frase por primera vez, sabía lo que estaba haciendo.</p>

<h2 id="problemas">Problemas</h2>

<p>Aunque pueda parecer que comer solo tiene consecuencias negativas en algunos aspectos (nuestro cuerpo físico y la forma)
, es
probablemente tenga consecuencias aún peores en otros aspectos de nuestra vida, que por supuesto son más importantes que
mantener un
vientre plano. Verás por ejemplo personas que comen alimentos de mala calidad, se mantienen delgados, pero verás otros
aspectos
que son indicativos de su dieta. Estos síntomas son más severos que el aspecto de su silueta.</p>

<h3 id="fatiga">Fatiga</h3>

<p>Cuando come alimentos pesados, con muchas calorías, nuestros órganos necesitan cambiar al modo de “trabajo duro” y
consumen más
energía para poder digerirlos. Simplemente matemáticas, nuestros órganos necesitan destinar más energía a esta tarea, y
habrá menos energía para hacer las tareas restantes, lo que lleva a sentirse cansado y sin ganas de hacer
cualquier cosa.</p>

<p>Algunos ejemplos de nutrientes no saludables que tienen un impacto considerable en este punto son aquellos que contienen
demasiada azúcar,
sal, o harina. Pueden ser un impulso instantáneo de energía, pero este efecto se pierde unos minutos más tarde, lo que
lleva a la
resultados opuestos.</p>

<h3 id="estado-animico">Estado animico</h3>

<p>Cada vez tenemos más avances y avances en diferentes aspectos, haciéndonos la vida más fácil. El problema es ese
a pesar de estas mejoras, por qué con mejores condiciones hay cada vez más burnouts, depresiones e incluso personas
suicidarse? Por supuesto, hay otras razones, pero uno de los factores está relacionado con la comida. Uno de los
razones, es que comer productos ricos en grasas trans, tienen un impacto directo en nuestras hormonas del estrés. esto
nos provoca
ser más agresivos, irritables y hacer que nuestro estado de ánimo y motivación se desplomen.</p>

<h3 id="enfoque">Enfoque</h3>

<p>Relacionado con nuestra actividad intelectual, intenta estudiar, o trabajar, y también verás que tener una mala
alimentación provocará
problemas con tu lucidez y agilidad. Puedes ver esto, por ejemplo, cuando te concentras en una tarea compleja o
memorizas
temas, o incluso un solo número.</p>

<h3 id="enfermedades-a-largo-plazo">Enfermedades a largo plazo</h3>

<p>No es de extrañar que los países con dietas saludables tengan una mayor esperanza de vida. Además, hay varios estudios
que relacionan los efectos de comer alimentos poco saludables con diferentes enfermedades. Por supuesto, esto no es
aplicable a los alimentos, pero
otros productos que bebemos o inhalamos. La solución es fácil: si quieres vivir más tiempo, empieza a cuidar lo que es
tu cuerpo
está utilizando como combustible.</p>

<h3 id="recuperación">Recuperación</h3>

<p>La nutrición tiene un papel importante tanto en la salud mental como en la física. Intenta practicar deporte con una
buena alimentación y una mala alimentación y
notarás la diferencia y cuánto cuestan algunas actividades o cuánto te cansas después del entrenamiento.</p>

<p>Como hemos visto para la concentración, tenemos que cuidar lo que le damos a nuestro cerebro, por lo que es posible</p>

<h2 id="cómo-arreglar-esto">Cómo arreglar esto</h2>

<p>Habiendo visto lo que está causando problemas a nuestra salud, debería haber algo que podamos hacer al respecto. Estos
son algunos trucos
para ayudarnos con una perfecta nutrición encaminada a conseguir el mejor rendimiento.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/nutrition/fruit.jpg" alt="Frutas y Verduras" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Comer verduras y frutas de temporada es una excelente manera de descubrir nuevas y sabrosas combinaciones
</span>
</p>

<h3 id="plan">Plan</h3>

<p>Cuando se trata de comida, como en muchos otros aspectos de la vida, no se puede improvisar. Tener la nevera vacía e ir
a la última
minuto al supermercado, y te puedo asegurar que probablemente terminarás con comida post procesada y de baja calidad.
nutrientes Este definitivamente no es el camino. Otro beneficio es que con esta técnica puedes evitar
productos en el supermercado y ahorrar una cantidad considerable de dinero.</p>

<h3 id="sé-constante">Sé constante</h3>

<p>Este también puede ser bastante evidente, pero es habitual que mucha gente empiece con su dieta muy motivada. En esto
caso siendo constante es mucho más importante que la intensidad. Definir metas realistas y factibles. De lo
contrario, en 1 semana volverás a donde empezaste.</p>

<h3 id="variedad">Variedad</h3>

<p>Cambiar lo que comes, mientras innovas asegura que no te aburras de la monotonía. Con esto en mente, puede
crea múltiples combinaciones y diviértete evitando los alimentos postprocesados ​​ya preparados.</p>

<p>Puede estar pensando que tener que pensar en lo que necesita cada día puede sonar un poco molesto a primera vista.
Sin embargo, esto le dará una mejor organización de lo que debe preparar. Además, uno de los trucos también es tomar
benefíciate de los productos de temporada y disfruta del sabor de estos productos.</p>

<h3 id="hora-de-romper-las-reglas-a-veces">Hora de romper las reglas (a veces)</h3>

<p>Aunque esto parece lo contrario de lo que se incluye arriba, podría tener su día de trampa, por ejemplo, el fin de
semana. Sin embargo,
aunque al principio probablemente estés anhelando que llegue este día, es posible que te des cuenta de lo siguiente. los
Al día siguiente de ir a este día especial, se sentirá más pesado y no tan saludable como los días anteriores. nuestro
cuerpo es
lo suficientemente inteligente como para advertirnos sobre algo que no les gustó y está causando que nuestro cuerpo
sufra.</p>

<p>Con el tiempo, verás que este día trampa probablemente esté causando más problemas a tu cuerpo, y no lo pedirás.
más. Y tu mente y tu cuerpo te lo agradecerán.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why you should start taking care of what you eat and why the food may be slowly killing you]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/nutrition/fr.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/nutrition/fr.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="es"><title type="html">Algorand Governance Periodo 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/algorand-governance-periodo-5/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Algorand Governance Periodo 5" /><published>2022-10-13T14:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-10-13T14:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/algorand-governance-periodo-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/algorand-governance-periodo-5/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introducción">Introducción</h2>

<p>Sin embargo, antes de continuar, puede ser relevante saber más sobre su funcionamiento.</p>

<h2 id="proceso">Proceso</h2>

<p>Tal y como se describió hace unos meses, en el Periodo de Gobernanza puedes votar y participar en las geniales
iniciativas que propone la Fundación Algorand. Al votar en las diferentes propuestas, obtienes una recompensa. Es
importante tener en cuenta que durante el periodo de 3 meses, la cantidad de tokens ALGO que comprometas debe ser
intacta. Reducir el saldo significa perder el acceso a la recompensa. Además de mantener, es clave que votes por tu
opción preferida. Por ejemplo, un usuario que comprometa 20.000 ALGO y venda 100 ALGO el último día no obtendrá nada. En
cambio, otro usuario que comprometa 1.000 ALGO y mantenga esa cantidad o más se llevará la recompensa. Por lo tanto, es
importante prestar atención a la cantidad comprometida y sólo incluir allí lo que está seguro de poder mantener. No
ocurre nada si asignas más de los ALGO comprometidos una vez que el periodo de gobernanza ha comenzado el 15 de octubre.
Las recompensas que se obtienen se calculan dividiendo el número total de tokens (70,5 millones) por el número de ALGO
comprometidos de todos los gobernantes. También puede ver las estadísticas en la siguiente
página: <a href="https://www.algorandstats.com/governance-period-5">https://www.algorandstats.com/governance-period-5</a></p>

<h2 id="crítica">Crítica</h2>

<p>Uno de los puntos que han aportado algunos usuarios es que garantizar una rentabilidad sin riesgo del 10% (alrededor del
2,5% cada trimestre) canibaliza otros proyectos DeFi en torno a Algorand. Este fue uno de los temas en las sesiones de
votación anteriores, donde hubo algunas iniciativas para impulsar diferentes proyectos DeFi y FutureFi, dando algunos
beneficios a estos proyectos.</p>

<p>Para responder a esto, una de las medidas fue incentivar a los usuarios de DeFi para impulsar diferentes proyectos y
asignar 7M de tokens ALGO a los gobernadores de DeFi. Esta fue la opción que apoyó la Fundación para la Gobernanza en el
último periodo de Gobernanza.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/algorand_5/timeline.jpg" alt="Steps" />
   <span class="caption text-muted">Los diferentes 4 pasos pueden ser definidos arriba para el quinto período
</span>
</p>

<h2 id="proyectos-clave">Proyectos clave</h2>

<p>Como recordarás de este artículo, los 3 pilares principales del uso de Algorand son</p>

<ul>
  <li>Pagos</li>
  <li>NFTs</li>
  <li>Stablecoins</li>
</ul>

<p>La mayoría de los proyectos construidos en la red Algorand están relacionados con DeFi y algunos de ellos también se han
desarrollado gracias a las subvenciones de la fundación Algorand. Conociendo los temas más importantes, es también el
momento de hablar de los proyectos más populares. Algunos de los proyectos más conocidos que utilizan la red Algorand
son los siguientes</p>

<h3 id="1-tinyman">1. Tinyman</h3>

<p>Tinyman es un exchange descentralizado en la que los “swappers” comercian con diferentes activos y los “poolers” proporcionan
liquidez a los pools. ¿Cuál es el objetivo de hacerlo? En este DEX, los poolers obtienen una parte de las comisiones que
los swappers pagan al intercambiar los diferentes tokens.</p>

<p><a href="https://tinyman.org/">Tinyman</a></p>

<h3 id="2-folks-finance">2. Folks Finance</h3>

<p>Folks Finance está construida sobre la chain Algorand y se utiliza para conceder a los usuarios la posibilidad de
prestar y tomar prestados activos en esta plataforma. Una de las ventajas de esta plataforma es que los usuarios pueden
seguir participando en la sesión de gobierno de Algorand sin renunciar a la liquidez. Esto se consigue con un token
gemelo de ALGO llamado gALGO con una equivalencia de 1 a 1.</p>

<p><a href="https://folks.finance/">Folks Finance</a></p>

<h3 id="3-algofi">3. AlgoFI</h3>

<p>AlgoFi es también un intercambio descentralizado y un protocolo de préstamo. Al prestar diferentes activos, los
propietarios pueden ser recompensados con algún interés. Los prestatarios de estos activos depositan algunos activos
como garantía. Una de las ventajas de esto es que incluso si se utiliza como garantía, los tokens ALGO pueden
comprometerse con el Gobierno de Algorand.</p>

<p><a href="AlgoFI">AlgoFI</a></p>

<h3 id="4-algoswap">4. AlgoSwap</h3>

<p>AlgoSwap es otro intercambio descentralizado que se puede integrar en diferentes dApps con sólo unas pocas líneas de
código. Esto lo convierte en una gran herramienta de integración que permite a los usuarios construir sus plataformas
DEX con el mínimo esfuerzo.</p>

<p><a href="https://algopay.finance/algoswap/">AlgoFI</a></p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/algorand_5/folks_finance.jpg" alt="Folks Finance" />
   <span class="caption text-muted">Por su innovación, Folks Finance es una de las estrellas clave apoyadas por la Fundación Algorand
</span>
</p>

<h2 id="monederos">Monederos</h2>

<p>Siguiendo con los siguientes pasos y el proceso de Gobierno, es hora de centrarse en cómo almacenar nuestros ALGOtokens.
Como has visto, hay muchos proyectos en torno a Algorand y muchas formas de depositar tus tokens ALGO. Algunos de los
monederos más populares que existen son</p>

<h3 id="a-myalgo">a) MyAlgo</h3>

<p>MyAlgo es uno de los monederos más intuitivos que existen, con algunas características avanzadas como la firma de
múltiples transacciones al mismo tiempo o la agrupación de transacciones.</p>

<p><a href="https://wallet.myalgo.com/">MyAlgo</a></p>

<h3 id="b-perawallet">b) PeraWallet</h3>

<p>PeraWallet es un monedero descentralizado, fácilmente utilizable tanto en el móvil como en el portátil, con soporte de
ledger también.Es fácil acceder al historial de transacciones, holdings o NFTs.</p>

<p><a href="https://perawallet.app/">PeraWallet</a></p>

<h3 id="c-algosigner">c) AlgoSigner</h3>

<p>AlgoSigner es una extensión para Chrome que puede utilizarse como monedero Algorand. Permite a los usuarios aprobar y
firmar las transacciones generadas por las aplicaciones de Algorand. La ventaja de AlgoSigner es que se puede conceder
acceso a diferentes dApps sin darles acceso a tus claves y que se puede integrar fácilmente en DEX.</p>

<p><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/algosigner/kmmolakhbgdlpkjkcjkebenjheonagdm">AlgoSigner</a></p>

<p>En cuanto a la obtención de ALGO, se encuentra en los intercambios centralizados más populares como Binance, Coinbase o
Kraken. Por lo tanto, no debería ser un problema conseguirlo en tu plataforma preferida. Al igual que con las
criptomonedas, es recomendable que en cuanto lo consigas, si no estás operando con él, lo muevas a uno de los monederos
mencionados para participar en el Goveranceperiod o en tu monedero frío.</p>

<h2 id="medidas-y-otros">Medidas y otros</h2>

<p>En relación con las votaciones, las medidas que se propondrán en el próximo periodo todavía no son y no se espera nada
hasta noviembre. No obstante, teniendo en cuenta las últimas propuestas y los proyectos en curso en torno aAlgorand, no
sería de extrañar que las votaciones vayan en la dirección de potenciar el poder de DeFi y FutureFi.</p>

<p>En este periodo de gobernanza, parece que hay algunas personas que envían algunas pequeñas cantidades a los diferentes
gobernantes, que incluyen algunos mensajes y que no provienen de la Fundación oficial Algorand. Lo más importante es no
hacer clic en ellos porque son mensajes de spam.</p>

<h2 id="participación">Participación</h2>

<p>Participando en el periodo de Gobernanza, estás contribuyendo al futuro de las finanzas. Algorand, una de las cadenas
más sostenibles, es una prueba de participación, y hemos visto el impacto positivo en el medio ambiente que tiene este
mecanismo con la fusión de Ethereum. Otros beneficios de la red Algorand son las bajas tasas, la velocidad y su tiempo
de inactividad cero, que no se puede decir de otras redes como Solana. Por lo tanto, si quieres formar parte de esta
aventura, no olvides comprometer tu ALGO antes de la fecha límite del 21 de octubre.</p>

<p>Una vez que se publique la sesión de votaciones, no te olvides de votar, ya que sólo los usuarios que hayan votado por
alguna de las opciones podrán recibir una participación de los 70,5 millones de tokens ALGO que se pagarán a principios
de enero.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[El periodo de gobernanza de Algorand está a punto de comenzar. Estos son algunos de los temas más importantes a tener en cuenta, incluyendo algunos de las wallets en esta blockchain.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/algorand_5/algorand.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/algorand_5/algorand.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Algorand Governance Period 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/algorand-governance-period-5/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Algorand Governance Period 5" /><published>2022-10-13T14:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-10-13T14:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/algorand-governance-period-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/algorand-governance-period-5/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
The fifth period of the Algorand Governance is about to start and there are some changes being introduced in this phase. The registration will close on October 20th and the rewards will be paid once the period ends on December 31st. 
As in previous governances, the payout of the rewards should be on the first week of January and depending on the wallet you use, you may also receive an NFT.
</div>
<div>
<p>
The page where you can connect your wallet is included below:
            <a href="https://governance.algorand.foundation/governance-period-5">Algorand Governance Period 5</a>

Nonetheless, before continuing, it may be relevant to know more about how it works.
</p>
</div>
<h2 id="process">Process</h2>

<p>As described some months ago, in the Governance Period you can vote and participate in cool initiatives that are
proposed by the Algorand Foundation. By voting on the different proposals, you get rewarded. It’s important to note that
during the 3-month period, the amount of ALGO tokens you commit must be untouched. Reducing the balance means losing the
access to the reward. In addition to holding, it is key that you vote for your preferred option. For example, one user
committing 20,000 ALGO and selling 100 ALGO on the last day will not get anything. Instead another user committing 1,000
ALGO and keeping that amount or more will get the reward. Therefore, it is important to pay attention to the committed
amount and just include there what you are sure you can maintain. Nothing happens if you allocate more than the
committed ALGO once the governance period has started on 15 October. The rewards you earn are calculated by dividend the
total number of tokens (70.5 million) by the number of committed ALGOs from all governors. You can also see the
statistics in the following page: https://www.algorandstats.com/governance-period-5</p>

<h2 id="criticism">Criticism</h2>

<p>One of the points that some users have brought is that guaranteeing a risk-free return of 10% (around 2.5% every
quarter) cannibalizes other DeFi projects around Algorand. This was one of the topics in previous voting sessions, where
there were some initiatives to push different DeFi and FutureFi projects, giving some benefits to these projects.</p>

<p>In order to respond to this, one of the measures was to incentivize DeFi users in order to push different projects and
allocate 7M ALGO tokens to DeFi governors. This was the option the Governance Foundation supported in the last
Governance period.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/algorand_5/timeline.jpg" alt="Steps" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">The different 4 steps can be defined above for the fifth period
</span>
</p>

<h2 id="key-projects">Key projects</h2>
<p>As you may recall from this article, the main 3 pillars of the Algorand usage are:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Payments</li>
  <li>NFTs</li>
  <li>Stablecoins</li>
</ul>

<p>Most of the projects built on the Algorand network are related to DeFi and some of them
have been also developed thanks to grants coming the Algorand foundation. Knowing the most important topics, it’s also
the moment to talk about the most popular projects. Some of the most well-known projects using the Algorand network are
the following</p>

<h3 id="1-tinyman">1. Tinyman</h3>

<p>Tinyman is a decentralized exchange where swappers trade different assets and poolers provide liquidity to the liquidity
pools. What’s the objective of doing so? In this DEX, Poolers get a part of the fees that swappers pay when exchanging
the different tokens.</p>

<p><a href="https://tinyman.org/">Tinyman</a></p>

<h3 id="2-folks-finance">2. Folks Finance</h3>
<p>Folks Finance is built on top of the Algorand chain and it’s used to grant users the possibility
lend and borrow assets in this platform. One of the benefits of this platform is that users can still participate in the
Algorand governance session without renouncing to the liquidity. This is achieved with an ALGO token twin called gALGO
with a 1 to 1 equivalent.</p>

<p><a href="https://folks.finance/">Folks Finance</a></p>

<h3 id="3-algofi">3. AlgoFI</h3>
<p>AlgoFi is also a decentralized exchange and a lending protocol. By lending different assets, the owners can
get rewarded with some interest. The borrowers of these assets deposit some assets as collateral. One of the advantages
of this is that even if used as collateral, the ALGO tokens can be committed to the Algorand Governance.</p>

<p><a href="AlgoFI">AlgoFI</a></p>

<h3 id="4-algoswap">4. AlgoSwap</h3>
<p>AlgoSwap is another decentralized exchange which can be integrated into different dApps with just a few
lines of code. This makes it a great integration tool enabling users to build their DEX platforms with minimum effort.</p>

<p><a href="https://algopay.finance/algoswap/">AlgoFI</a></p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/algorand_5/folks_finance.jpg" alt="Folks Finance" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Due to its innovation, Folks Finance is one of the key stars supported by the Algorand Foundation
</span>
</p>

<h2 id="wallets">Wallets</h2>
<p>Continuing with the next steps and the Governance process, it is time to focus on how to store our ALGO
tokens. As you have seen, there are many projects around Algorand and many ways to commit your ALGO Tokens. Some of the
most popular wallets out there are:</p>

<h3 id="a-myalgo">a) MyAlgo</h3>
<p>MyAlgo is one of the most intuitive wallets out there, with some advance features such as signing multiple
transactions at the same time or transaction-grouping.</p>

<p><a href="https://wallet.myalgo.com/">MyAlgo</a></p>

<h3 id="b-perawallet">b) PeraWallet</h3>
<p>PeraWallet is a decentralized wallet, easily used in both mobile and laptops, with ledger support too.
It’s easy to access the transaction history, holdings or NFTs.</p>

<p><a href="https://perawallet.app/">PeraWallet</a></p>

<h3 id="c-algosigner">c) AlgoSigner</h3>
<p>AlgoSigner an extension for Chrome that can be used as an Algorand wallet. It lets users approve and
sign transactions that are generated by Algorand applications. The benefit of AlgoSigner is that there is you can grant
access to different dApps without giving them access you your keys and that it can be integrated into easily into DEX.</p>

<p><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/algosigner/kmmolakhbgdlpkjkcjkebenjheonagdm">AlgoSigner</a></p>

<p>Related to getting ALGO, it is in most popular centralized exchanges such as Binance, Coinbase or Kraken. Therefore, it
should not be a problem to get it you’re your preferred platform. As with crypto, it is recommended that as soon as you
get it, if you are not trading it, you move it to one of the mentioned wallets in order to participate in the Goverance
period or in your cold wallet.</p>

<h2 id="measures--other">Measures &amp; Other</h2>
<p>Related to the voting, the measures that will be proposed in the upcoming period are still not now
and nothing is expected until November. Nonetheless, considering the latest proposals and ongoing projects around
Algorand, it would not surprise that the voting sessions go in the direction of boosting the power of DeFi and FutureFi.</p>

<p>In this governance period, it seems that there are some people sending some small amounts to the different governors.
They include some messages and are not coming from the official Algorand Foundation. The most important thing is not to
click on them because they are spam messages.</p>

<h2 id="participation">Participation</h2>
<p>Taking part in the Governance period, you are contributing to the future of finance. Algorand, one of the most sustainable chains, is proof of stake, and we have
seen the positive impact in the environment that this mechanism has with the Ethereum Merge. It’s also one of the
reasons for being named the Green Blockchain- Other benefits of the Algorand network are the low fees, speed and its
zero downtime, which cannot be said from other networks such as Solana. Therefore, if you want to be part of this
adventure, don’t forget to commit your ALGO before the deadline on 21 October.</p>

<p>Once the voting session is published, you
should not forget to vote, since just users who voted for any of the options will be eligible to receive a stake of the
70.5 million ALGO tokens to be paid on beginning of January</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Algorand Governance Period is about to start. These are some of the most important topics to consider, including some of the most important wallets in this blockchain]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/algorand_5/algorand.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/algorand_5/algorand.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="es"><title type="html">El Ethereum Merge Explicado</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/el-ethereum-merge-explicado/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="El Ethereum Merge Explicado" /><published>2022-09-18T14:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-18T14:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/el-ethereum-merge-explicado</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/el-ethereum-merge-explicado/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
En las últimas semanas hemos visto mucho entusiasmo proveniente de diferentes lugares con respecto a lo que se llama el evento del año en el mundo crypto. 
Me refiero a Ethereum y lo que no es un cambio de juego solo para Ethereum en sí mismo para toda la industria crypto como resultado de los grandes cambios que conlleva esta bifurcación.
</div>

<p>El Ethereum Merge ha sido uno de los cambios más ambiciosos y esperados en la red. Muy esperado porque los primeros
planes sobre los datos de actualización de este software se remontan a 2014, y la actualización se produjo el 15 de
septiembre de 2022, casi 10 años después. El fork también abre nuevas oportunidades para el uso de blockchain en
diferentes componentes y estándares, debido a los problemas y la ineficiencia que trae consigo el nuevo mecanismo de
consenso.</p>

<p>Además, aunque Ethereum ya es la red con más utilidades y casos de negocios, esto puede impulsar la comercialidad de
esta red y llevarla al siguiente nivel con la entrada de nuevos jugadores.</p>

<p>Sin ir más lejos, este evento puede ser también el que cambie las tornas para recuperar la confianza perdida y ver que hay
diferentes proyectos intentando potenciar las utilidades de las distintas cadenas.</p>

<p>No obstante, incluso si algunas fuentes dijeron que esta fusión solucionará algunos de los problemas conocidos en la red
Ethereum, no tienen ningún impacto en ellos. Tendremos que ver actualizaciones adicionales para ver si estos temas se
modifican.</p>

<p>Estos son básicamente los puntos que conlleva esta actualización de red y cuáles, para evitar malentendidos, problemas
que no se abordan con esta modificación en este cambio de software.</p>

<h2 id="cuáles-son-los-principales-cambios">¿Cuáles son los principales cambios?</h2>

<h3 id="1-energía">1. Energía</h3>

<p>Cambiar de los protocolos de Proof of Work a Proof of Stake significa que el consumo de energía se reducirá
aproximadamente en un 99 %.</p>

<p>El derroche y la eficiencia energética ha sido uno de los temas que algunos criptodetractores como los reguladores han
incluido como una de las desventajas del crecimiento de blockchain.</p>

<p>Varios han criticado algunas de las cadenas de bloques PoW como Bitcoin o Ethereum por el impacto ambiental negativo que
tenían y el uso excesivo de energía para validar las transacciones en la red.</p>

<p>Algunos de los usos más conocidos y controvertidos de Ethereum son la acuñación de NFT utilizando ERC-721. Este cambio
tendrá un impacto mucho mayor en el mercado volátil de los NFT debido a la caída del uso de energía para acuñarlos, lo
que permitirá el crecimiento de este negocio.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/ethereum/sustainable.jpeg" alt="Thinking about the future" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Independientemente de los otros detalles técnicos, es un gran hito reducir el uso de energía en alrededor del 99 % gracias a Merge.
</span>
</p>

<h3 id="2-recompensas-más-democráticas">2. Recompensas más democráticas</h3>

<p>Además del cambio en la eficiencia energética, el cambio a la Proof of Stake también significa que, a través de este
mecanismo, se terminaron las recompensas por validar y asegurar la red que estaban reservadas para aquellos con
computadoras potentes.</p>

<p>Hay que tener en cuenta que se necesita al menos 32 ETH (alrededor de 48 000 USD al momento de escribir este artículo) más la
computadora para realizar el staking por su cuenta. Sin embargo, existen opciones más utilizadas, como el liquidity staking,
utilizando ERC-20, donde puede asignar parte de sus tokens ETH a un grupo (para alcanzar el mínimo de 32 ETH).</p>

<p>En caso de que no esté satisfecho con ninguna de estas opciones, a pesar de no ser tan popular, otra posibilidad para
recibir recompensas de apuesta por su parte es apostarlas a través de un intercambio centralizado.</p>

<p>Al igual que con todos estos casos, investiga por tu cuenta antes de delegar tus tokens.</p>

<h3 id="3-precio-y-valor">3. Precio y valor</h3>

<p>El orecio y valor de  un activo no deben entenderse de forma equivocada. Esto tampoco es algo bueno o malo proveniente del Merge</p>

<p>Aunque el Merge se ha esperado durante años, lo cierto es que Ether ha perdido alrededor del 60% de su valor de mercado
durante 2022. Sin embargo, si tomamos como referencia el índice CMC 200, la caída del precio también está alineada con
la caída de este.</p>

<p>En cambio, por ejemplo, Ethereum tuvo un incremento del 100%, cuando los precios en agosto pasaron de 1.000 USD a 2.000 USD.</p>

<p>Como se discutió en otros temas, no ha habido un cambio drástico, al alza o a la baja, en el precio de Ethereum en la
fecha en que se completó la bifurcación. Al igual que con otros activos, el precio ya está descontado cuando ocurren
estos grandes eventos. Como habrás notado, hubo un aumento en el precio en los meses previos a la Fusión.</p>

<p>En el futuro, Ethereum pasará a ser un activo deflacionario. Antes de la fusión y con el PoW, se emitían diariamente 13
000 nuevos tokens de Ether. El cambio cambia esto y de 13.000 veremos alrededor de 1.600 tokens de Ether por día.</p>

<p>Cuantos menos tokens haya, mayor debería ser el precio de los tokens Ether, siendo un activo deflacionario alternativo.</p>

<h2 id="aspects-that-remain-unchanged">Aspects that remain unchanged</h2>

<p>Probablemente, algunos de los temas más comunes cuando se trata de Ethereum son las tarifas. La mala noticia es que la
lógica de estos permanece sin cambios. Estos son otros problemas que Ethereum Merge no resuelve o no se han modificado
con Merge.</p>

<h3 id="1-tarifas">1. Tarifas</h3>

<p>“La bifurcación definitivamente hará que las tarifas del gas sean más baratas”. Esto es erróneo y los cambios que
ocurrieron en la red no tuvieron ninguna consecuencia en las tarifas que se deben pagar en cada transacción de
blockchain para recompensar a los validadores de las transacciones que ocurren en la cadena. El último cambio en la red
que afectó cómo se debe pagar el Wei por transacción fue el London Upgrade en 2021.</p>

<h3 id="2-velocidad">2. Velocidad</h3>

<p>Relacionado con el dilema de blockchain, el Merge no aumenta la velocidad ni aumenta la cantidad de transacciones que se
pueden procesar por minuto. Puede haber una ligera mejora en la velocidad, pero será imperceptible para los usuarios.
Para los cambios de velocidad habrá que esperar por si algún día llega esta modificación.</p>

<h2 id="conclusiones-clave">Conclusiones clave</h2>

<p>Ha habido mucha expectación debido a este hito del Merge, y se ha esperado durante algún tiempo. Debido a todas las
noticias en torno a este tema durante el último año, estos son los principales datos que podemos decir para concluir y
ver cómo evoluciona este tema.</p>

<h3 id="impacto-medioambiental">Impacto medioambiental</h3>

<p>Este es definitivamente el mayor cambio y la principal ventaja de la actualización del software. No solo relacionado con
la crisis energética actual, este es un gran paso para proteger nuestro planeta con un uso más sensato y responsable de
la electricidad. Esto puede ser un hito clave para alcanzar la sostenibilidad en la industria crypto (aunque, por
ejemplo, no hay planes, por ejemplo, para Bitcoin y cambiar de PoW a PoS en este caso) debido a las nuevas posibilidades
en las diferentes redes y estándares que permite.</p>

<h3 id="staking-para-todos">Staking para todos</h3>

<p>Si bien validar y asegurar la red era una acción reservada para aquellos con más poder de cómputo, por lo que las
recompensas eran solo para ellos, el cambio a PoS significa que todos podemos participar asegurando las transacciones y
siendo recompensados ​​por los tokens de Ether que usamos para lograr eso</p>

<h3 id="impacto-comercial">Impacto comercial</h3>

<p>Haber reducido el uso de energía y mejorar la eficiencia energética también ha abierto nuevas ideas para Ethereum, que
ya tenía muchas aplicaciones en este ecosistema. Además, esto no solo es importante para Ethereum, sino para otras
cadenas, y también significa que la evolución de las diferentes cadenas de bloques conducirá a una mejor experiencia
para los usuarios y a más ideas de negocios que hace algunos años eran impensables por cuestiones de sostenibilidad.</p>

<hr />

<p>Habiendo explicado los cambios más importantes y también negado cosas que el Merge no cambia, es cierto que algunos de
estos cambios pueden impulsar a Ethereum y al sector de las criptomonedas. Al mismo tiempo, no se puede negar que
algunos usuarios se han decepcionado porque esperaban mucho más. El tiempo dirá.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Los cambios que el Ethereum Merge, incluyendo el impacto que crean y qué aspectos no se modifican con este fork en la red]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/ethereum/eth.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/ethereum/eth.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">The Ethereum Merge Explained</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-ethereum-merge-explained/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ethereum Merge Explained" /><published>2022-09-18T14:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-18T14:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-ethereum-merge-explained</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-ethereum-merge-explained/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<div class="text-article">
In the last weeks we have seen a lot of excitement coming from different places in regards to  what’s called the event of the year in crypto world. I’m
referring to Ethereum and what is not a gamechanger just for Ethereum itself for the whole crypto industry as as result of the big changes that this fork carries.
</div>

<p>The Ethereum Merge has been one of the most ambitious and awaited changes in the network. Long-awaited because there
first plans about this software upgrade data back to 2014, and the upgrade occurred on 15 September 2022, almost 10
years later. The fork also opens new opportunities for the usage of blockchain in different components and standards,
due to the problems and inefficiency that the new consensus mechanism brings.</p>

<p>Furthermore, although Ethereum is the already network with more utilities and business cases, this can boost the
commerciality of this network and push it to thew next level with the entry of new players.</p>

<p>Besides, this event can be the one that turn the tables in order to recover the lost trust and see that there are
different projects trying to enhance the utilities of the different chains</p>

<p>Nonetheless, even if some sources said that this Merge will fix some of the known issues in the Ethereum network, they
don’t have any impact on them. We will need to see additional upgrades in order to see if these topics are modified.</p>

<p>This is basically the points that this network upgrade entails and what, in order to avoid misunderstandings, problems
that are not tackled with this modification in this software change.</p>

<h2 id="what-are-the-main-changes">What are the main changes?</h2>

<h3 id="1-energy">1. Energy</h3>

<p>Switching from the Proof of Work to Proof Stake protocols means that the energy consumption will decline approximated by
99%.</p>

<p>Energy waste and efficiency has been one of the topics that some crypto detractors such as regulators have included as
one of the disadvantages of the growth of blockchain.</p>

<p>Several have criticized some of the PoW blockchains such as Bitcoin or Ethereum because of the negative environmental
impact they had and the excessive usage of energy to validate the transactions in the network.</p>

<p>Some of the most known - and controversial - usages of Ethereum is the minting of NFTs using ERC-721. This change will
have a much better impact on the volatile market of the NFTs because of the drop of the energy usage to mint them,
enabling the growth of this business.</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/ethereum/sustainable.jpeg" alt="Thinking about the future" />
    <span class="caption text-muted">Regardless of the other technical details, it is a great milestone to reduce the energy usage on around 99% thanks to the Merge
</span>
</p>

<h3 id="2-more-democratic-rewards">2. More democratic rewards</h3>

<p>Apart from the change in the energy efficiency, the switch to Proof of Work also means that via this mechanism, the
staking rewards for validating and securing the network that were reserved for those with powerful computers is over.</p>

<p>Please note you will need at least 32 ETH (around 48,000 USD at the time of writing) plus the computer to perform
staking on your own. However, there are more used options such as liquidity staking, using ERC-20, where you may
allocate part of your ETH tokens to a pool (in order to reach the minimum of 32 ETH).</p>

<p>In case you are not happy with none of these options, despite not being that popular, another possibility in order to
receive staking rewards for your share are staking them via a centralized exchange.</p>

<p>As with all these cases, please do your own research before delegating your tokens.</p>

<h3 id="3-price-and-value">3. Price and value</h3>

<p>Price and value must not be understood in the wrong way. This is also not a good or bad thing coming from the Merge.</p>

<p>Although the Merge has been waited for years, the truth is that Ether has lost around 60% of its market value during 2022.
However, if we use the CMC 200 index as reference, the price drop is also aligned with the drop in the CMC 200
index.</p>

<p>On the other hand, for instance, it had an increase of 100%, when the prices went in August from 1,000 USD to 2,000 USD.</p>

<p>As discussed in other topics, there has not been a drastic change – upwards or downwards- in Ethereum’s price on the
date the fork was completed. As with other assets, the price is already discounted when these big events occur. As you
may have noticed, there were a surge on the price in the months prior to the Merge.</p>

<p>In the future, Ethereum will be transition to a deflationary asset. Before the Merge and with the PoW, 13,000 new Ether
tokens were issued on a daily basis. The change changes this and from 13,000 we will see around 1,600 Ether tokens per
day.</p>

<p>The less tokens there are, the higher the price should be for Ether tokens, being an alternative deflationary asset.</p>

<h2 id="aspects-that-remain-unchanged">Aspects that remain unchanged</h2>

<p>Probably some of the most common topics when it comes to Ethereum are fees. The bad news is that the logic for these remains unchanged.
These are other problems that Ethereum Merge does not solve or haven’t been modified with the Merge.</p>

<h3 id="1-fees">1. Fees</h3>

<p>“The fork will definitely make the gas fees cheaper.” This is wrong and the changes that occurred in the network did not
have any consequences on the fees that must be paid on each blockchain transaction to reward the validators of the
transactions occurring in the chain. The last change in the network that affected how the Wei that must be paid per
transaction was the London Upgrade in 2021.</p>

<h3 id="2-speed">2. Speed</h3>

<p>Related to the blockchain dilemma, the Merge does not make the speed faster neither increases that number of
transactions that can be processed per minute. There may be a slight improvement in the speed, but it will be
unnoticeable for users. For the speed changes, we will have to wait in case this modification arrives one day.</p>

<h2 id="key-takeaways">Key takeaways</h2>

<p>There has been a lot of hype because of this Merge milestone, and it has been waited for some time now. Due to all the
news surrounding this topic for the last year, these are the main facts that we can say in order to conclude and see how
this topic evolves.</p>

<h3 id="environmental-impact">Environmental impact</h3>

<p>This is definitely the biggest changes and main advantage of the software upgrade. Not just related to the current energy crisis, this is a huge step in order to protect our
planet with a more sensible and responsible usage of electricity. This can be a key milestone for a reaching
sustainability in the crypto industry (although for example there are no plans for example for Bitcoin and switching
from PoW to PoS in this case) because of the new possibilities on the different networks and standards that enables.</p>

<h3 id="staking-for-all-users">Staking for all users</h3>

<p>While validating and securing the network was an action reserved for those with more computing power, hence the rewards
were just for them, the change to PoS means that all of us can take part securing the transactions and getting rewarded
for the Ether tokens we use to achieve that.</p>

<h3 id="commercial-impact">Commercial impact</h3>

<p>Having reduced the energy usage and improving the energy efficiency has also opened new ideas to Ethereum, which already had many apps
around this ecosystem. Furthermore, this is not just important to Ethereum, but other chains, and it also means that the
evolution of the different blockchains will lead to a better experience for the users and more business ideas that some
years ago were unthinkable because of sustainable issues.</p>

<hr />

<p>Having explained the most important changes and having also denied things that the Merge does not change, it’s true that some of these changes can boost Ethereum and the crypto sector. 
At the same time, it cannot be denied that some users have been disappointed because they were expecting much more. Time will tell.</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The changes that the Ethereum Merge, including the impact they create and what aspects are not modified with this fork in the network]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/ethereum/eth.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/ethereum/eth.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="enn"><title type="html">10 Benefits of HIIT</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/09/11/benefits_10_hiit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 Benefits of HIIT" /><published>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/09/11/benefits_10_hiit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/09/11/benefits_10_hiit/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        In the past years, there is being a surge on sport and health topics. We
        look more and more for some alternatives or variations of the most classic
        sports that keep evolving throughout years. One of the activities that has
        been quite trendy in the last years it’s HIIT.
    </p>
</div>

<p>
    In this post we will discuss how HIIT - High Intensity Interval Training
    works and how it may help you in your day-to-day life.
</p>
<p>
    The different advantages that HIIT has goes from mere performance
    improvement to health improvements. However, there is more than this and
    HIIT also includes some advantages to our well-being and the enjoyment of
    our activities.
</p>
<p>
    But before we start describing, in case you don’t know, what’s HITT and how
    it works?
</p>
<p>
    In simple terms, HIIT is the combination of both:
</p>
<ul>
    - High intensity intervals
</ul>
<ul>
    - Low intensity intervals that are used to recover from the high intensity
</ul>
<p>
    By high intensity intervals, it’s meant by those intervals where the heart
    rate capacity is equal to at least 80% of the maximum heart rate.
</p>
<p>
    The frequency of the high and low intensity may vary, and it can go from to
    2:1 or 1:2
</p>
<p>
    An example may be clearer if we add some numbers.
</p>
<p>
    Let’s imagine runner who performs the following steps:
</p>
<ul>
    1. 60-seconds sprint
</ul>
<ul>
    2. 120-second Low intensity jogging
</ul>
<ul>
    3. 60-seconds sprint
</ul>
<ul>
    4. 120-second Low intensity jogging
</ul>
</li>
<p>
    And like that you can play with different variations. For example, sprints
    of 60 seconds and rest 60 seconds, etc.
</p>
<p>
    The goal of the HIIT session is to give everything and end exhausted at the
    end of it.
</p>
<p>
    Starting with HIIT means also getting out of your comfort zone and it may
    be challenging for you at the beginning. Nevertheless, being progressive
    and reading the following benefits will for sure help you go to the next
    level.
</p>
<h3>
    1. Lack of time
</h3>
<p>
    We would like to have days of 48 hours, but this is not possible. With HIIT
    you can reduce your sessions to more than half of it. From a 60-minute
    low-intensity session, you can switch it to a 15/20-minute HIIT session.
</p>
<p>
    A 20-minute session will be enough to complete your daily activity and
    objectives.
</p>
<p>
    In other words, the usual 45 minutes sessions you have can be to just
    20-minute session. The minutes you don’t use can be used for any other
    thing.
</p>
<p>
    Even if shorter duration, you will with a higher sensation of completeness
    and job well done because of the work that your body does after the work.
</p>
<p>
    Further, there is no need to do these sessions every day. Since in every
    session, a lot of stress is added to your organs and muscles, 3 or 4 HITT
    sessions will be more than enough for you and your body. We will later see
    the post-process.
</p>
<p>
    This benefit is a good argument to tell people who complain that they don’t
    do any exercise because they have too many things to do and no time. Most
    of us should be able to take 20 minutes from other daily tasks.
</p>
<h3>
    2. Get fit
</h3>
<p>
    As we have described above, if you have been without performing sport for
    some time, you should start slowly with HIIT. At the same time, this is a
    great technique to get in shape quite quickly compared to low-intensity
    trainings. Therefore, it may be a good idea in case you have joined a race
    in a few months, and you should prepare it beforehand.
</p>
<h3>
    3. Multiple variations
</h3>
<p>
    Although HIIT is more associated to jogging, many sports and activities can
    be applied to this technique. This means that you can enrich your portfolio
    of exercises and increase the fun.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/diverse_hiit.jpg" alt="Cientos de maneras">
    <span class="caption text-muted">El HIIT no es exclusivo de trotar, y puedes experimentarlo de muchas maneras
</span>
</p>
<p>
    Some of the most important activies are:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Swimming
    </li>
    <li>
        Cycling
    </li>
    <li>
        Weight training
    </li>
    <li>
        Rope jumping
    </li>
    <li>
        Rowing
    </li>
    <li>
        Burpees
    </li>
    <li>
        Dancing
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
</p>
<p>
    As it occurs with nutrition, having a diversified set of exercises will
    help you not get bored and opening your mind to practice new ones.
</p>
<h3>
    4. Muscular mass
</h3>
<p>
    For professionals who compete, you may have heard different opinions about
    the different exercises and planning. Some argue that with running, they
    may lose part of their muscular mass that they have gained.
</p>
<p>
    The benefit of HIIT, linked also to the duration is that you can achieve
    the following:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Reduce the body fat
    </li>
    <li>
        Maintain the muscular mass
    </li>
    <li>
        Increase the muscular mass in the legs
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Another example is if in the Olympics or you have a look at the bodies of
    different sports.
</p>
<p>
    If you have a look at the bodies of marathon runners or long-distance
    cyclists you may see very thin athletes with low fat, but also low muscular
    mass except for the legs. The reason is that when performing these long-duration activities, the
    glucogen reserves are empty and the body starts taking energy from: fat and
    lipids.
</p>
<p>
    For that reason, HIIT is a clear win-win solution and the reason for being
    the preferred choice for many athletes.
</p>
<h3>
    5. Metabolism
</h3>
<p>
    High Intense Interval Training is also called metabolic booster. The reason is that practicing HIIT
    produces a considerable acceleration in the metabolism of our body. But why
    is that? Due to the work that is performed, our body is pushed to the next
    level. Our body is clever enough and demands a bigger amount of oxygen to
    provide to our organs: heart, lungs, etc. However, it is not that the only
    reason only.
</p>
<p>
    Apart from that, some components that were broken in the exercise must be
    restored and the energy that must be used to recover these proteins,
    tendons, etc., in the recovery phase is why our body keeps working even if
    we are in our sofa.
</p>
<p>
    This process last around 48 hours and that’s why during this time, our body
    keeps burning calories. This is another reason for just having to perform
    this activity 3-4 times per week.
</p>
<h3>
    6. Better performance
</h3>
<p>
    Depending on the activity, some parts of our body will be development.
    However, HIIT has a great impact in the performance, and you may see
    improvements in the following factors:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Speed
    </li>
    <li>
        Agility
    </li>
    <li>
        Power
    </li>
    <li>
        Resistance
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    If you practice HIIT you may have noticed that your performance in other
    sports such as swimming or cycling has also improved.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/cycling.jpg" alt="Useful for other sports">
    <span class="caption text-muted">HIIT can boost your VO2 Max levels that can be very beneficial for sports such as cycling</span>
</p>
<p>
    One common thin with these sports is the VO2 max effectiveness. VO2 max
    measures the efficiency that your body uses the oxygen while performing
    your activity. Higher VO2 Max higher performance. There is a story back to
    the times of when triathlons were created in 1970 and who would win?
    Runners, swimmers, or cyclists? Some said that cyclists would be the
    winners because back then Eddy Merckx had the highest VO2 levels.
</p>
<h2>
    7. Heart
</h2>
<p>
    Not everything must be fun and performance. One of the most important
    characteristics is related to our health. If you suffer from health issues
    such as high pressure, you will be happy to hear that runners that practice
    HIIT benefit from a much better heart health.
</p>
<p>
    Further, HIIT increases the amount of blood that the heart can pump.
</p>
<p>
    Of course, if you have some health issues, another piece of advice would be
    having some medical checks before starting practicing this technique.
</p>
<h3>
    8. Cost
</h3>
<p>
    Starting with other sports and activities means increasing the fun.
    Nonetheless, in most cases to invest in different articles (bicycle,
    dumbbells, skis, goggles, etc.) If you are already jogging, there is
    nothing that you would have to buy.
</p>
<p>
    This one is obvious, but with HIIT, you will be able to reuse the equipment
    you already have, and this will not mean an extra cost.
</p>
<h3>
    9. Kill the monotony
</h3>
<p>
    Coming back to the duration, being running at the same pace for 45 or 60
    minutes may not be the most exciting activity. If you live in a big city, you
    will not find many tracks close to your place with 45/60 minutes routes.
</p>
<p>
    Since the duration for HIIT is much shorter, this also gives you many more
    possibilities when combining the different routes.
</p>

<p>
    Related to the variations and the monotony, there are also many other
    variations that we may say in other articles. For example, you may practice
    HIIT while doing some trail or as we have seen in other sports.
</p>
<h2>
    10 Risk of injuries
</h2>
<p>
    Finalizing with another health topic, being running for 60 minutes every
    day on the road or any other hard surface may not be the most convenient
    way to keep your knees.
</p>
<p>
    I remember this was my main reason for switching to HIIT some 5-6 years
    ago.
</p>
<p>
    After 20-30 minutes low-intensity running, I had a strong pain in the left
    knee, and I had to stop running. After 3-4 times, I decided I had to reduce
    the duration of these exercises or just stop. I decided to continue but
    compensating the lower duration with a more active and high interval
    trainings. That’s how I started and ever since I did not have any problem.
</p>
<p>
    Every time we run our knees and other articulations may be subject to
    prolonged times of and a wrong way of running may lead to injuries. By
    reducing the duration of our training, we also reduce the risk of injuries
    and conserve intact our articulations.
</p>
<h2>
    What’s next
</h2>
<p>
    In conclusion, you have seen different advantages of practicing HIIT. It
    may sound challenging for you at the beginning, but I can assure you that
    this will not deceive you and will push your body to the next level.
</p>
<p>
    We have found what the different benefits in terms of time, fun, health, and
    performance are. As discussed in one of the points, trying is free, and you may start with a just 10-minute session
    to give it a
    try.
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[From performance to health, what HIIT can add to your daily routines]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">10 Benefits of HIIT</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/10-benefits-hiit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 Benefits of HIIT" /><published>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/10-benefits-hiit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/10-benefits-hiit/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        In the past years, there is being a surge on sport and health topics. We
        look more and more for some alternatives or variations of the most classic
        sports that keep evolving throughout years. One of the activities that has
        been quite trendy in the last years it’s HIIT.
    </p>
</div>

<p>
    In this post we will discuss how HIIT - High Intensity Interval Training
    works and how it may help you in your day-to-day life.
</p>
<p>
    The different advantages that HIIT has goes from mere performance
    improvement to health improvements. However, there is more than this and
    HIIT also includes some advantages to our well-being and the enjoyment of
    our activities.
</p>
<p>
    But before we start describing, in case you don’t know, what’s HITT and how
    it works?
</p>
<p>
    In simple terms, HIIT is the combination of both:
</p>
<ul>
    - High intensity intervals
</ul>
<ul>
    - Low intensity intervals that are used to recover from the high intensity
</ul>
<p>
    By high intensity intervals, it’s meant by those intervals where the heart
    rate capacity is equal to at least 80% of the maximum heart rate.
</p>
<p>
    The frequency of the high and low intensity may vary, and it can go from to
    2:1 or 1:2
</p>
<p>
    An example may be clearer if we add some numbers.
</p>
<p>
    Let’s imagine runner who performs the following steps:
</p>
<ul>
    1. 60-seconds sprint
</ul>
<ul>
    2. 120-second Low intensity jogging
</ul>
<ul>
    3. 60-seconds sprint
</ul>
<ul>
    4. 120-second Low intensity jogging
</ul>
</li>
<p>
    And like that you can play with different variations. For example, sprints
    of 60 seconds and rest 60 seconds, etc.
</p>
<p>
    The goal of the HIIT session is to give everything and end exhausted at the
    end of it.
</p>
<p>
    Starting with HIIT means also getting out of your comfort zone and it may
    be challenging for you at the beginning. Nevertheless, being progressive
    and reading the following benefits will for sure help you go to the next
    level.
</p>
<h3>
    1. Lack of time
</h3>
<p>
    We would like to have days of 48 hours, but this is not possible. With HIIT
    you can reduce your sessions to more than half of it. From a 60-minute
    low-intensity session, you can switch it to a 15/20-minute HIIT session.
</p>
<p>
    A 20-minute session will be enough to complete your daily activity and
    objectives.
</p>
<p>
    In other words, the usual 45 minutes sessions you have can be to just
    20-minute session. The minutes you don’t use can be used for any other
    thing.
</p>
<p>
    Even if shorter duration, you will with a higher sensation of completeness
    and job well done because of the work that your body does after the work.
</p>
<p>
    Further, there is no need to do these sessions every day. Since in every
    session, a lot of stress is added to your organs and muscles, 3 or 4 HITT
    sessions will be more than enough for you and your body. We will later see
    the post-process.
</p>
<p>
    This benefit is a good argument to tell people who complain that they don’t
    do any exercise because they have too many things to do and no time. Most
    of us should be able to take 20 minutes from other daily tasks.
</p>
<h3>
    2. Get fit
</h3>
<p>
    As we have described above, if you have been without performing sport for
    some time, you should start slowly with HIIT. At the same time, this is a
    great technique to get in shape quite quickly compared to low-intensity
    trainings. Therefore, it may be a good idea in case you have joined a race
    in a few months, and you should prepare it beforehand.
</p>
<h3>
    3. Multiple variations
</h3>
<p>
    Although HIIT is more associated to jogging, many sports and activities can
    be applied to this technique. This means that you can enrich your portfolio
    of exercises and increase the fun.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/diverse_hiit.jpg" alt="Cientos de maneras">
    <span class="caption text-muted">El HIIT no es exclusivo de trotar, y puedes experimentarlo de muchas maneras
</span>
</p>
<p>
    Some of the most important activies are:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Swimming
    </li>
    <li>
        Cycling
    </li>
    <li>
        Weight training
    </li>
    <li>
        Rope jumping
    </li>
    <li>
        Rowing
    </li>
    <li>
        Burpees
    </li>
    <li>
        Dancing
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
</p>
<p>
    As it occurs with nutrition, having a diversified set of exercises will
    help you not get bored and opening your mind to practice new ones.
</p>
<h3>
    4. Muscular mass
</h3>
<p>
    For professionals who compete, you may have heard different opinions about
    the different exercises and planning. Some argue that with running, they
    may lose part of their muscular mass that they have gained.
</p>
<p>
    The benefit of HIIT, linked also to the duration is that you can achieve
    the following:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Reduce the body fat
    </li>
    <li>
        Maintain the muscular mass
    </li>
    <li>
        Increase the muscular mass in the legs
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Another example is if in the Olympics or you have a look at the bodies of
    different sports.
</p>
<p>
    If you have a look at the bodies of marathon runners or long-distance
    cyclists you may see very thin athletes with low fat, but also low muscular
    mass except for the legs. The reason is that when performing these long-duration activities, the
    glucogen reserves are empty and the body starts taking energy from: fat and
    lipids.
</p>
<p>
    For that reason, HIIT is a clear win-win solution and the reason for being
    the preferred choice for many athletes.
</p>
<h3>
    5. Metabolism
</h3>
<p>
    High Intense Interval Training is also called metabolic booster. The reason is that practicing HIIT
    produces a considerable acceleration in the metabolism of our body. But why
    is that? Due to the work that is performed, our body is pushed to the next
    level. Our body is clever enough and demands a bigger amount of oxygen to
    provide to our organs: heart, lungs, etc. However, it is not that the only
    reason only.
</p>
<p>
    Apart from that, some components that were broken in the exercise must be
    restored and the energy that must be used to recover these proteins,
    tendons, etc., in the recovery phase is why our body keeps working even if
    we are in our sofa.
</p>
<p>
    This process last around 48 hours and that’s why during this time, our body
    keeps burning calories. This is another reason for just having to perform
    this activity 3-4 times per week.
</p>
<h3>
    6. Better performance
</h3>
<p>
    Depending on the activity, some parts of our body will be development.
    However, HIIT has a great impact in the performance, and you may see
    improvements in the following factors:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Speed
    </li>
    <li>
        Agility
    </li>
    <li>
        Power
    </li>
    <li>
        Resistance
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    If you practice HIIT you may have noticed that your performance in other
    sports such as swimming or cycling has also improved.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/cycling.jpg" alt="Useful for other sports">
    <span class="caption text-muted">HIIT can boost your VO2 Max levels that can be very beneficial for sports such as cycling</span>
</p>
<p>
    One common thin with these sports is the VO2 max effectiveness. VO2 max
    measures the efficiency that your body uses the oxygen while performing
    your activity. Higher VO2 Max higher performance. There is a story back to
    the times of when triathlons were created in 1970 and who would win?
    Runners, swimmers, or cyclists? Some said that cyclists would be the
    winners because back then Eddy Merckx had the highest VO2 levels.
</p>
<h2>
    7. Heart
</h2>
<p>
    Not everything must be fun and performance. One of the most important
    characteristics is related to our health. If you suffer from health issues
    such as high pressure, you will be happy to hear that runners that practice
    HIIT benefit from a much better heart health.
</p>
<p>
    Further, HIIT increases the amount of blood that the heart can pump.
</p>
<p>
    Of course, if you have some health issues, another piece of advice would be
    having some medical checks before starting practicing this technique.
</p>
<h3>
    8. Cost
</h3>
<p>
    Starting with other sports and activities means increasing the fun.
    Nonetheless, in most cases to invest in different articles (bicycle,
    dumbbells, skis, goggles, etc.) If you are already jogging, there is
    nothing that you would have to buy.
</p>
<p>
    This one is obvious, but with HIIT, you will be able to reuse the equipment
    you already have, and this will not mean an extra cost.
</p>
<h3>
    9. Kill the monotony
</h3>
<p>
    Coming back to the duration, being running at the same pace for 45 or 60
    minutes may not be the most exciting activity. If you live in a big city, you
    will not find many tracks close to your place with 45/60 minutes routes.
</p>
<p>
    Since the duration for HIIT is much shorter, this also gives you many more
    possibilities when combining the different routes.
</p>

<p>
    Related to the variations and the monotony, there are also many other
    variations that we may say in other articles. For example, you may practice
    HIIT while doing some trail or as we have seen in other sports.
</p>
<h2>
    10 Risk of injuries
</h2>
<p>
    Finalizing with another health topic, being running for 60 minutes every
    day on the road or any other hard surface may not be the most convenient
    way to keep your knees.
</p>
<p>
    I remember this was my main reason for switching to HIIT some 5-6 years
    ago.
</p>
<p>
    After 20-30 minutes low-intensity running, I had a strong pain in the left
    knee, and I had to stop running. After 3-4 times, I decided I had to reduce
    the duration of these exercises or just stop. I decided to continue but
    compensating the lower duration with a more active and high interval
    trainings. That’s how I started and ever since I did not have any problem.
</p>
<p>
    Every time we run our knees and other articulations may be subject to
    prolonged times of and a wrong way of running may lead to injuries. By
    reducing the duration of our training, we also reduce the risk of injuries
    and conserve intact our articulations.
</p>
<h2>
    What’s next
</h2>
<p>
    In conclusion, you have seen different advantages of practicing HIIT. It
    may sound challenging for you at the beginning, but I can assure you that
    this will not deceive you and will push your body to the next level.
</p>
<p>
    We have found what the different benefits in terms of time, fun, health, and
    performance are. As discussed in one of the points, trying is free, and you may start with a just 10-minute session
    to give it a
    try.
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[From performance to health, what HIIT can add to your daily routines]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="es"><title type="html">10 Beneficios del HIIT</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/10_beneficios_hiit" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 Beneficios del HIIT" /><published>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-11T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/10-beneficios-hiit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/10_beneficios_hiit"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introducción
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        En los últimos años, ha habido un auge en temas de deporte y salud. Cada vez buscamos más algunas alternativas o
        variaciones de los deportes más clásicos que van evolucionando a lo largo de los años. Una de las actividades
        que ha estado bastante de moda en los últimos años es el HIIT.
    </p>
</div>

<p>
    En este post hablaremos de cómo funciona el HIIT (High Intensity Interval Training) - Entrenamiento Interválico de Alta Intensidad y cómo puede
    ayudarte en tu día a día.
</p>
<p>
    Las diferentes ventajas que tiene el HIIT van desde la mera mejora del rendimiento hasta la mejora de la salud. Sin
    embargo, hay más que esto y el HIIT también incluye algunas ventajas para nuestro bienestar y el disfrute de
    nuestras actividades.


</p>
<p>
    Pero antes de comenzar a describir, en caso de que no lo sepas, ¿qué es el HITT y cómo funciona?


</p>
<p>
    En términos simples, HIIT es la combinación de lo siguiente
</p>
<ul>
    - Intervalos de alta intensidad
</ul>
<ul>
    - Intervalos de baja intensidad que se utilizan para recuperarse de la alta intensidad
</ul>
<p>
    Por intervalos de alta intensidad se entiende aquellos intervalos en los que la capacidad de frecuencia cardiaca es
    igual al menos al 80% de la frecuencia cardiaca máxima.
</p>
<p>
    La frecuencia de la intensidad alta y baja puede variar, y puede ir desde relaciones 2:1 o 1:2.
</p>
<p>
    Un ejemplo puede ser más claro si agregamos algunos números.
</p>
<p>
    Imaginemos un corredor que realiza los siguientes pasos:

</p>
<ul>
    1. Sprint de 60 segundos
</ul>
<ul>
    2. Trote de baja intensidad de 120 segundos
</ul>
<ul>
    3. Sprint de 60 segundos
</ul>
<ul>
    4. Trote de baja intensidad de 120 segundos
</ul>
</li>
<p>
    Y así puedes jugar con diferentes variaciones. Por ejemplo, sprints de 60 segundos y descanso de 60 segundos, etc.

</p>
<p>
    El objetivo de la sesión de HIIT es darlo todo y acabar agotado al final de la misma.

</p>
<p>
    Comenzar con HIIT también significa salir de tu zona de confort y puede ser un desafío para ti al principio. Sin
    embargo, ser progresista y leer los siguientes beneficios seguramente lo ayudará a pasar al siguiente nivel.


</p>
<h3>
    1. Falta de tiempo
</h3>
<p>
    Nos gustaría tener días de 48 horas, pero esto no es posible. Con HIIT puedes reducir tus sesiones a más de la
    mitad. De una sesión de baja intensidad de 60 minutos, puedes pasar a una sesión de HIIT de 15/20 minutos.


</p>
<p>
    Una sesión de 20 minutos será suficiente para completar tu actividad y objetivos diarios.


</p>
<p>
    En otras palabras, las sesiones habituales de 45 minutos que tienes pueden ser de solo 20 minutos. Los minutos que
    no uses los puedes usar para cualquier otra cosa.


</p>
<p>
    Aunque sea de menor duración, lo harás con una mayor sensación de plenitud y trabajo bien hecho por el trabajo que
    realiza tu cuerpo después del trabajo.


</p>
<p>
    Además, no hay necesidad de hacer estas sesiones todos los días. Como en cada sesión se añade mucho estrés a tus
    órganos y músculos, 3 o 4 sesiones de HITT serán más que suficientes para ti y tu cuerpo. Más adelante veremos el
    post-proceso.


</p>
<p>
    Este beneficio es un buen argumento para decirle a la gente que se queja de que no hace nada de ejercicio porque
    tiene demasiadas cosas que hacer y no tiene tiempo. La mayoría de nosotros debería poder tomar 20 minutos de otras
    tareas diarias.


</p>
<h3>
    2. Ponte en forma
</h3>
<p>
    Aunque el HIIT está más asociado al jogging, a esta técnica se le pueden aplicar muchos deportes y actividades. Esto
    significa que puede enriquecer su cartera de ejercicios y aumentar la diversión.


</p>
<h3>
    3. Multiples combinaciones
</h3>
<p>
    Aunque el HIIT está más asociado a correr, a esta técnica se le pueden aplicar muchos deportes y actividades. Esto
    significa que puede enriquecer su cartera de ejercicios y aumentar la diversión.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/diverse_hiit.jpg" alt="Cientos de maneras">
    <span class="caption text-muted">El HIIT no es exclusivo de trotar, y puedes experimentarlo de muchas maneras
</span>
</p>
<p>
    Algunas de las actividades más populares son:
</p>

<ul>
    <li>
        Natación
    </li>
    <li>
        Ciclismo
    </li>
    <li>
        Entrenamiento con pesast training
    </li>
    <li>
        Saltar a la comba
    </li>
    <li>
        Remo
    </li>
    <li>
        Burpees
    </li>
    <li>
        Bailar
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
</p>
<p>
    Al igual que ocurre con la nutrición, tener un conjunto diversificado de ejercicios te ayudará a no aburrirte y a
    abrir tu mente para practicar nuevos.


</p>
<h3>
    4. Masa muscular
</h3>
<p>
    Para los profesionales que compiten, es posible que haya escuchado diferentes opiniones sobre los diferentes
    ejercicios y la planificación. Algunos argumentan que al correr pueden perder parte de la masa muscular que han
    ganado.


</p>
<p>
    El beneficio del HIIT, ligado también a la duración, es que puedes conseguir lo siguiente:


</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Reducir la grasa corporal
    </li>
    <li>
        Mantener la masa muscular

    </li>
    <li>
        Aumentar la masa muscular en las piernas.

    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Otro ejemplo es si en las Olimpiadas o si echas un vistazo a los cuerpos de diferentes deportes.


</p>
<p>
    Si observas los cuerpos de los corredores de maratón o ciclistas de larga distancia, es posible que vea atletas muy
    delgados con poca grasa, pero también poca masa muscular, excepto en las piernas. La razón es que mientras se
    practican estos deportes de larga duración, las reservas de glucógeno se vacían y el cuerpo empieza a tomar energía
    de: grasas y lípidos.


</p>
<p>
    Por esa razón, HIIT es una solución win-win y la razón de ser la opción preferida por muchos atletas.


</p>
<h3>
    5. Metabolismo
</h3>
<p>
    El entrenamiento de intervalos de alta intensidad también se denomina refuerzo metabólico. El motivo es que
    practicar HIIT produce una aceleración considerable en el metabolismo de nuestro cuerpo. Pero ¿por qué es eso?
    Debido al trabajo que se realiza, nuestro cuerpo es empujado al siguiente nivel. Nuestro cuerpo es lo
    suficientemente inteligente y exige una mayor cantidad de oxígeno para proporcionar a nuestros órganos: corazón,
    pulmones, etc. Sin embargo, no es esa la única razón.


</p>
<p>
    Aparte de eso, hay que reponer algunos componentes que se rompieron en el ejercicio y la energía que hay que emplear
    para recuperar estas proteínas, tendones, etc., en la fase de recuperación es por lo que nuestro cuerpo sigue
    funcionando aunque estemos en el sofá.


</p>
<p>
    Este proceso dura alrededor de 48 horas y es por eso que durante este tiempo, nuestro cuerpo sigue quemando
    calorías. Esta es otra razón para tener que realizar esta actividad 3 o 4 veces por semana.


</p>
<h3>
    6. Mejor rendimiento
</h3>
<p>
    Dependiendo de la actividad, algunas partes de nuestro cuerpo se desarrollarán. Sin embargo, HIIT tiene un gran
    impacto en el rendimiento y es posible que vea mejoras en los siguientes factores:


</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Velocidad
    </li>
    <li>
        Agilidad
    </li>
    <li>
        Potencia y Energía
    </li>
    <li>
        Resistencia
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Si practicas HIIT habrás notado que tu rendimiento en otros deportes como la natación o el ciclismo también ha
    mejorado.


</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/hiit/cycling.jpg" alt="Useful for other sports">
    <span class="caption text-muted">El HIIT puede aumentar sus niveles de VO2 Max, lo que puede ser muy beneficioso para deportes como el ciclismo.
</span>
</p>
<p>
    Una característica común de estos deportes es la efectividad máxima del VO2. VO2 max mide la eficiencia con la que
    tu cuerpo utiliza el oxígeno mientras realizas tu actividad. Mayor VO2 Max mayor rendimiento. Hay una historia que
    se remonta a los tiempos en que se crearon los triatlones en 1970 y ¿quién ganaría? ¿Corredores, nadadores o
    ciclistas? Algunos dijeron que los ciclistas serían los ganadores porque en ese entonces Eddy Merckx tenía los
    niveles más altos de VO2.


</p>
<h2>
    7. Corazón
</h2>
<p>
    No todo debe ser diversión y rendimiento. Una de las características más importantes está relacionada con nuestra
    salud. Si sufres problemas de salud como presión alta, te alegrará saber que los corredores que practican HIIT se
    benefician de una salud cardíaca mucho mejor.


</p>
<p>
    Además, HIIT aumenta la cantidad de sangre que el corazón puede bombear.


</p>
<p>
    Por supuesto, si tienes algún problema de salud, otro consejo sería hacerte unos controles médicos antes de empezar
    a practicar esta técnica.


</p>
<h3>
    8. Coste
</h3>
<p>
    Comenzar con otros deportes y actividades significa aumentar la diversión. No obstante, en la mayoría de los casos
    invertir en diferentes artículos (bicicleta, mancuernas, esquís, gafas, etc.) Si ya estás haciendo jogging, no hay
    nada que tengas que comprar.


</p>
<p>
    Esto es obvio, pero con HIIT podrás reutilizar el equipo que ya tienes, y esto no supondrá un coste extra.


</p>
<h3>
    9. Mata la monotonía
</h3>
<p>
    Volviendo a la duración, correr al mismo ritmo durante 45 o 60 minutos puede no ser la actividad más emocionante. Si
    vives en una gran ciudad, no encontrarás muchas pistas cerca de tu casa con rutas de 45/60 minutos.


</p>
<p>
    Dado que la duración del HIIT es mucho más corta, esto también te da muchas más posibilidades a la hora de combinar
    las diferentes rutas.


</p>
<p>
    Relacionado con las variaciones y la monotonía, también hay muchas otras variaciones que podemos decir en otros
    artículos. Por ejemplo, puedes practicar HIIT mientras haces algún trail o como hemos visto en otros deportes.


</p>
<h2>
    10 Riesgo de lesiones
</h2>
<p>
    Finalizando con otro tema de salud, estar corriendo 60 minutos todos los días en la carretera o cualquier otra
    superficie dura puede no ser la forma más conveniente de mantener las rodillas.


</p>
<p>
    Recuerdo que esta fue mi razón principal para cambiarme a HIIT hace unos 5 o 6 años.


</p>
<p>
    Después de 20-30 minutos de carrera a baja intensidad, tuve un fuerte dolor en la rodilla izquierda y tuve que dejar
    de correr. Después de 3 o 4 veces, decidí que tenía que reducir la duración de estos ejercicios o simplemente parar.
    Decidí continuar pero compensando la menor duración con entrenamientos más activos e interválicos. Así empecé y
    desde entonces no he tenido ningún problema.


</p>
<p>
    Cada vez que corremos nuestras rodillas y otras articulaciones pueden estar sujetas a tiempos prolongados y una
    forma incorrecta de correr puede derivar en lesiones. Al reducir la duración de nuestro entrenamiento, también
    reducimos el riesgo de lesiones y conservamos intactas nuestras articulaciones.


</p>
<h2>
    ¿Qué viene ahora?
</h2>
<p>
    Para concluir, has visto diferentes ventajas de practicar HIIT. Puede sonar desafiante para ti al
    principio, pero puedo asegurarte que esto no te engañará y llevará tu cuerpo al siguiente nivel.

</p>
<p>
    Hemos observado diferentes beneficios en términos de tiempo, diversión, salud y rendimiento. Como se discutió en uno
    de
    los puntos, probar es gratis y puede comenzar con una sesión de solo 10 minutos para intentarlo.


</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Desde rendimiento a salud, que puede el HIIT añadir a tus rutinas]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/hiit/hiit.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="enn"><title type="html">Learn and Earn Crypto</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/28/learn_and_earn_crypto/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learn and Earn Crypto" /><published>2022-08-28T04:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-08-28T04:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/08/28/learn_and_earn_crypto</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/28/learn_and_earn_crypto/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        Some centuries ago, different organizations across Europe and Asia were
        accused of conspiracies and polemics. Mostly these accusations were
        provoked by the information that these sects or groups kept for themselves.
        or Myth or reality, what cannot be denied is that in the Middle Ages,
        knowledge was something considered hermetic and exclusive to certain groups
        that wisdom for them and the exclusive members of their circle.
    </p>
</div>
<p>
    Fortunately, things have changed in the last decades and in this era of
    information, we have more access to things we could not have imagined a few
    years ago. On the other hand, it may be shocking and paradoxical that in
    this era, we are less cultivated and informed.
</p>
<br>
<p align="center">
    <em>
        "If money is your hope for independence you will never have it. The only
        real security that a man will have in this world is a reserve of
        knowledge, experience, and ability."
    </em> -
    <strong>
        Henry Ford    </strong>

</p>
<br>
<p>
    Knowledge is enough motivation for most of us to learn about new topics,
    but apart what if I tell you that apart from learning interesting topics
    and state of the art technologies you can also get rewarded?
</p>
<p>
    As discussed in previous articles, the best investment you can make is
    learning. It’s undeniable the benefits that the continuous learning brings
    in the long term.
</p>
<p>
    Although, learning by itself is already a rewarding and motivating
    activity, some of use will also appreciate additional bonuses. Keeping us updated is important in the competitive world we all live in.
    Not just for now, but for future years.
    By reward, I don’t mean just the new information or benefits you get, but
    new tokens, coins, or discounts you may get.
</p>
<p>
    This post is not merely about getting free coins, but also new skills that
    you can get and apply in your professional world. Let’s dig deeper to see
    what these options are.
</p>
<br>
<h2>
    Learn to Earn Programs
</h2>
<p>
    The first group of this article is related to those programs where you
    learn the theory, or the basic concepts of a given blockchain or token. In
    the subsections below, you don’t just learn something new, but you also
    have the chance of getting rewarded with crypto currencies.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/learn_earn/coinbase.jpg" alt="Pioneer">
    <span class="caption text-muted">In the Learning Rewards Section you can see different articles, courses and quizzes</span>
</p>
<p>
    These are some of the most famous Learn to Earn programs out there, where
    you learn interesting new topics and you are rewarded in different manners.
</p>
<p>
    Please bear in mind that these courses do not have any requirements such as
    “deposit 10 to earn 20, etc.”. Apart from learning and reading/watching the
    information, the only other requirement is that in some cases you may need
    to verify and pass the KYC checks.
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Coinbase
</h3>
<p>
    Coinbase is sometimes criticized for different reasons such as
    business-related topics (dismissal of employees, business plan) or the
    trading fees. However, since they started in 2018, they have promoted
    different initiatives in the crypto community. One of the most famous ones
    is the Learning Rewards program, where users can earn different tokens. The
    process is quite easy and just watching a short video and answering some
    questions you can get some free tokens.
</p>
<p>
    There is no surprise here and you can exchange as soon as you receive. The
    rewards are not a big amount, but, lately, they tend to occur quite often.
    Regardless of the rewards, videos are nice to watch and very well done. In
    addition to these videos, you may also see different articles.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Coinbase Information</h5>
            One of the first ones to start with this initiative, Coinbase keeps offering these courses from time to time<br>
            <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/learn/tips-and-tutorials/how-to-earn-crypto-rewards">Coinbase Learning Rewards</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Binance
</h3>
<p>
    Binance is without any doubt, the largest crypto exchange in the world. In
    my opinion, the initially based Chinese exchange may be quite annoying with
    several daily notifications, but Changpeng Zhao’s organization have also
    several nice initiatives for their customers.
</p>
<p>
    Since 2022, they have followed what Coinbase started and offer some small
    rewards for watching some videos and answering different questions. There
    are several courses, and the rewards are quite small. However, it is nice
    to understand and be aware of new projects, and in addition to learning and
    getting new ideas, being rewarded for so.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Binance Information</h5>
            Binance offers several short courses about new altcoins and tradings<br>
            <a href="https://academy.binance.com/en/learn-and-earn">Binance Learn and Earn</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Cake DeFi
</h3>
<p>
    Cake DeFi is a quite new player in the Decentralized Finance sector and now
    quite known for many people. However, with their current solutions, it is
    likely that you will get hear from them more and more. They are a company
    based in Singapore specialized in passive income, being the main pillars of
    these platform the following s
</p>
<p>
    1. Liquidity mining: as opposed to centralized exchanges, in a DEX, liquidity
    is needed in order to enable trades between the different pairs. With
    liquidity mining you provide your crypto assets so other can use these to
    trade.
</p>
<p>
    2. Staking: Via the Proof of Stake protocol, you lock your tokens to protect
    the network., and you get rewarded with additional tokens
</p>
<p>
    3. Lending: The last strategy one is income generated from lending your coins
    to other DeFi participants.
</p>
<p>
    With the available courses, you can at the moment earn the following
    tokens.
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        DFI (DeFiChain) tokens
    </li>
    <li>
        BTC-DFI Tokens
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Both of them are allocated to Staking and Liquidity mining, but after you
    unfreeze them you can do whatever you want with the coins you got in the
    courses plus the ones you got from the freeze period.
</p>
<p>
    There is also a course coming soon related to Ethereum, where you will also
    learn something new and get rewarded.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Cake DeFi Information</h5>
            With short quizzes you can learn different Decentralized Finance and crypto topics while you have fun<br>
            <a href="https://app.cakedefi.com/learn">Cake DeFi Learn</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Revolut
</h3>
<p>
    Revolut is very good for many aspects such as banking, currency conversion,
    travelling and the super cool features of the app such as virtual cards or
    instant transfers. However, when it comes to their investment features such
    as purchasing stock or crypto, there are still some aspects that should be
    improved.
</p>
<p>
    That’s probably why in order to take off, Revolut has launched a Learn
    &amp; Earn Program related to Polkadot. Compared to other courses, the
    lessons are related to one of the most important blockchains and the
    amounts are also higher.
</p>
<p>
    In addition to the videos, you have also the option to see the glossary,
    where some important crypto and blockchain terms are explained.
</p>
<p>
    There is no referral program here and you will get those tokens for you.
    You decide if you want to sell them for fiat or exchange them the moment
    you receive them.

<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Revolut Information</h5>
            The purpose of the program is to learn about a specific cryptocurrency and familiarise with the world of crypto.
            <br>
            <a href="https://www.revolut.com/legal/crypto-learn-and-earn/">Revolut Learn & Earn Site</a>            <br>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h2>
    Technical Courses & Sites
</h2>
<p>
    Although the previous courses will reward you with direct tokens and the
    ones below will not, given the lack of technical skills that we will see in
    the future, the courses below may have a more relevant reward in upcoming
    years.
</p>
<p>
    Once we have focused described the most important courses related to
    business and blockchains, we can also get more technical and in this
    matter, there are also very good courses to add new skills.
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Uniswap
</h3>
<p>
    Uniswap, named as the name of the company that created it, is one of the most famous decentralized exchanges. Apart from the
    exchange and being an example of governance, Uniswap explains clearly very
    important topics related to DeFi.
</p>
<p>
    They offer some projects located in GitHub and the open-source interface
    for their protocol is available in GitHub.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/learn_earn/uniswap.jpg" alt="Building a great community of developers">
    <span class="Regardless of the background, you may find many resources for different topics"></span>
</p>
<p>
    On top of these resources and what you may swap or earn in the exchange,
    you can also build different apps that integrate with the protocol and get
    paid from their grant program.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Uniswap Information</h5>
            With the detailed documentation, you can learn about different topics and contribute to UniSwap in infinite ways.
            <br>
            <a href="https://uniswap.org/">Uniswap Site</a>            <br>
            <a href="https://docs.uniswap.org/">Documentation Uniswap</a>
            <br>
            <a href="https://github.com/Uniswap/interface">
                Uniswap Interface
            </a>

        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Ethernaut
</h3>
<p>
    Probably you have been hearing recently about the Ethereum Merge and the
    consequences that the fork may have not just for the Ethereum network but
    the whole crypto scene. Ethernaut is a war game played in an Ethereum
    Virtual Machine. developed by the OpenZeppelin, Ethernaut is a Web3
    application developed with Solidity, where you can also learn this
    programming language.
</p>
<p>
    The purpose of the game is both having fun and learning about Ethereum with
    different coding exercises at the same time you assimilate understand the
    Ethereum concepts with some practice.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Ethernaut Information</h5>
            Inpspired by other game             <a
                href="https://overthewire.org/"
        >
            overthewire.org
        </a>, each level of Ethernaut is a Smart Contract that you must hack to pass the level.<br>
            <a
                    href="https://ethernaut.openzeppelin.com/"
            >
                Visit Ethernaut
            </a><br>
            <a href="https://github.com/OpenZeppelin/ethernaut">
                Visit GitHub Ethernaut
            </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>
    Crypto Zombies
</h3>
<p>
    Similar to Ethernaut, Crypto Zombies is a game where you can build a Zombie
    Factory to build your personal army composed of unique zombies.
</p>
<p>
    Once you have created the zombies, the fun is not over. It’s now where you
    can fight other learners’ armies. Furthermore, you also get unique
    collectibles like other games. As with Ethernaut, you will also learn
    blockchain specific topics such as ERC721, Web3 or zkSync, making this
    website quite complete in order to have basic knowledge about dApp
    creation.
</p>

<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Crypto Zombies Information</h5>
            With Crypto Zombies, the player can learn every aspect of how blockchains works while having fun.
        <br>
            <a href="https://cryptozombies.io/">
            Visit Crypto Zombies
        </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<br>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>
    As with many things in life, the best learning is practicing. Therefore,
    simple, or complex, why don’t start creating your own project once you know
    the basics? We are privileged to live in an era where information is
    accessible for everyone with infinite level of resources.
</p>
<p>
    As you may see from the links, the technical courses may require more time,
    so it would be better to start learning the basic concepts from the first websites.
</p>
<p>
    With new technologies and the expected growth, these technologies will
    eliminate several jobs, but there will a job shortage and companies not
    able to hire new talent because there are too few professionals with the
    required skills. One of them may be blockchain and everything that
    surrounds this industry.
</p>
<br>
<p align="center">

    <em>
        "Live as if you were to die tomorrow. Learn as if you were to live
        forever.”
    </em>
    — <strong>Mahatma Gandhi</strong>
</p>
<br>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn about crypto and get rewarded for your knowledge]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/learn_earn/learn_earn.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/learn_earn/learn_earn.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>