<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-07-31T11:32:45+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Life of a Modern Man</title><subtitle>Advising in Lifestyle and Finance</subtitle><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><entry><title type="html">Affordable Watches Loved by Collectors</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/07/31/affordable_watches_loved_collectors/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Affordable Watches Loved by Collectors" /><published>2022-07-31T05:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-31T05:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/07/31/affordable_watches_loved_collectors</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/07/31/affordable_watches_loved_collectors/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        It’s true that some of the most wanted and known watches will be out of
        budget for most of us. We have seen that the prices of luxury watches have
        gone to the roof in the last years. They have been mainly used for
        investment, hedging and protection against inflation, similar to what’s
        done with other alternative assets. That’s main reason for having seen the
        prices in primary and secondary markets skyrocketed. Although even if it
        said that watches are an investment on many occasions, in most cases this
        will not be true and even if you are an experienced professional, it would
        not be advisable to follow these steps.
    </p>
</div>
<p>
    Anyway, the topic of this article is not to discuss about luxury articles
    or investments, but the opposite. In this post, the focus is to show some
    affordable but good-looking watches that will look like a luxury watch and
    will not disappoint any watch collector.
</p>
</p>
</p>
<h2>
    1. Orient Bambino
</h2>
<p>
    We start the list with a fine piece coming from Japan. It may be a
    non-famous brand for some, but Orient belongs to the Seiko group
</p>
<p>
    The Orient Bambino is possibly one of the best affordable automatic dress
    watches available on the market today. A piece appreciated even by the most
    demanding collectors, despite not being a high value jewel.
</p>
<p>
    Essentially, we are dealing in this case with a vintage-style watch with a
    clean and traditional design equipped with a precise mechanism, whose
    quality is endorsed by Orient, a Japanese watch brand whose tradition dates
    back to 1950, although it currently belongs to Seiko, another guarantee of
    quality.
</p>
<p>
    The best thing about the Orient Bambino is that they move in a fairly
    affordable price range, so they are an excellent starting point for those
    who want to start collecting watches without spending a fortune, but who
    also want to be recognized among others. the connoisseurs in watches.
</p>
<p>
    Due to the success and the sales of the Bambino, there are around 10
    version of this watch. If I had to choose one, my favorite one will be the
    one with the blue dial.
</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/affordable_watches/orient_bambino.jpeg" alt="Classic and elegant">
    <span class="caption text-muted">If you are starting with your collection, the Orient Bambino will be ideal as a dress watch </span>
</p>
<p>
    From the first glance you will be fascinated by the contrast of the dial of
    this Orient Bambino v4 fac08004d model. The dial is characterized by an
    ocean blue color in the central part that gradually intensifies until it
    reaches the edges, where it reaches a contrasting black.
</p>
<p>
    The strap is black and made of high-quality leather, a feature that makes
    it extremely comfortable and easy to wear.
</p>
<p>
    The diameter of the case is 42.5 mm, ideal for any type of wrist, both
    small and large, the case has a perfectly round shape that is very
    reminiscent of vintage watches.
</p>
<p>
    All bambino versions are water-resistant up to 30 meters. However, since it
    is a dress watch and because of the leather strap, swimming with it will
    not be recommendable.
</p>
<p>
    If you are looking for a classic watch, the best value for money out there
    may be the Bambino and one of their versions.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Orient Bambino Information</h5>
            Watch Type: <Strong>Dress-watch </Strong></br>
            Price Range: <Strong>150 $</Strong></br>
            Site:
            <a
                    href="https://orient-watch.com/"
            >
                Orient Watch
            </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
</p>
</p>

<h2>
    2. Seiko Save the Ocean Series
</h2>
<p>
    Since we have introduced one Orient model, there is no doubt we would be
    also taking about Seiko. If we are presenting affordable and quality
    watches, there is no doubt that Seiko must be on the list. As it would be
    impossible to include the different models that could be included in this
    list, we have decided to include a limited edition of Seiko, which not be
    known to some.
</p>
<p>
    The new Seiko Prospex Save the Ocean are another example of how Seiko
    continues to dive deeper and deeper into its passion for underwater
    watchmaking, of which we have already seen some examples). Back in 2018, at
    Baselworld, the Japanese manufacturer announced Fabien Cousteau as the new
    ambassador, grandson of the legendary Jacques Cousteau, the French
    biologist and oceanographer who taught us to love the oceans.
</p>
<p>
    If you have realized about the name, you may guess that here we are talking
    about a watch related to the sea. When it comes to orology, this is of
    course related to diver watches, which also means that they are certified.
</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/affordable_watches/seiko_ocean.jpeg" alt="Ideal for Summer">
    <span class="caption text-muted">The Save the Ocean models are ideal for wearing on the beach (or pool)</span>
</p>
<p>
    There are so many unique models in this limited edition and for that reason
    it is not possible to focus on all of them. That’s why I will focus on my
    favorite version of this edition is the Seiko Save the Ocean Black Series.
    Since they a covered by black PVC, they have a more elegant look
</p>
<p>
    We have already said that there are different models, colors, and type of
    watches: Turtle, Samurai and these models will adapt to your wrist.
    Therefore, in this collection you will find multiple versatile options for
    your collection.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Seiko Save the Ocean</h5>
            Watch Type: <Strong>Diver</Strong></br>
            Price Range: <Strong>500 $</Strong></br>
            Site:
            <a
                    href="https://www.seikowatches.com/es-es/products/prospex/special/keepgoingforward/savetheocean"
            >
                Seiko Save The Ocean
            </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
</p>
</p>
<h2>
</h2>
<h2>
    3. G-Shock GA-2100
</h2>
<p>
    We end our trip to Japan, with a low-cost but high-quality company producer
    Casio. In the 80s, a small team of engineers from Casio led by Ibe Kikuo
</p>
<p>
    started working a new project. Due to the fragility and delicacy of the
    watches at that time, their goal was to create an indestructible watch that
    would be valid for different occasions. One of them was the one related to
    those workers in the industry.
</p>
<p>
    With not very success at the start, mainly because the sales on the home
    country did not bring the attention of the Japanese, it started
    surprisingly to catch the eye of Americans and Europeans. It has now become
    one of the watches that almost every collector and part of a niche-market.
</p>

<p>
    Ever since, they have brought different breakthroughs to the watch
    industry. From solar energy to Bluetooth connectivity, it has always
    remained at the forefront of technology, design, and functionality,
    accompanying its evolution.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/affordable_watches/casioak.jpeg" alt="Future Classic">
    <span class="caption text-muted">The same that happened with other Casio models, there is no doubt that the GA-2100 will become a classic</span>
</p>
<p>
    G-Shock has created different iconic watches over the years. One of the most
    recent ones, Nicknamed the CasioOak for having a similar - but much more
    affordable - design (octogonal shape too) to the one of the Royal Oak from the Audemars Piguet,
    the G-Shock was an instant hit when it was released in 2020.
</p>
<p>
    The G-Shock GA-2100 is not as rough as other G-Shock models. It’s quite thin. For instance:
    example: at 11.8mm, it's the thinnest G-Shock currently makes. It's also a
    predominantly analog piece, with two hands and a physical day indicator. On
    the other hand, it also has a number of digital complications, including a
    timer, stopwatch, world time, calendar, and LED light. The most iconic
    version is the total black CasioOak, and that my seem that it is not easy
    to read, this is not true once you try it.
</p>
<p>
    In the past, one of the characteristics for which G-Shock had some
    detractors, is that their design was not the most sophisticated and elegant
    one. However, with the GA-2100, this is not an argument they may use. The
    GA-2100 model combines both elegance and robustness, making it an
    indestructible yet beautiful piece.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>G-Shock GA-2100 Information</h5>
            Watch Type: <Strong>Sports watch</Strong></br>
            Price Range: <Strong>100 $</Strong></br>
            Site:
            <a
                    href="https://de.casio-shop.eu/p/ga-2100-1a1er/"
            >
                Casio
            </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
</p>
</p>
<h2>
    4. Tissot PRX
</h2>
<p>
    The decades of 70s and 80s were good decades for music lovers with special
    mention to disco music. In 1978, the first Superman was released in the
    cinemas and Argentina – without Maradona- won their first football world
    cup home. It was also in 1978 when the Swiss manufacturer Tissot released
    the PRX.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/affordable_watches/tissot.jpeg" alt="A Blast from the Past">
    <span class="caption text-muted">Tissot is making very interesting products in the last years and the PRX is probably the most relevant surprise</span>
</p>
<p>
    The PRX had an integrated steel bracelet, a barrel-shaped case which evoked
    a classic and clean design. In 2021, Tissot decided to reedit this model
    and generated very good reviews and good opinions.
</p>
<p>
    The name maybe a bit unknown for the users, but they are synonyms of:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        P: Precise
    </li>
    <li>
        R: Robust
    </li>
    <li>
        X: It’s a reference to the water resistance of 10 (X) bars.
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    The reedition of this watch was an instant hit. It can be used as both
    dress or sports watch, and it also has some similarities with the Audemars
    Piguet Royal Oak or the Vacheron Constantin Overseas. Because of the good
    feedback, Tissot had also the idea of having new versions in 2022, like the
    chronographer, which is slightly bigger
</p>
<p>
    Either for a classic version or one of the latest versions, you will get a
    polyvalent and elegant watch that will not disappoint.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Tissot PRX Information</h5>
            Watch Type: <Strong>Sports watch</Strong></br>
            Price Range: <Strong>700 $</Strong></br>
            Site:
            <a
                    href="https://www.tissotwatches.com/en-en/tissot-prx.html"
            >
                Tissot
            </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
</p>
</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>
    We have seen watches from different types: sport, dress, or a combination of both. They have been
    selected taking into account the quality, design and affordable. If you are
    interested on some luxury watches, there is a link to some classic watches
    in this <a href="https://mrfreire.net/2022/03/21/watches-for-a-lifetime/">
    article</a> too, but these will also excellent and very good looking in your wrist. In following weeks, we will try
    to show other affordable watches that will also grab the attention of many watch lovers.
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Lifestyle" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Different fine pieces that can increase the quality of your collection]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/affordable_watches/affordable_watches.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/affordable_watches/affordable_watches.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">9 Products with High Protein Content</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/07/10/products_8_proteins/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="9 Products with High Protein Content" /><published>2022-07-10T05:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-10T05:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/07/10/products_8_proteins</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/07/10/products_8_proteins/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        Together with fat and carbohydrates, proteins are part of the 3
        macronutrients that are essential for our body. In this article, we will
        analyze why they are so important for a healthy lifestyle and some examples
        of how to integrate them effortlessly into our meals.
    </p>
    <p>
        Proteins are built from amino acids and are the main components of all
        cells in the body. While human beings can produce some proteins internally,
        others must be obtained through the consumption of some aliments and foods.
    </p>
</div>
    <p>
        When you hear about diets, some people blame carbohydrates and fat, but
        never the third macronutrient. The reason is that our body is able to store
        fat and carbohydrates. However, it is not possible to store proteins.
        That’s why it’s important to keep a diet that is rich in protein (either
        protein or vegetable).
    </p>
    <p>
        Our body is not just composed of one unique protein, but we have many types
        that have a specific role. Some of these functions are related to
        transport, defense, or structure. Without going into detail, the first
        question you would be asking yourself is how you can get proteins and the
        ideal meals for this.
    </p>
    <p>
        When it comes to products, it’s likely that you may have heard about whey
        protein on more than one occasion. It is a product, which is made up as the
        main element of the proteins that are extracted from the whey of milk, and
        that can provide interesting benefits to our health. For this reason, it is
        widely used as a dietary supplement, especially indicated for practicing
        sports. However, having this product everyday – even with different flavors
        – may be a bit boring after several weeks.
    </p>
    <p>
        For this simple reason, this article collects other products that may help
        in order to achieve a diversifying and funny diet, from complete natural
        products.
    </p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
    <h2>
        Quark
    </h2>
    <p>
        Quark is quite trendy recently in several countries and you may see with
        many flavors. Quark is a type of cheese obtained from the rennet of milk in
        which proteins are concentrated due to the fact that the largest aqueous
        portion or whey is separated from the milk after its acidification.
    </p>
    <p>
        Their protein content is variable, being able to find around 10 to 20% in
        them. One of the biggest advantages is that quark It is a source of casein,
        a protein of high biological value that our body can make the most of.
    </p>
    <h2>
        Greek yoghurt
    </h2>
    <p>
        Although the one you may find in your supermarket. may not have many things
        with the original Yoghurt from Greece, in both cases the content of
        proteins will give a boost to your daily intake.
    </p>
    <p>
        A 6-ounce serving of Greek yogurt provides you with 15 to 20 grams of
        protein, significant amounts of potassium, calcium, vitamin B-12 and B-6,
        and magnesium. It has low levels of sodium and cholesterol. Furthermore, it
        does not include too many carbohydrates, compared to the “normal” youghurt.
    </p>
    <h2>
        Skyr
    </h2>
    <p>
        Between cheese and yoghurt, we have the next product coming from a small
        island in the North. Skyr is a dairy product of Icelandic origin that has
        been gaining prominence for its health benefits. Although many classify it
        as a yogurt, it is actually a hybrid between it and a fresh cream cheese
        since its texture and flavor fall somewhere between the two.
    </p>
    <p>
        Skyr is usually made from skimmed milk, from which cream or cream has been
        removed.
    </p>
    <p>
        Because of this ancient historic process, Skyr is low in fat, but it keeps
        the milk, which is why it has big content on protein, vitamins, and
        minerals.
    </p>
    <h2>
        Eggs
    </h2>
    <p>
        Criticized by many not many years ago, eggs are one of the most common
        products. Apart from the big number of proteins, they are known for having
        a good quality due to the high proportion of amino acids.
    </p>
    <p>
        Furthermore, when it comes to combining them, eggs offer a multitude of
        gastronomic possibilities thanks to their versatility, easiness to prepare
        and technical properties. You can have them prepared in various ways such
        as fried, baked, boiled, or even used in some desserts. Obviously, if fried
        or in desserts (think of French eclairs or the Portuguese Molotof pudding
        or French eclairs), they will not be very healthy either. However, just a
        simple omelet (including also Spanish omelet) can be a good boost of
        proteins in your meals. If you add for example tuna, you will be almost
        covered for the day.
    </p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/proteins/eggs.jpg" alt="Versatile and Complete">
    <span class="caption text-muted">Very simple to cook (or part of more sophisticated recipes), eggs are one of the most complete sources of proteins</span>
</p>
    <h2>
        Cod
    </h2>
    <p>
        In general, all fish and meat have a high proportion of protein in their
        composition. Nonetheless, compared to other fish such as salmon, cod stands
        out above other varieties of fish, since it has a very low amount of fat,
        which is an advantage regarding the proportion of protein compared to the
        rest of the macronutrients.
    </p>
    <p>
        Despite not being one of the most famous fish by the general public, the
        truth is that cod offers multiple options in the kitchen to satisfy all
        kinds of palates. In each country or region, you will see cooked in
        complete different ways.
    </p>
    <h2>
        Peanuts
    </h2>
    <p>
        Although surprising for some, nuts are two food groups that offer variable
        amounts of protein and can be very helpful in a vegetarian diet to meet the
        dietary needs of this macronutrient in the diet. Some examples are almonds
        or pistachios.
    </p>
    <p>
        This also happens with peanuts, a legume that, due to its appearance and
        form of consumption, is often confused with a nut. Peanuts offer
        interesting amounts of protein in the diet, whether consumed raw or with
        the classic peanut butter that many are passionate about. Here are some
        fantastic recipes with peanuts. One of the most popular ones is the peanut
        butter, which you can combine with many meals.
    </p>
    <p>
        The disadvantage is that they may be too caloric or contain too much salt,
        but just taking a bunch of them as a little snack will not harm anyone.
    </p>
    <h2>
        Oatmeal
    </h2>
    <p>
        Oatmeal is one of the most nutritious, versatile, and healthy cereals.
        Hence, more and more people are betting on incorporating it into their
        daily diet, mainly for breakfast.
    </p>
    <p>
        Oatmeal can boast of being one of the cereals with the highest protein
        content. We can obtain a protein of high biological value, in combination
        with foods such as milk or legumes.
    </p>
    <p>
        Its richness in protein (12 grams per 100 grams) and mostly complex
        carbohydrates (60 grams per 100), makes this cereal an ideal food for
        athletes. The disadvantage is that it may not be very tasty. For that
        reason, one solution is incorporating it into shakes.
    </p>
    <h2>
        Lupins
    </h2>
    <p>
        If you take care of your health, most of aforementioned products may be
        known to you.
    </p>
    <p>
        I never thought that the last one would be considered a high source of
        protein and it may be good for some of you to know. Lupins are similar to
        corn and eaten as snack. In some countries they may be more popular. They
        are legumes and are perfect to add proteins to vegetarian diets.
    </p>
    <p>
        It may not be very famous because it was always marginalized and linked to
        poverty.
    </p>
    <p>
        Nevertheless, their properties and some research about them have given them
        a more notorious role. The extraordinary properties of lupins have made
        this product popular, which is good news, since it is an inexpensive
        product, very healthy.
    </p>
    <p>
        Some of the most important attributes of this aliment is that they contain
        a high source of protein (they contain 40%). They are also. Ideal for
        diets. Its high fiber content (34%), low levels of fat (less than 6%) and
        antioxidants.
    </p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/proteins/algae.jpg" alt="The future of proteins">
    <span class="caption text-muted">Microalgae can be an interesting product to consider with the growth of population and lack of resources in the years to come.</span>
</p>
    <h2>
        Microalgae
    </h2>
    <p>
        The last one is more a product to be considered for the future and the
        scarcity of some resources, including the increase of population in the
        current century.
    </p>
    <p>
        Several genera of microalgae are a valuable source of protein that compete
        favorably in quantity and quality with traditional products such as eggs,
        soy, or fish. In addition, they have the ability to synthesize all 20 amino
        acids and to be a rare source of essential amino acids.
    </p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
    <h2>
        Conclusion
    </h2>
    <p>
        We have seen different ways of having proteins in our daily diet. As we
        have seen, they have different advantages that will be beneficial for our
        health.
    </p>
    <p>
        They are effective for weight loss. Besides, proteins help the development
        of muscles and improves recovery, thereby contributing to the increase in
        their strength.
    </p>
    <p>
        reducing body fat while maintaining muscle, a goal that is often very
        difficult to achieve through exercise or diet alone.
    </p>
    <p>
        Not just related to aesthetics or sport, beneficial health effects. Many
        studies have concluded that the supplement with Whey protein can be a great
        help to combat certain diseases and to have a better general state of
        health.
    </p>
    <p>
        Having said this, it’s now your turn to try the different options or even
        find new sources of protein. This also does not mean that you should forget
        about the other 2 macronutrients because they are also essential for a
        correct functioning of our body.
    </p>
    <br>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[9 Products to add to your meals to boost your daily protein intake]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/proteins/proteins.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/proteins/proteins.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Handle Stress</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/18/how_to_handle_stress/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Handle Stress" /><published>2022-06-18T14:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-06-18T14:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/18/how_to_handle_stress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/18/how_to_handle_stress/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    <p>
        While our life is easier compared to some years ago in many aspects, the
        first world has also led to new trends, problems, or even diseases.
    </p>
    <p>
        Unknown or ignored in the past in the past, the importance of our mental
        health is taking the attention it deserves. We need to understand that
        there are few important things that our mind and body. Not taking care of
        it, may lead to several issues in our behavior, thinking or mood.
</div>
    </p>
    <p>
        Stress can be characterized as a response to any occasion which is seen,
        deliberately or unknowingly, as a danger to our safety or happiness. Stress
        which we experience as unmanageable can be detected as injury by our
        sensory system and become part of ourselves, damaging our body
    </p>
    <p>
        Here are some of my tricks to make sure that we fight back and defeat our
        worst fears and the general stress from our life.
    </p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
    <h3>
        1. HIIT
    </h3>
    <p>
        Low intensity training may be boring and will not cause much an impact once
        done. However, if we switch to high intensity interval training, in just
        20-minute sessions we will not just achieve more than in the low-paced
        session, but it will also help generate more hormones.
    </p>
    <p>
        One of these hormones involved in the process is cortisol. Cortisol is
        known to handle stress
    </p>
    <p>
        Therefore, if you are changing to go to the next level when it comes to
        your workout, this may also help reduce the stress.
    </p>
    <p>
        As with anything, everything in excess is bad. Therefore, too much workout
        will also not be the best option for de-stressing, because it will also
        have negative impact in our cortisol levels, being these too high.
    </p>
    <h3>
        2. Meditate
    </h3>
    <p>
        Meditation can provide you with a feeling of peace, harmony, and quietness.
        This process can help both your general wellbeing. You may use the
        mediation to relax and focus all the activity on fighting the stress. Not
        just that but being an expert on this technique can help you stay focused
        and keeping your inner peace. This means that, like sports, the benefits
        don’t end once you stop meditating, but in upcoming stressful environments
        and situations too.
    </p>
    <h3>
        3. Cook some pasta
    </h3>
    <p>
        When it comes to stress, it is also known that some people like cooking to
        disconnect from the world. Apart from that
    </p>
    <p>
        Eating complex carbohydrates may be not the best idea if you are trying to
        lose weight and cut additional calories. However, if you are stressed, why
        not having your favorite recipe of Your favorite Rigatoni Bolognese or
        spaghetti amatriciana after a nice workout session? It’s been
        scientifically proved that eating pasta can increase the serotonin levels,
        which amongst many tasks, it helps regulate anxiety, mood, and happiness.
    </p>
    <p>
        On the other hand, you should not abuse of too many carbs. When it comes to
        food, it must be important to say that ultra-processed food and sugar will
        have a negative impact. Therefore, it is also good to keep our diet as
        healthy as possible. It has a big impact in both our body and mental
        health.
    </p>
    <h3>
        4. Dress <strike>up</strike> down
    </h3>
    <p>
        Nature is not something in the environment, but it’s something that we can
        carry with ourselves. That’s why it’s important to choose the correct
        clothes when starting the day. For example, if you want to reduce
        eagerness, the best way after having your morning shower is selecting
        carefully natural clothes (linen, cotton, etc.) that will create a relaxed
        outfit. If you are stressed, dressing up with tight and elegant clothes may
        not be the best choice. Having a comfier garment on you will help you have
        a more easygoing lifestyle.
    </p>
    <h3>
        5. Explore nature
    </h3>
    <p>
        It’s said that people on villages are much happier than those living in big
        cities with all the traffic, pollution, and noise. It may be easier for
        some and more difficult for other. Nonetheless, one suggestion for those
        living in big cities is to try to escape for some days or do some
        excursions to the beach, lakes, or mountains.
    </p>
    <p>
        Especially these ones may be the best choice because researchers have
        proved that since air in high altitude is charged with negative ions (atoms
        that have lost electrons), these molecules help hikers relax and forget
        about their problems.
    </p>
    <h3>
        6. Sleep, Sleep &amp; Repeat
    </h3>
    <p>
        The function of sleeping has many processes behind that helps repair our
        brain and bodies. We all would like to have more time and we often tend to
        sacrifice our sleeping time in order to get many more things done in the
        day. However, with this are generating debt that we will pay the days
        after.
    </p>
    <p>
        Sleeping does not just make sure that we are more productive the day after,
        but it helps our whole body to recover and handle the stress accordingly
    </p>
    <p>
        It’s a vicious circle. Stress leads to insomnia and insomnia leads to more
        stress.
    </p>
    <h3>
        7. Switch it off
    </h3>
    <p>
        Having multiple devices with thousands of notifications per day is not the
        best way to stay focused and in good mood. Apart from the constant
        distractions, some of these messages and pop ups will create negative
        feelings (war, crisis, hunger, etc.) and increase the level of stress
        inside our bodies.
    </p>
    <p>
        For that reason, it is a good idea to keep the number of apps in our phone
        as reduced as possible and have some focus times defined in our day.
    </p>
    <p>
        Another piece of advice is that once the workday or week are over, just
        toggle off the mailbox from your phone and hide the work laptop somewhere
        else. Even if it would seem that the world will collapse if you do so, try
        also to minimize the usage of your mobile phone to just those moments that
        really required.
    </p>
    <h3>
        8. Coffee
    </h3>
    <p>
        This one may be very obvious, but once we get into this habit is not easy
        to stop. We have discussed what the negative consequences of not sleeping
        are. The day after we need some energy, and the most accessible drug is a
        coffee shot. Since it seems to wake us up, we try one after another and
        some minutes later we are active, but our stress levels have also gone
        quite up. Cutting drastically coffee may be suicidal for some people.
        Therefore, a better idea may be to cut it progressively and replace it for
        healthier drinks such as green, matcha, black, and red tea. These infusions
        have great benefits when it comes to sleep quality, anxiety, and management
        of hormones
    </p>
    <h3>
        9. Eat more fruit
    </h3>
    <p>
        Either in solid state or in form of shakes and juices, fruit is very
        important and has a big impact on our bodies. Not just in our bodies or
        diet, fruits contain big amounts of different vitamins – for instance C and
        D-, that help us surpassing the stress threshold level. Therefore, these
        products can be a good booster to our anti-stress protection.
    </p>
    <p>
        If for some reason, you think you will not reach the needed vitamin levels,
        having some supplements will also help us achieve our goals.
    </p>
    <h3>
        10. Breathing Exercises
    </h3>
    <p>
        This one can be a technique that is used just when we are about to blow up or collapse.
        The trick in those tense situations is to handle our breathing in a good,
        consistent way with an efficient technique.
    </p>
    <p>
        You need to be as comfortable as you can and try to evade your mind and
        focus just on controlling your breathing. For example, put attention to the
        effect of inspiring through the nose and expiring through the moth.
        Counting the process will also help if you want to focus just on this
        activity as much as you can.
    </p>
    <h3>
        11. Spend time with animals
    </h3>
    <p>
        As with nature, spending time with animals will let us avoid our current
        work and responsibilities, with a more easygoing approach to life. The make
        us more aware of what the important aspects of life are.
    </p>
    <p>
        Furthermore, it has been confirmed that being in contact with animals such
        as dogs or cats activate the oxytocin hormone, which regulates the stress
        and comfort.
    </p>
    <h3>
        12. Read a novel
    </h3>
    <p>
        When there are many topics going through your mind, what I do is just
        trying to disconnect and focusing on only single topic. The easiest way to
        do so is taking the favorite book from the shelf or your book eReader.
        Although it is said that music may be a better way to disconnect it has
        been demonstrated with multiple researchs that reading a science or
        adventure story helps us totally disconnect from our daily tasks immersing
        ourselves in the story. In any case, you can leave the music for your HIIT
        session.
    </p>
    <h3>
        13. Switch on the PS4
    </h3>
    <p>
        In the case a book is not enough for you to evade the reality and manage
        the anxiety, a more active solution would be going to your computer or vide
        console and playing an adventure or any other type of game.
    </p>
    <p>
        As it occurs when reading, videogames help us distract ourselves with the
        preferred games. Videogames are engaging, fun and at the same time they are
        somehow challenging, getting some rewards. At the same time, as eating
        pasta, they increase our serotonin levels, having a positive impact on our
        well-being and mood.
    </p>
    <h3>
        14. Massage session
    </h3>
    <p>
        Massages can be a great complement to an exercise and apart from the
        muscular regeneration benefits, they also have benefits when it comes to
        anti-stress techniques.
    </p>
    <p>
        They help reduce the heart rate, blood pressure and overall improving our
        sleep quality and mental health, giving a boost to our well-being. Having
        just a 15–30-minute session can be a shot of good emotions and feelings.
    </p>
    <h3>
        15. Clean your body
    </h3>
    <p>
        To conclude the list, cleaning your body and face might me a good activity
        to increase our mood and relaxation levels. You may start exfoliating your
        face, continuing with a long bath with bath salts and candles and putting a
        face or ice will probably the best idea after a stressful working day.
    </p>
    <p>
        After the whole process you will leave the bathroom totally rejuvenated –
        and not just for your skin -.
    </p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
    <h2>
        Next steps
    </h2>
    <p>
        These are some tricks that may help you in your daily tasks and stressful
        activities. There may situations where you are about to explode. For these times, I encourage to remember these suggestions and apply them to you.
        </p>
<p>
        However, remember that like almost everything, practice makes
        the master. Therefore, why not putting these suggestions to work?
    </p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[15 tricks to help you managing your stress, mental health and wellbeing]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/stress/stress.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/stress/stress.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Blockchain Layers Explained</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/03/blockchain_layers_explained/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blockchain Layers Explained" /><published>2022-06-03T14:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-06-03T14:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/03/blockchain_layers_explained</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/03/blockchain_layers_explained/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    If you have been in the crypto or blockchain scene for some time, you may
    be familiar with the different layers of the blockchain, their functions,
    and how they interact one with another. However, if you are new, you may
    hear terms such as L1 or L2 and you may ask yourself what these words are.
    Don’t worry about this.
</div>
<p>
    In this article we explain not just the different layers but also the
    importance of each of it. It’s also important to note what they mean and
    why some tokens may be correlated because they are part of the same layer.
</p>
<p>
    As it occurs with the OSI and the Internet Protocol (TCP/IP) models, we
    also have different layers in blockchains.
    The different OSI layers are: Physical, Data Link, Network, Transport,
    Session, Presentation, and Application.
    The ones of the Interest Protocol are just 4: Link, Internet, Transport,
    Application. A similar structure occurs in the Blockchains.
</p>
<p>
    We can distinguish 4 different Blockchain layers, where each one has a
    specific purpose. Each layer is essential and has some defined functions
    and roles. They start with Layer 0 and the last one is Layer 3. In order to
    see the different features, it’s better to see this with some examples.
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
    Layer 0
</h2>
<p>
    This protocol is where everything starts and the bottom of the different
    blockchain protocols that we see later. It’s like the foundations of the
    building where the different infrastructure, hardware and internet are
    provided. Although, the other layers would be useless without this initial
    layer, it’s also the layer that cannot be seen and sometimes ignored.
</p>
<p>
    They allow interconnectivity and integration between traditional and
    blockchain network.
</p>
<p>
    As mentioned, this is where everything starts. Therefore, they allow other
    blockchains be built upon them and also that different blockchains are
    operable between them. In other words, the chains that are created on the
    layers above are interoperable and compatible thanks to the L0 protocols.
</p>
<p>
    For these characteristics they can be seen as the data transfer layer of
    the OSI model. Without this one, Bitcoin or Ethereum would not be able to
    run. Basically, their objective is to interconnect different chains between
    L1 protocols.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <p>
            <h5>L0 Example</h5>
            <h5>PolkaDot: Web3.0 Interoperability</h5>
            <small> The most famous example is probably PolkaDot. The goal of the protocol is
                like the one of a bridge between different L1 blockchains. It allows cross-blockchain transfers of any
                sort of data or asset, not just
                tokens. Connecting to Polkadot offers users the potential to interoperate
                with a wide form of blockchains in the Polkadot network.<br>
                <a href="https://polkadot.network/">
                    Additional information
                </a>
            </small>
            </p>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
    Layer 1
</h2>
<p>
    Layer 1 blockchains are probably the most famous ones for most of us. They
    are also known as public chains because they have their own structure,
    encryption, algorithms, technology and mechanisms. These are blockchains
    that are used to process transactions on their own blockchain and have
    different utilities.
</p>
<p>
    This protocol consists of the following sublayers: Data layer, Network
    layer, Consensus layer and Activating layer
</p>
<p>
    Since the transactions need to be processed and validated, the famous
    Consensus Mechanism (PoW, PoS, etc.) is also inherent to this layer.
    However, there are also other technical aspects involved such as the block
    time, the different rules and the dispute resolution. In this layer, we
    also see different limitations such as scaling.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="mx-auto d-block" src="/img/posts/blockchain_layers/algorand.png" alt="Sustainable and scalable">
    <span class="caption text-muted">Algorand is probably one of the most sustainable blockchain due to the technology and consensus mechanism</span>
</p>
<p>
    The goal of Layer 1 blockchains is to achieve the following 3
    characteristics:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Decentralization
    </li>
    <li>
        Security
    </li>
    <li>
        Scalability
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    There is a famous term called the Blockchain Trilemma, which says basically
    that basic chains can just achieve 2 out of 3.
</p>
<p>
    In order to achieve the first 2, scalability is sacrificed and left for
    later. It’s here where Layer 2 plays a key role too.
</p>
<p>
    Probably these blockchains are the most famous ones to you. Bitcoin,
    Ethereum, Cardano or Solana are examples of this category and most
    probably.
</p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <p>
            <h5>L1 Example</h5>
            <h5>Algorand: Offsetting the Carbon Footprint</h5>
            <small> As opposed to Ethereum, Algorand is a L1 chain, without needing L2
                protocols for scability purposes. This is because the consensus mechanism
                in the Algorand Network is quite different. In this case, a group of
                validators is selected randomly each time, without needing to have the
                majority. Algorand is also known as the Green Blockchain.<br>
                <a href="https://www.algorand.com/">
                    Additional information
                </a>
            </small>
            </p>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
    Layer 2
</h2>
<p>
    In L1 blockchains, we have seen the Blockchain Trilemma and the problem
    with scalability. Apart from the Blockchain Trilemma Bitcoin and Ethereum
    are getting older and what was valid some years ago it is no longer enough,
    mainly with the increasing number of users. .For example, we have several
    problems in terms of scalability, speed and gas fees. For that reason, the
    purpose of L2 blockchains is to enhance the L1 blockchains, with several
    updates and applications. Via this layer, the processing of the different
    transactions is also increased. This layer is seen as an auxiliary
    extension of the L1 protocol .
</p>
<p>
    For example, Ethereum is only able to process around 10 transactions per
    second. Ethereum is famous for many benefits, but one of the disadvantages
    is the gas fees. When the network is congested, there is a lot of
    competition to process the different transactions and it’s when the gas
    fees considerably increase – the law of supply and demand -. This problem
    is becoming more often because of the adoption of Ethereum and the
    applications within the ecosystem.
</p>
<p>
    What the L2 protocol does is to free up Ethereum (L1) from this work. This
    way, they can process thousands of transactions per second. Ethereum is the
    layer with more L2 protocols.
</p>
<p>
    Ethereum is famous for having many L2 solutions, but it also applies to
    other L1 layers such as Bitcoin.There are some examples for Etherum:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Polygon is one example running on top of Ethereum. The goal of the
        Indian platform is to connect blockchains built on Ethereum.
    </li>
    <li>
        Optimism is also developed for Ethereum in order to improve speed and
        reduce fees in the Ethereum network
    </li>
    <li>
        Immutable X is the second layer protocol used in the NFT Marketplace
        OpenSea (built on ERC-721), that helps also reduce fees when
        transacting in the blockchain.
    </li>
</ul>
<p>

</p>
<p>
    <div class="container">
        <div class="post-heading">
            <div class="card-header">
            <p>
            <h5>L2 Example</h5>
            <h5>Lightning Network</h5>
            <small>For the most famous chain, the Lightning Network is a L2 payment protocol layered on top
                of Bitcoin. It permits fast transactions among participating nodes and has
                been proposed as an approach to the bitcoin scalability trouble.<br>
                <a href="https://lightning.network/">
                    Additional information
                </a>
            </small>
            </p>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
    Layer 3
</h2>
<p>
    We have seen that L1 and L2 layers are quite linked to each one, but there
    are many differences between the different blockchains in these layers. The
    reason is that they use completely different technologies and processes.
    The purpose of the third layer is to abstract these differences and make
    the things much easier for the user. With this, the different ecosystems
    are interconnectable and can communicate regardless of the technical
    differences that we can find among them
</p>
<p>
    This is something similar to what’s done in the IP Internet Protocol and
    the application layer. L3 is the protocol that hosts the DApps. These
    applications are related to diverse topics such as DeFi, games, or storage
    apps.
</p>
<p>
    Although Bitcoin is the most known one here, Ethereum is the one that has
    more applications and has a huge ecosystem. The different cases vary across
    sectors:
</p>
<p>
    Ethereum aside, Solana is also famous for having many consolidated
    applications.
</p>
<p>
<h3>
    Examples of dApps
</h3>
<p>
    In order to understand the last layer, these are some examples of complete different applications accessible to
    users.
</p>
</p>
<h4>
    1. Uniswap (v2 and v3)
</h4>
<p>
    <a href="https://uniswap.org/">
        Uniswap</a> is one of the largest DEXs in the space and is powered by the Ethereum
    blockchain. One of the main differences compared to Binance or Coinbase is
    that Uniswap operates without an order book. Instead, it uses framework to
    provide trading liquidity.
</p>
<h4>
    2. OpenSea
</h4>
<p>
    <a href="https://opensea.io/">
        OpenSea</a> is the world’s largest Non-Fungible Token marketplace which is
    based on Ethereum ERC-721. In this platform all users can buy, sell, or exchange different items, such as collectibles, gaming articles and other type of goods.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/blockchain_layers/opensea.jpg" alt="An art and collectible game-changer">
    <span class="caption text-muted">OpenSea allows users to buy, sell, and discover exclusive digital items.</span>
</p>
<h4>
    3. Orca
</h4>
<p>
    <a href="https://www.orca.so/">
        Orca</a> is the first user-friendly cryptocurrency exchange built on Solana. It
    offers minimal fees and latency compared to Ethereum. There, users can exchange tokens with minimal transaction fees
    and lower latency than any decentralized exchange on Ethereum. Apart from that, users
    can provide liquidity to a trading pool to earn a share of trading fees.
</p>
<h4>
    4. PancakeSwap
</h4>
<p>
    <a href="https://pancakeswap.finance/">
        PancakeSwap</a> an be seen as an alternative to UniSwap.
    As this one, is a decentralized exchange, which allows for
    trading cryptocurrencies and tokens without an intermediary, and runs on
    Binance Smart Chain. It is built on an automated market maker system, which
    relies on liquidity pools between token pairs to enable crypto trades.

</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Blockchain" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The utilities and functions of each Blockchain Layer (L0, L1, L2, L3) explained with several real examples]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/blockchain_layers/layers.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/blockchain_layers/layers.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What DAO you want?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/08/what_dao_you_want/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What DAO you want?" /><published>2022-05-08T14:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-08T14:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/08/what_dao_you_want</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/08/what_dao_you_want/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    You have been probably hearing the term DAO for some time, but some topics may
    not be clear yet to you. A DAO is a Decentralized Autonomous
    Organization. In other words, it is an organization that is controlled
    by algorithms or smart contracts, it is not bound by any particular law
    since it is controlled by a blockchain and smart contracts. In other
    words, what it is looking for is to get rid of intermediaries, just as
    bitcoin did when it was created more than 10 years ago. The purpose of
    a DAO is also the one for a company or an institution to be able to
    function without hierarchical management.
</div>
<p>
    To give you an example, bitcoin can be considered a primitive DAO,
    since it works with a series of given rules, is autonomous, and is
    managed in a decentralized way following a consensus protocol.
    Although, the use of Smart contracts, typical of DAOs, did not reach
    the Ethereum platform, which allowed their creation, and has given them
    their current structure.
</p>
<p>
    Initially, Bitcoin was considered the first fully functional DAO, as it
    has a set of pre-programmed rules, works autonomously, and is
    coordinated through a distributed consensus protocol. Since then, the
    use of smart contracts and dApps has been made possible by the Ethereum
    platform, which has brought the creation of DAOs closer to the general
    public and shaped their current look.
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
    How it works
</h2>
<p>
    The launch of development of a DAO is composed of 3 different steps easy to understand. This is how DAOs work and the distinct phases before it becomes totally decentralized.
</p>
<h3>
    First phase
</h3>
<p>
    The first phase is setting the rules according to which it will work.
    Those rules are codes as a smart contract, existing autonomously on the
    Internet, but at the same time requiring developers to perform some
    specific tasks.
</p>
<h3>
    Second phase
</h3>
<p>
    Once the rules are established, the next phase is the financing phase.
    This is a very important milestone part for two reasons. First of all,
    a DAO has to have some kind of internal property. In this case, these
    are tokens that can be spent by the organization or used to reward
    certain activities within it.
</p>
<p>
    Second, by investing in a DAO, users gain voting rights, as if they
    owned the shares of a company. Consequently, you can give your opinion
    and take part in the decisions of the DAO.
</p>
<h3>
    Third phase
</h3>
<p>
    Once the funding period ends and a DAO is deployed, it becomes a fully
    autonomous body and completely independent from its creators, as well
    as from anyone else. They are open-source, which means their code can
    be viewed by anyone. Also, all financial rules and transactions are
    recorded on the blockchain. This makes DAOs transparent, immutable, and
    incorruptible.
</p>
<p>
    Once the DAO is up and running, all decisions about where and how to
    spend your funds are made by consensus. Everyone who bought a stake in
    a DAO can make proposals about its future. To prevent the network from
    being spammed with proposals, a monetary deposit may be required to
    submit such a proposal.
</p>
<p>
    Subsequently, the interested parties vote on the proposal. To perform
    any action, the majority needs to agree to do it. The percentage
    required to reach that majority may vary depending on each DAO, as may
    be specified in its code.
</p>
<p>
    Essentially, DAOs allow people to exchange their funds with anyone in
    the world. This can be done in the form of an investment, a charitable
    donation, fundraisers, loans, etc. all without a middleman. One
    potentially important problem with the voting system is that even if a
    security hole was detected in early code, it cannot be fixed until the
    majority votes on it. While the vote is taking place, such hackers can
    exploit a bug in the code.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/dao/dao_types.jpg" alt="Diversity of DAOs">
    <span class="caption text-muted">There are diverse DAO categories and more and more DAOs created in those</span>
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
    How to invest
</h2>
<p>
    Investing in a DAO is relatively easy, especially if we know have
    experience buying other cryptocurrencies and we already have a wallet
    to store the coins. All we really need to do is buy tokens of a
    particular DAO. As described before, buying tokens would be the
    equivalent of buying shares of Amazon, Apple, or Microsoft. In some
    cases, there are dedicated channels like Discord where some interesting
    information is shared.
</p>
<p>
    Once the financing phase is over, we will be able to make proposals,
    vote on them and even obtain benefits. The number of tokens purchased
    will correlate to the amount of voting power we will get within the
    DAO.
</p>
<p>
    However, before investing, we must be sure about the project to know
    exactly what we are getting into. DAOs are completely transparent and
    their underlying code is always open source, which means that only we
    have the opportunity to review the code to make sure there are no bugs
    in it.
</p>
<p>
    It is undeniable that the very concept of DAOs is extremely exciting as
    it strives to solve everything that is wrong with the way modern
    organizations are managed. A perfectly structured DAO gives each
    investor the opportunity to shape the organization. There is no
    hierarchical structure, which means that each innovative idea can be
    submitted by anyone and considered by the entire organization. With a
    set of pre-written rules that every investor knows before joining the
    organization, as well as the voting system, they leave no room for
    discussion.
</p>
<p>
    Furthermore, since both submitting a proposal and voting in favor of it
    require the investor to spend a certain amount of money, it pushes him
    to evaluate his decisions and not waste time on ineffective solutions.
    Finally, as all the rules, as well as each of the financial
    transactions, are registered in the Blockchain, available for review by
    anyone, the DAOs are completely transparent. Everyone who participates
    helps decide how to spend the funds and can track how those funds are
    spent.
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
     Examples
</h2>
<p>
    Depending on the purpose, there are several types of DAOs. Some of them
    are the following ones:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Investment DAOs
    </li>
    <li>
        Collector DAOs
    </li>
    <li>
        Entertainment DAOs
    </li>
    <li>
        Grant DAOs
    </li>
    <li>
        Protocol DAOS
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    In this article, we will focus on some names related to different DAO
    categories, with no preferential order.
</p>
<h3>
    1. Maker DAO
</h3>
<p>
    This is probably one of the most famous DAO out there. We have seen
    that with DeFi, we can reach the democratization of finance and we can
    make many products available to almost everyone around the world
</p>
<p>
    MakerDao, not to be confused with DAO Maker, has world’s first unbiased
    currency, Dai, which is a Maker Dao’s star product. DAI is a stable,
    decentralized currency that does not discriminate. Any individual or
    business can take benefit from the advantages of digital money.
</p>
<p>
    Dai is a stable coin, hence there is no volatility and for that reason,
    it is used in different financing projects. With this coin, you can
    exchange your assets for Dai and use this money in various aspects of
    finance.
</p>
<p>
    Regarding governance, a community of MKR token holders governs the
    Maker Protocol, the smart contracts that power the stable coin Dai.
</p>
<p>
    Over 400 apps and services such as wallets, DeFi platforms, or games
    have integrated Dai as an allowed payment method.
</p>

<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Maker DAO Information</h5>
                <strong>Site: </strong> <a href="https://makerdao.com/en/">https://makerdao.com/en/
            <a/> <br>
                <strong>Price: </strong> <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/maker/">MKR</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>

<h3>
    2. KlimaDAO
</h3>
<p>
    With the importance of climate change and small reactivity from some
    governments and companies, it is time that we do something about it.
    While our actions may not have had much positive impact in the past. we
    can start pushing for a change with KlimaDao
</p>
<p>
    With KlimaDAO, users can make a better more sustainable and greener
    world, by fighting against climate change. Via this mechanism, owners
    of this token can earn rewards with the KLIMA token. KLIMA is a digital
    currency backed by real carbon assets.
</p>
<p>
    They have started a decentralized and open market for carbon. Besides,
    the KLIMA token incentivizes investors, citizens, and organizations to
    participate in and govern this new economy.
</p>
<p>
    By increasing access and demand for carbon offsets, KlimaDAO makes
    pro-climate projects more profitable. At the same time, this process
    forces companies to adapt faster to climate change.
</p>

<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>KlimaDAO Information</h5>
                <Strong>Site: </Strong>
                <a href="https://www.klimadao.finance/">
                    https://www.klimadao.finance/
                </a><br>
                <Strong>Price: </Strong>
                <a
                        href="https:/coinmarketcap.com/currencies/klimadao/"
                >
                    KLIMA
                </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>

<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/dao/klima.jpg" alt="Time to Act">
    <span class="caption text-muted">KlimaDAO's goal is fighting the climate change global problem and at the same time profit from fighting against it.</span>
</p>

<h3>
    3. Olympus DAO
</h3>
<p>
    With all the central banks printing money and excessive Quantitative
    Easing, these actions have led to many negative consequences. For
    example, it has caused the devaluation of our currencies and assets in
    most countries.
</p>
<p>
    Olympus is building a community-owned, decentralized, and
    censorship-resistant reserve currency that is deeply liquid,
    asset-backed, and used widely. The name of this currency is OHM.
</p>
<p>
    With the rise of decentralized finance and economy, these concepts will
    also need a decentralized reserve currency. In other words, we need a
    currency that is not pegged to any central bank or fiat system
</p>
<p>
    Via this, Olympus DAO’s goal is to build a stable but independent
    currency that achieves purchasing power, broad acceptance, and high
    utility for all users.
</p>

<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Olympus DAO Information</h5>
                <strong>Site: </strong>
                <a href="https://www.olympusdao.finance/">
                    https://www.olympusdao.finance/
                </a><br>
                <strong>Price: </strong> <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/olympus/">OHM</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>


<h2>
    4. Seed Club
</h2>
<p>
    Seed Club is a DAO whose mechanisms are similar to those of a modern
    incubator or accelerator, investing in start-ups. You can make an
    enormous impact when it comes to deciding what your favorite projects
    and start-ups are and finance those thanks to Seed Club
</p>
<p>
    They also state that their goal is to support and help projects for the
    long-term, and they are not looking for short-term wins.
</p>
<p>
    Overall, Seed Club is a DAO that builds and invests in communities
    investing in early projects. One of their focuses is on Web3
    communities. They have financed to date more than 30 projects and one
    of their flagship communities is included below.
</p>

<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Seed Club Information</h5>
                <strong>Site: </strong> <a href="https://www.seedclub.xyz/">https://www.seedclub.xyz/</a><br>
                <strong>Price: </strong>
                <a
                        href="https:/coinmarketcap.com/currencies/seed/"
                >
                    SEED
                </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>


<h3>
    5. Krause House
</h3>
<p>
    Krause House is one of the projects financed thanks to Seed Club. If
    you like basketball and the best league of the world, you may be
    interested in this DAO whose goal is to buy an NBA franchise.
</p>
<p>
    Krause House is a Decentralized Autonomous Organization (DAO) ruled
    through a network of enthusiasts, basketball enthusiasts, and purists.
    Together, we can write the consensus regulations as an effective way to
    bring the primary fan-ruled group to the NBA. The collective of
    formidable participants whose purpose is to very own an NBA crew
    describes the underlying mission of DAOs in its purest form:
</p>
<p>
    They will permit our contributors to take part in selections affecting
    the running approaches of a National Basketball Association (NBA) crew
    along with however now not restrained to a standard control, ticketing,
    merchandising, and partnership.
</p>
<p>
    This means that you can be the owner of an NBA team without being Mark
    Cuban or Steve Ballmer. Imagine signing the next free agent or picking
    your favorite prospect in the NBA draft? This will be soon possible.
</p>


<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Krause House Information</h5>
                <strong>Site: </strong> <a href="https://www.krausehouse.club/">
                https://www.krausehouse.club/
            </a><br>
                <strong>Price: </strong> <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/krause/">KRAUSE</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>

<h3>
    6. Jenny Metaverse DAO
</h3>
<p>
    Related to collector DAOs, the goal of the Jenny Metaverse DAO is to
    build the most amazing NFT collection in the world. In this
    contemporary art collection, Jenny DAO gives you the chance to be a
    visitor, user, and director at the same time.
</p>
<p>
    Jenny DAO is built on Unicly and collaborates with different prominent
    digital artists and influencers. Thanks to these. they have an
    exclusive collection of unique artworks and photographs.
</p>
<p>
    This is how it works: The DAO pool funds into the treasury, and these
    funds are later used be used to purchase different NFTs art
    collections.
</p>
<p>
    In this digital gallery, you may find unique and exclusive art
    collectibles, such as BAYC, Crypto Punks, Meebits, CyberKong VX or Tom Sachs Rocket Factory.
</p>


<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <h5>Jenny Metaverse DAO Information</h5>
                <strong>Site :</strong> <a href="https://www.jennynft.io/">https://www.jennynft.io/</a><br>
                <strong>Price :</strong>
                <a
                        href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/jenny-metaverse-dao-token/"
                >
                    UJENNY
                </a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
    Conclusion
</h2>
<p>
    DAOs and crypto in general have brought different benefits to users.
    Some of them are access, costs, or transparency. We are happy about the
    fact that are more opportunities that focus on our goals and that via
    pooling individuals with the same objectives we can achieve our desired
    goal. At the same time, there is also criticism related to the level of
    experience the members may have. The comment is that as opposed to
    traditional organizations, where a specific number of experience people
    (e.g. board of directors) make the decisions, granting all members of a
    DAO the power to make any change may not be the best generating the
    best results for these autonomous organizations in the long-term.
</p>
<p>
    However, what is certain is that DAOs have created disruption and could
    shake in the long-term the current organization design and how the
    interactions within these.
</p>
<p>
    Although there has been an increase in the number of DAOs, we will see
    many more interesting in the next years. In case you would like to
    investigate further, please note that the code of these DAOs is
    accessible. Therefore, please analyze in deep the content and the data
    in order to detect any problem independent of the topic/goal of the
    chosen one.
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Blockchain" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What do NBA, climate change or an art gallery have in common? DAO is the answer for this. In this article we explain briefly 6 interesting projects related to DAOs]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/dao/daos.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/dao/daos.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Web3 Is Coming</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/06/web3_is_coming/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Web3 Is Coming" /><published>2022-05-06T14:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-06T14:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/06/web3_is_coming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/06/web3_is_coming/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    If you are already up to date with concepts such as the ones of blockchain,
    DeFi, or metaverse, now is the time to find out about Web3. This term has
    gained traction in 2021 and 2022 and continues to be mentioned in articles
    that discuss about topics such NFTs, cryptocurrencies, or decentralized
    finance. However, Web3 (or Web 3.0) is far more than that as you will see
    below.
</div>
<p>
    On top of the latest trends and news, I see more ads, courses and job
    offers related to Web3. That is related to the growth and how the corporate
    world can benefit from this generation.
</p>
<p>
    Web3 is the third generation of Internet services for web site and
    applications. This concept focuses on the use of machine-based data
    understanding to provide a semantic and data-centric Web. The final goal of
    Web3 is to create smarter, more connected, and more open websites. Not just
    that, but the goal of Web3, as we will see later, is also to give back the
    prominence to the users.
</p>
<p>
    Web3 is not implemented yet, so there is no clear definition about various
    aspects yet. To give you an idea, making the transition from the original
    web, from Web 1.0 to Web 2.0, took more than one decade. Nowadays, we are
    still working with Web 2.0 and there may be still years to come until we
    see the full capabilities of Web3.
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
    History of the Internet
</h2>
<p>
    To give you some history about the internet, we can see that each topic for
    each of the Web version:
</p>
<h3>
    Web 1.0
</h3>
<p>
    If the early web, called 1.0, everything worked around hyperlinks. Web 1.0,
    also known as the World Wide Web, appeared first. Some of us will remember
    those days when connecting to the Internet was a still a slow process and
    there were still not many options yet.
</p>
<h3>
    Web 2.0
</h3>
<p>
    Next, we have Web2.0. This one was around social networks. This is the term you have been hearing in the last years with the boom of Facebook, Twitter and other companies.
</p>
<p>
    As more people began to use the Internet, the potential it had was
    understood globally. For this reason, new infrastructures were created to
    promote it. The Internet became faster and allowed for heavier applications
    and websites, which gave rise to the era of social networks and huge
    platforms such as Netflix, YouTube, Facebook, or Amazon.
</p>
<p>
    Today, people from all over the world can share information and be
    entertained, shop, find answers to their questions and interact with each
    other thanks to Web 2.0.
</p>
<h3>
    Web3
</h3>
<p>
    The last generation, Web 3.0, is based on tokens, the digital units of
    exchange for blockchain technologies.
</p>
<p>
    There are already some Web3 examples. On one hand, we have Apple's Siri,
    which
    <strong>
        uses voice recognition techniques and artificial intelligence to bring
        results and perform actions
    </strong>
    . To give us an idea of the improvement that this entails, Webs 1.0 and 2.0
    carry out word-by-word matches of the text in relation to what is published
    on the network. This often brings with it an information bias.
</p>
<p>
    Web3 systems, however, seek contextualized knowledge to help people in
    their searches, pointing to a series of analyses and potentially useful
    information. One of the distinctions of the Web 3.0 search engine is the
    time the user needs to spend navigating through a universe of data to find
    what they really want resolved.
</p>
<p>
    Companies like Amazon, Apple and IBM have been investing heavily in Web 3.0
    technologies. For example, Google Inc. over the last decade has made
    several acquisitions of companies in the Semantic Web area, such as Applied
    Semantics and Metaweb Technologies, Inc, among others.
</p>
<p>
    On the other hand, not everything will take so long to arrive to our daily
    lives. There are some technologies that will define this new web that are
    already being developed. For example, smart home and home automation
    applications using wireless networks and IoT are examples of how Web3 is
    already impacting technology.
</p>
<p>
    If we go to existing devices: Apple's Siri or Amazon’s Alexa are examples
    of Web3 since they combine artificial intelligence with voice recognition.
    This network is still developing and there is still a long way to go.
    Another important player in Web3 is the Brave Browser and some interesting
    reward mechanisms such as BAT tokens.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/web3/web3_2.webp" alt="Tokens">
    <span class="caption text-muted">Users and content creators will gain power via tokenization and rewards in Web3</span>
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
    Characteristics of Web3
</h2>
<p>
    First, Web 3.0 will be primarily data centric. This data is endless and for
    that reason it is necessary to design an appropriate storage architecture
    and technology. Although Big Data seems to be the way to go, there is still
    research to be done on the most effective use of technology to store and
    manage this data, as privacy issues could arise in the future too.
</p>
<h4>
    Tokenization
</h4>
<p>
    This new web model has many services based on the token economy, so that
    the ownership and control of these services would be distributed among the
    owners of the tokens, who are also users. The tokens, as we know, have
    exchange value, so this means that users can collect these tokens whenever
    they want. Therefore, Web3 and DeFi may also come hand in hand.
</p>
<p>
    What it does seem is that Web 3.0 will be primarily data centric. This data
    is infinite and therefore it is necessary to design an appropriate storage
    architecture and technology. Although Big Data seems to be the way to go,
    there is still a lot of research to be done on the most effective use of
    technology to store data, as privacy issues could arise.
</p>
<h4>
    Robustness
</h4>
<p>
    This network will give creators and users more freedom in general. It will
    ensure that the latter always have control over their online data by using
    decentralized networks. The next version of the Internet is also expected
    to be more reliable given its decentralized nature, which eliminates the
    possibility of a single point of failure
</p>
<h4>
    Democratization
</h4>
<p>
    It does not need to be controlled by a single entity. The largest companies
    may no longer have full control over the Internet. As a result,
    decentralized applications or apps cannot be censored or restricted in any
    way.
</p>
<p>
    What is going on now with Web 2.0 is that users create but it is the
    technology companies that monetize this content
</p>
<h4>
    Customization
</h4>
<p>
    We will also be able to personalize our browsing experience because this
    type of website will be able to understand our preferences and tastes. This
    will also allow us to navigate more productively, focusing on what we are
    really interested in.
</p>
<h4>
    Commerce
</h4>
<p>
    The same way Web3 will help users, this version will also help businesses,
    and this will cause eCommerce to continue growing. Sellers will better
    understand our purchasing needs and will show us those products and
    services that we are interested in buying with the help of artificial
    intelligence. This will allow us to see better, more relevant ads that are
    more likely to be beneficial to us.
</p>
<h4>
    Better connectivity
</h4>
<p>
    In the past years, we have seen cases that because of interruptions in the
    service, we have lost access to some sites or services for hours.
</p>
<p>
    Since the data will be stored in distributed databases by decentralization,
    users will not have to worry about service interruptions or account
    suspensions for technical reasons.
</p>
<h4>
    Decentralization
</h4>
<p>
    As we have commented in the previous point, one of the key characteristics
    of web 3.0 is decentralization. In this new version, the data will be
    connected in a decentralized way, unlike 2.0, in which it is mainly stored
    in centralized places. Therefore, the data will not be kept in the
    datacentres of big corporations anymore.
</p>
<p>
    We saw with the explosion of web 2.0 brings social networks and
    interactivity with the user, which creates most of its content. It is the
    era of companies like Facebook, Google, Apple, Amazon, creating silo,
    centralized services dependent on these corporations.
</p>
<h2>
    The role of corporations
</h2>
<p>
    The impact of Web 3.0 on companies will take place in different ways. In
    some cases,    <strong>it will make them highly user-centric and more transparent</strong>
    . Everything that was wrong in terms of user data will undergo a radical
    transformation.
</p>
<p>
    Traditional and new businesses alike will welcome Blockchain technology and
    all the possibilities it brings. You will see that your applications will
    receive blockchain updates in which everything will be made public and
    accessible.
</p>
<p>
    Web 3.0 will bring about a major change in how the Internet works by
    focusing on user privacy. In fact, this is a problem that has been
    discussed for a long time but has not been effectively solved.
</p>
<p>
    Web3 uses blockchain technology, unlike Web 2.0, which takes advantage of
    the Internet to develop applications. It is technically safer to store
    customer data on a blockchain as it is decentralized and its use by
    businesses is transparent, thus protecting it from hackers. Some experts
    say the transfer of data ownership to consumers could disrupt the
    technology sector. And this is because many technology companies would lose
    access to the data that has given them a competitive advantage until now.
</p>
<p>
    Also, thanks to blockchain technology, visitors to a website will have a
    more pleasant login experience. Think how many times you have logged into
    websites using your Facebook profile. Blockchain technology employs the
    same principle as Facebook, which already owns the user's information.
    However,
    <strong>
        by using Blockchain, you will be the sole owner of your information.
    </strong>
</p>
<p>
    <strong> </strong>
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
    What's next?
</h2>
<p>
    <strong>To sump up, in Web</strong>
    <strong>3</strong>
    <strong>
        , users will also be able to interact with data thanks to the use of
        artificial intelligence and machine learning technology.
    </strong>
    That is, it will combine the concepts of the Semantic Web with AI.
</p>
<p>
    On the other hand, the use of artificial intelligence will allow data much
    faster to users and that these data will be more relevant and personified.
    We are starting to see the use of this technology on the Internet
    <strong>
        through algorithms that are used to suggest products or videos to users
        based on their previous searches
    </strong>
    .
</p>
<p>
    However, this will be even more advanced, and we have still to see a wide
    range of new possibilities in the upcoming years.
</p>
<p>
    We could say that with Web3 we come back to where the Internet started and
    the original idea: a decentralized internet, where there is no control from
    central authorities and the power is given back to the users and consumers.
    However, the full potential of Web3 is still to be seen.
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web3 contains different advantages and will include many changes in our daily life and in many organizations]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/web3/web3_1.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/web3/web3_1.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Investing in Niche Sectors</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/24/niche_sectors_investing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Investing in Niche Sectors" /><published>2022-04-24T14:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-24T14:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/04/24/niche_sectors_investing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/24/niche_sectors_investing/"><![CDATA[<h2 xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/html" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/html">
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    Some weeks ago, we introduced some investment funds or ETFs focusing on
    specific countries or indexes such as the S&amp;P500 or the Nasdaq. We also
    went further and analyzed some interesting regions with a considerable
    expected growth for the following years.
</div>
<p>
    I have also said that I prefer to focus on these broad investment vehicles
    in order to get the best possible returns with the lowest possible risk,
    due to the diversification that these products offer.
</p>
<p>
    However, this approach may be boring, and we can always allocate some of
    our savings to have some fun, either in the way of cherry picking some
    stocks or in this case with some niche sectors. The idea on selecting these
    specific areas for the ETF, is because we think that there will be a huge
    growth in these sectors in the upcoming years (or in the short-term).
    Depending on our strategy, they help us combine our defensive and
    aggressive options in our portfolio.
</p>
<p>
    Please note that the price of a security is composed of the current
    earnings and the estimated growth. This also means that for sectors with a
    high growth, the current price already reflects it.
</p>
<p>
    In any case, these are some of the industries that will create a
    considerable impact in the years to come, and for that reason it may be
    worth to have some of our portfolio destined to any of these sectors.
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
    1. Videogames
</h2>
<p>
    When I was young, the video games sector was already important, but it was
    below the movies or the music industry. Today, this industry’s revenue is
    bigger than the one of these two industries combined. The growth has been
    incredible in the last 15 years, but it will for sure not stop there.
</p>
<p>
    While some years ago, most games could not be played online, this activity
    has also changed in the last years, opening new possibilities. For example,
    we have also seen this with the different organizations supporting and
    investing in eSports. New ways of entertainment have been included, giving
    more importance to social or mobile games.
</p>
<p>
    The latest trends such as NFT or the metaverse have also an important role
    on some of these games and the different unique items that the players may
    get. In some cases, the trends could change completely the way we game.
    Therefore, if the growth in the last decade was already impressive, these
    two blockchain phenomenon will help to push the videogames even further.
</p>
<p>
    <div class="container">
        <div class="post-heading">
            <div class="card-header">
                <p>
                    <h5>Example</h5>
                    <strong>VanEck Video Gaming and eSports UCITS ETF</strong><br>
                    <small>At a time when the video gaming industry is growing meteorically, the VanEck Video Gaming and eSports UCITS ETF provides exposure to the sector’s innovators. They are disrupting traditional media and sport, bringing together entertainment, video gaming, sports and media.<br>
                    </small>
                    <a href="https://www.vaneck.com/ch/en/espo/">
                       Additional information
                    </a>
                </p>
            </div>
        </div>
</div>
    </p>
<p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/niche/videogames.jpg" alt="Evolution">
    <span class="caption text-muted">In just a few decades, the growth of the video consoles and other devices has been immense</span>
</p>
</p>
    <h2>
        2. Artificial Intelligence
    </h2>
    <p>
        The advance of Artificial Intelligence is unstoppable, as organizations
        are adopting different branches of this technology to boost their
        digital transformation, giving great strength to a market that
        encompasses AI software, hardware, and services.
    </p>
    <p>
        Today, the application fields of AI range from finance to robot
        control, from image recognition to vehicle driving and much more. We
        can see that big players like Google, Apple, Intel, Amazon, IBM are
        investing massively in the development of this sector. Not long ago,
        Google bough the company DeepMind for $400 million.
    </p>
    <p>
        Artificial Intelligence (AI) is a branch of computer science that seeks
        to bring technology to mimic human behavior. Theorizing of a computer
        mind that mimics the functioning of the human goes back more than half
        a century, in 1956, when the term Artificial Intelligence was
        introduced as part of the Dartmouth Summer Research project.
    </p>
    <p>
        The shift from theory to practice came hand in hand with the rise of
        computer skills. The technological acceleration of recent years has
        allowed the development of increasingly sophisticated and powerful
        algorithms. Today, the application fields of AI range from finance to
        robot control, from image recognition to vehicle driving and much more.
        Big conglomerates like Google, Apple, Intel, Amazon, IBM are investing
        massively in the development of this sector.
    </p>
    <p>
        According to some sources, sales in the next eight years may grow by up
        to 35,570 million dollars, or what is the same, an increase capacity of
        more than 600%. In addition to this astonishing information, investment
        in AI is increasing at a rate of 37% per year and by 2022 it will
        exceed 77 billion dollars, three times more than the current 24
        billion.
    </p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <p>
            <h5>Example</h5>
            <strong>WisdomTree Artificial Intelligence UCITS ETF – USD Acc</strong><br>
                <small>The WisdomTree Artificial Intelligence UCITS ETF (the “Fund”) seeks to track the price and yield performance, before fees and expenses, of the NASDAQ CTA Artificial Intelligence Index (the “Index”)</small><br>
                <a href="https://www.wisdomtree.eu/en-ch/etfs/thematic/wtai---wisdomtree-artificial-intelligence-ucits-etf---usd-acc">
                    Additional information
                </a>
            </p>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<p>
</p>
    <h2>
        3. eCommerce
    </h2>
    <p>
        Although eCommerce had been growing steadily for years, COVID-19 was
        the trigger that changed in many cases how we buy different products
        and articles, and in general the shopping experience. Due to the loosen
        restrictions in most countries, the growth has been normalized in 2021,
        but predictions say that eCommerce will be growing every year. Indeed,
        the pandemic helped some people discover that buying could be much
        easier and without any issue.
    </p>
    <p>
        Some factors helping the growth will be related to mobile phones and
        faster technologies such as 5G. More services such as augmented
        reality, virtual reality, image recognition or artificial intelligence
        will be possible to offer a broader range of possibilities to the
        customer. Besides, almost every company today has an online application
        and from there the user can buy directly almost anything.
    </p>
    <p>
        Furthermore, the rise of more payment options such as of
        cryptocurrencies will also be an added benefit to customers wanting to
        buy online.
    </p>
    <p>
        While more senior people were initially reluctant to online shopping,
        younger generations such as the millennials are the early adaptors of
        this trend. This means that this way of buying will be already
        inculcated for the new generations to come and will be seen as
        something completely normal in the everyday life of every customer in a
        few years from now.
    </p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <p>
            <h5>Example</h5>
            <Strong>L&amp;G Ecommerce Logistics UCITS ETF</Strong><br>
                <small>The L&G Ecommerce Logistics UCITS ETF (the "ETF") aims to track the performance of the Solactive Ecommerce Logistics Index (the "Index").</small><br>
                <a href="https://fundcentres.lgim.com/ch/qual/fund-centre/ETF/Ecommerce-Logistics/">
                    Additional information
                </a>
            </p>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<p>
    <h2>
        4. Cannabis
    </h2>
    <p>
        This is a controversial topic in some cases, but the truth is that more
        and more countries are allowing the usage of marijuana for therapeutic
        treatments. I have said that it is a polemic aspect because Cannabis
        has been seen as a criminal or something that should be avoided until
        recently. Although, we need more education on this topic, mainly for
        younger generations. it has been proved that the Marijuana derivative
        medicaments or therapies have multiples benefits in diseases.
        Furthermore, the price of this medication is generally lower compared
        to other alternatives, and it also has less side effects.
    </p>
    <p>
        The US and Canada have been two of the latest countries that have
        approved the usage of Marijuana, and as many things occur, some other
        regions such as Europe or Asia may also follow soon.
    </p>
    <p>
        It is expected to grow between 2022 and 2030 with an annualized rate of
        25%. Apart from the medical advances, the decriminalization has also an
        important role in this rise.
    </p>
    <p>
        There are two factors that will be key for the expansion of the
        Cannabis sector:
    </p>
    <p>
        In terms of regulation, it is predicted that more and more countries
        will allow medical treatment with Marijuana or derivatives from this
        drug.
    </p>
    <p>
        Another key aspect is the global population aging. We live more years,
        and because of this, we also suffer from more diseases. In some cases,
        Marijuana can play an important role to mitigate of our life
        expectancy. All in all, Cannabis has the potential to help humankind,
        being part of the different breakthroughs in terms of health.
    </p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <p>
            <h5>Example</h5>
            <strong>Rize Medical Cannabis and Life Sciences UCITS ETF</strong><br>
                <small>In a single trade, FLWR delivers access to dozens of companies that are favourably positioned to ride the tailwinds of the medical cannabis and life sciences theme.</small><br>
                <a href="https://rizeetf.com/funds/medical-cannabis-and-life-sciences/">
                    Additional information
                </a>
            </p>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/niche/cannabis.jpg" alt="Upcoming developments">
    <span class="caption text-muted">There is still a lot to learn in the Cannabis industry </span>
</p>
    <h2>
        5. Water
    </h2>
    <p>
        Because all these investments don’t have to be necessarily related to
        technological improvements, we refer in this section to one of the
        oldest things in history. We are made for the most part out of water
        and we need water to survive. While people think on electricity or gas
        when investing in different companies, we could survive without these
        two, but water is essential for our survival. Other utilities such as
        oil and gold are also
    </p>
    <p>
        Unfortunately. due to climatic change and other linked problems, water
        is becoming scarcer. Besides, accessing to water in some countries is
        still a nightmare. Out of the total water on earth, 97% is saltwater.,
        and out of the remaining 3%, another percentage is frozen.
    </p>
    <p>
        Since we all need water and there is less for all of us, with the
        expected growth of the global population, the more demand and less
        supply means that the value of water will increase.
    </p>
<p>
<div class="container">
    <div class="post-heading">
        <div class="card-header">
            <p>
            <h5>Example</h5>
            <strong>iShares Global Water UCITS ETF</strong><br>
            <small>The Fund seeks to track the performance of an index composed of 50 of the largest global companies engaged in water related businesses</small><br>
                <a href="https://www.ishares.com/ch/individual/en/products/251913/ishares-global-water-ucits-etf">
                    Additional information
                </a>
            </p>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>

    <h2>
        Conclusion
    </h2>
    <p>
        We have described 5 sector that are expected to grow in the years to
        come at cruise speed. Investing in companies that are focused on these
        sectors can add additional diversification to our portfolio, add
        defensive or aggressive variants to it while we have some fun with our
        choice.
    </p>
    <p>
        There are other sectors that were not included in this post, but that
        will grow very much in the next decade. Some of them are the following
        ones: Blockchain, semiconductors or metaverse
    </p>
    <p>
        As mentioned in the introduction, even if they are expected to grow,
        the current price may already reflect the expected expansion and
        development of these industries.
    </p>
    <p>
        Another factor to be noted is liquidity. For example, if you want to
        buy or sell, there may be less options, not just in the form of funds
        or ETFs, but in the number of orders.
    </p>
    <p>
        All in all, there are some advantages and disadvantages when selecting
        niche funds. Therefore, I would not recommend including 100% of your
        portfolio into niche sectors. On the other hand, allocating just some
        of the money into these funds could be a wise and fun option for the
        future.
    </p>
    <p>
        If you are interested on how to access to buy them, an example of
        different funds and ETFs has been included. You can see a list of
        brokers in one of my past articles:
        <a href="https://mrfreire.net/2021/12/26/achieving-economic-independence/">
Achieving Economic Independence</a>
    </p>
</nav>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Finance" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[From videogames to water or cannabis: Top 5 industries with high expected growth for the next years where you can invest]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/niche/water.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/niche/water.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Algorand Governance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/16/algorand_goverance_defi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Algorand Governance" /><published>2022-04-16T12:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-16T12:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/04/16/algorand_goverance_defi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/16/algorand_goverance_defi/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    In previous posts, we have explained different alternatives for our
    investments, and related to this one, we have also explained some ones
    focused on crypto or DeFi. The Algorand Foundation is another way to
    diversify your portfolio at the same time you take part in the decisions of
    the Algorand ecosystem. Connected to this, the Algorand Governance second
    period ended some days ago (31 March) and the third period just started
    some days ago
</div>
<p>
    But, what’s Algorand, and what is this Governance? For several people, these
    terms may be completely unknown.
</p>
<p>
    The history of Algorand begins in the year 2017, when the company was
    created by Silvio Micali, a well-known MIT professor, Turing award winner,
    and specialist in cryptography. Micali, who has been part of the crypto
    community since 1980, has significant work in asymmetric cryptography to
    his credit, and is a co-creator with Shafirira Goldwasser of zero-knowledge
    proofs (ZKP).
</p>
<p>
    Micali, who has always been a researcher, knows about blockchain technology
    and Bitcoin in 2015, and is interested in it. At that point, Micali started
    working on his personal cryptocurrency project, he decided to improve the
    specifications of Bitcoin and Ethereum. This led him to associate with
    Nickolai Zeldavich, a colleague from MIT and who served as Head of
    Distributed Systems at this institution, and who participated in the
    Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory (CSAIL).
</p>
<p>
    It is how Algorand was created. Algorand's main objective is to become a
    platform dedicated to offering high-speed decentralized applications
    (DApps) and DeFi that are available to everyone. To achieve this, Algorand
    is a permissionless blockchain. In this way, anyone can be part of it,
    within a transparent system in which everyone can achieve success through
    decentralized projects and applications.
</p>
<p>
    On the other hand, to deal with the Blockchain Trilemma, Algorand is based
    on a powerful and fast consensus protocol that can be used by any user with
    minimal computational power, who owns $ALGO and is online. All of these
    elements give you the right to be chosen to participate in Algorand's block
    consensus, which is a derivative of the Proof of Stake system.
</p>
<p>
    But along with this, Algorand focuses its development on creating tools
    that facilitate the deployment of decentralized applications and all the
    infrastructure necessary for their operation.
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
    How does Algorand work?
</h2>
<p>
    As we discussed a moment ago, Algorand is a permissionless blockchain and
    network. This first point is vital to eliminate any type of barrier in the
    use and evolution of the protocol. The main idea behind this principle is
    to guarantee a high level of decentralization, scalability and security.
</p>
<p>
    Second, Algorand's operation is based on a consensus protocol derived from
    Proof of Stake (called Pure Proof of Stake - PPoS). This system is created
    in order to guarantee the full participation of those who are part of the
    network, providing protection and speed. The use of PPoS is framed in
    achieving block production speed measured in a few seconds, which would
    allow a high scalability of the network, thus serving thousands of users
    concurrently, with truly short waiting times and, above all, with very low
    commission costs.
</p>
<p>
    In addition, the Algorand development team has devised new consensus
    algorithms, Byzantine fault-tolerant systems, and an entirely new hashing
    and digital signature system, with a focus on enabling the greatest
    possible scalability.
</p>
<h3>
    Pure Proof of Stake
</h3>
<p>
    The main pillar of Algorand's scalability and speed is its Pure Proof of
    Stake or Proof of Pure Participation (PPoS) protocol. This protocol is a
    derivative of the well-known Proof of Stake (PoS) of other cryptocurrencies
    such as the upcoming Ethereum Merge. The idea of this protocol in Algorand
    is to allow a sufficiently secure resistance to Byzantine faults, while
    providing great speed in the generation and validation of blocks within the
    network. At the same time, PoS is capable of supporting a large number of
    concurrent users and scales well as the network increases in number of
    validators.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/algorand/gov.jpg" alt="Governance Period 3">
    <span class="caption text-muted">The main dates for the third Governance period are included above</span>
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>
<h2>
    Algorand Governance
</h2>
<p>
    Before introducing the Governance period, we have described how Algorand
    works and the different benefits. Furthermore, the purpose of the
    organization is that everyone has a voice in the future plans of the
    network. The Algorand Governance first period started on 1 October 2021 and
    each of these periods last 3 months.
</p>
<p>
    This is done with a term called “Governor.” Governors are responsible for
    the most important economic and political decisions. This is be done
    through regular public votes that the Algorand Foundation will responsibly
    execute for the benefit of the broader ecosystem, based on the decisions of
    these Governors.
</p>
<p>
    It must be noted that Algorand holders are not automatically enrolled in
    the community governance. Algos holders need to go to the governance web
    portal and specify how many Algo tokens they are going to commit in each
    governance period. To participate, governors must sign a transaction
    representing the amount of tokens invested. The governance web portal can
    be used to generate a transaction in the correct format
</p>
<p>
    For keeping your ALGO, you can use your Ledger, Pera Algo, AlgoSigner or My
    Algo wallet. It must be noted that in order to be eligible for the rewards
    paid at the end of the quarter, the following conditions must be fulfilled:
</p>
<p>
<ul>
    <li>
        The number of ALGO committed for the period cannot decrease
    </li>
    <li>
        You must vote in the voting session for the respective period
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p class="big">
<hr class="bigHr">
</p>

<h3>
    Conclusion
</h3>
<p>
    Via this mechanism, the main objectives of the Governance periods are the
    following:
</p>
<p>
    On one hand, in this period the owners of ALGO who have committed can
    decide on the future steps of the Algorand network and any improvements
    that can be done via voting.
</p>
<p>
    On another hand, by committing the ALGO tokens, the owners are rewarded.
    There are generally 70.5 Billion algos for rewards. These need to be
    distributed between all the committed ALGO. On average, in the recent
    periods the return rate is around 10% per year, which is around 2.5% per
    quarter.
</p>
<p>
    The more total ALGOs are committed, the lower the APY will be. However, the
    main goal of this governance periods is also to make of the Algorand
    ecosystem the future of finance.
</p>
<p>
    Furthermore, we can also see recent new projects such as AlgoFi that will
    also play a key role in the growth and adoption of Algorand.
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Algorand Governance: Take part in the decisions of the future of DeFi]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/algorand/algorand.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/algorand/algorand.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Products for great Eyes and Look</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/05/products-protect-eyes-look/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Products for great Eyes and Look" /><published>2022-04-05T19:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-05T19:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/04/05/products-protect-eyes-look</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/05/products-protect-eyes-look/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<<div class="text-article">>
    It’s said that eyes are the soul's reflection and they are totally right.
    Our look can say man things about how we feel, our emotions and our energy.
</div>
<p>
    Nobody can’t disagree to this statement, but then, why we don’t pay
    attention to these two organs and the muscles around them? The technology
    has brought many advantages to our lifestyle. However, With our time
    exposed to screens and different devices, our eyes are suffering much more
    compared to other times in history
</p>
<h2>
    The importance of the eyes
</h2>
<p>
    Think for a moment about your eyes. You use them all the time when
    you're awake. You blink (between 11,000 and 15,000 times a day), you wink,
    you squint when you see the price of the new phone or clothes, you rub them
    when you're tired, etc. All in all, you use them for almost everything.
    These actions occur thanks to the number of tiny muscles that surround our
    eyes.
</p>
<p>
    Around our eyes, There are 22 muscles. called periorbital muscles and these
    muscles allow you to enjoy a wide range of gestures and movements. Besides,
    they have some characteristics that make them peculiar and, above all, they
    are clear indicators of how we feel. For example: when you sleep too
    little, don't drink enough water, your diet is not the best one, you are
    tired or sad, you abuse alcohol or any other substances... the eye contour
    is the first part of our body that shows this problem to the world.
</p>
<h2>
    Sensitive Organs
</h2>
<p>
    The skin around your eyes is the thinnest skin on your face. It is five
    times thinner than the rest of your face, and ten times thinner than that
    of other parts of the body. That means it has hardly any sebaceous glands
    and no supporting tissue, which is basically collagen. Therefore, it droops
    sooner.
</p>
<p>
    This causes this area to break down more quickly, leading to wrinkles known
    as crow's feet, and eyelid sagging.
</p>
<h2>
    The impact of sun
</h2>
<p>
    We have just described that the part of the eyes is very sensitive since it
    is a very thin skin. Therefore, it has fewer layers underneath and, exposed
    to Ultraviolet rays. This results in what is known as hyperpigmentation.
    Another cause of this unfortunate coloration is genetics; there are simply
    people who naturally have more dark circles under their eyes than others.
</p>
<p>
    Although fluid retention occurs to women in other parts of the body, in men
    this problem occurs in the eyes are. That’s when appear the feared dreaded
    bags as we get older.
</p>
<p>
    Aging is another critical factor for us. When you are young, the membrane
    is responsible for retaining the fat in the eyelids. But when we gain
    weight or older, the eyes membrane gets thinner and loses strength over
    time,
</p>
<h2>
    How to protect them?
</h2>
<p>
    All in all, we can say that the skin around the eye contour is the thinnest
    in the human body, it has a small number of sebaceous glands and its blood
    microcirculation is very slow. As a result, it is fragile, dehydrates
    easily and accumulates toxins quickly. In addition, and due to constant
    muscle contractions, it is the first area where signs of fatigue or aging
    become visible.
</p>
<p>
    We have seen the different problems men have when it comes to eyes and the
    areas surrounding it. Since it is a very sensitive area, we are exposed to
    the sun, and high-resolution screens, we need to find some ways to protect
    and repair the damage.
</p>
<p>
    Of course, a good diet, sleeping at least 8 hours or drinking enough water
    are of the utmost importance. However, without recurring to cosmetic
    surgery, there are some products that can be our allies to mitigate these
    problems.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/eye/steps.jpg" alt="Simple steps">
    <span class="caption text-muted">Following a daily mornign and night routine can help us improve our look without big efforts, but big benefits</span>
</p>
<h2>
    Products that will help us
</h2>
<h3>
    Idealove, Eye See You(th), Super-Ferment Eye Cream, 1.05 oz (30 g)
</h3>
<p>
    <strong>Idealove</strong>
    ™ <em>Eye See You(th), Super-Ferment Eye Cream</em> is rich in
    fermentation, peptides, and ceramides; this non-greasy eye treatment helps
    to firm, moisturize, and build elasticity for a youthful and rested look.
</p>
<p>
    Link:
    <a
            href="https://www.iherb.com/pr/idealove-eye-see-you-th-super-ferment-eye-cream-1-05-oz-30-g/102556"
    >
            Idealove, Eye See You(th), Super-Ferment Eye Cream, 1.05 oz (30 g)
    </a>
</p>
<h3>
    Idealove™Eye Admire Gold Hydrogel Eye Patches
</h3>
<p>
    These patches contain effective anti-aging ingredients that help hydrate
    the delicate skin around the eyes to help them appear glowing and youthful.
    This moisturizing blend delivers the ultimate infusion into your skin for
    dramatic results.
</p>
<p>
    Link:
    <a
            href="https://www.iherb.com/pr/idealove-eye-admire-gold-hydrogel-eye-patches-60-patches/97407"
    >
        Idealove™Eye Admire Gold Hydrogel Eye Patches
    </a>
</p>
<h3>
    Acure, Ultra Hydrating, Eye Cream, 0.5 fl oz (14.7 ml)
</h3>
<p>
    It wakes up your undereyes with their morning dose of coffee. It comes with
    deep moisturizing adaptogenic ashwagandha, holy basil, reishi mushroom and
    turmeric and stimulating supergreens and green coffee oil.
</p>
<p>
    Link:
    <a
            href="https://www.iherb.com/pr/acure-ultra-hydrating-eye-cream-0-5-fl-oz-14-7-ml/102728"
    >
        Acure, Ultra Hydrating, Eye Cream, 0.5 fl oz (14.7 ml<strong>)</strong>
    </a>
</p>
<h3>
    Yeouth, Retinol Eye Cream, 1 fl oz (30 ml)
</h3>
<p>
    This cream offers the following benetits:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Helps reduce the look of fine lines and wrinkles resulting in the
        appearance of a more youthful complexion.
    </li>
    <li>
        Attracts moisture to help skin appear more supple.
    </li>
    <li>
        Reduces the appearance of puffiness, wrinkles and bags around and under
        the eyes. Lessens the appearance of dark circles and improves the look
        of skin tone for brighter, more youthful looking skin.
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    Link:
    <a
            href="https://www.iherb.com/pr/yeouth-retinol-eye-cream-1-fl-oz-30-ml/81493"
    >
        Yeouth, Retinol Eye Cream, 1 fl oz (30 ml)
    </a>
</p>
<h3>
    1.6.5 Purito, Centella Green Level Eye Cream, 1 fl oz (30 ml)
</h3>
<p>
    It contains core ingredients such as Centella Asiatica extract (49%),
    Asiaticoside, Asiatic acid, and Madecassic acid. It gently spreads out and
    absorbed on the skin around the eyes. 4 types of peptide help with wrinkles
    and penetrate deeply inside of your skin. It keeps skin moisturized and is
    suitable for sensitive skin.
</p>
<p>
    Link:
    <a
            href="https://www.iherb.com/pr/purito-centella-green-level-eye-cream-1-fl-oz-30-ml/102168"
    >
            Purito, Centella Green Level Eye Cream, 1 fl oz (30 ml)
    </a>
</p>
<p>
    You may find other useful products elsewhere. However, if you would like to
    use the links above, you may use the code included here for a discount.
    Link: <a href="https://iherb.co/8tsMMkC">https://iherb.co/8tsMMkC</a>
</p>
<p>
    However, the purpose of this article is just describing the different
    solutions we can use to protect our eyes and have a perfect look.
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Beauty" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[5 Creams and products to enhance our look and protect our eyes]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/eye/tiger.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/eye/tiger.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Crypto Staking and Ethereum Merge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/03/staking-ethereum-merge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crypto Staking and Ethereum Merge" /><published>2022-04-03T12:01:13+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-03T12:01:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/04/03/staking-ethereum-merge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/03/staking-ethereum-merge/"><![CDATA[<h2>
    Introduction
</h2>
<div class="text-article">
    The world of crypto assets or cryptocurrencies is an ever-changing process
    that, like many others, is looking for the next big trend to continue
    generating digital and real value. This new trend could be Staking, the
    method that rewards users based on the number of coins they back the
    blockchain with. Staking comes from the Proof-Of-Stake, the consensus
    mechanism used in some of the crypto currency networks. Through
    proof-to-stake, some investors are already earning quite considerable
    annual percentage return while generating substantial passive income
    without efforts.
</div>
<h2>
    PoW vs PoS
</h2>
<p>
    Currently, both bitcoin and ether rely on miners to complete complex
    puzzles to validate transactions and create new coins. This process is
    known as proof-of-work (PoW) and requires an enormous amount of energy,
    having negative consequences in the environment. The reason is that for
    this validation process, the PoW consumes a high number of fossil fuels.
    Other cryptos, such as Solana or Algorand, already operate with
    proof-of-stake (PoS), with also quite reasonable returns.
</p>
<p>
    Specifically, the PoS process allows users to validate transactions based
    on the number of coins they contribute or wager. The more coins they wager,
    the higher the probability of validation. This reward can include an annual
    percentage return, and the exact amount depends on the blockchain
    technology used. In addition, Proof of Stake is considered the most
    environmentally friendly option nowadays.
</p>
<p>
    So far, we can distinguish between the following validation mechanisms for
    which the most known tokens are included below:
</p>
<h3>
    Proof of Work
</h3>
<ul>
    <li>
        Bitcoin
    </li>
    <li>
        Ethereum
    </li>
    <li>
        Dogecoin
    </li>
    <li>
        Litecoin
    </li>
</ul>
<h3>
    Proof of Stake
</h3>
<ul>
    <li>
        Solana
    </li>
    <li>
        Cardano
    </li>
    <li>
        Algorand
    </li>
    <li>
        Tezos
    </li>
</ul>
<h2>
    Ethereum Merge
</h2>
<p>
    Ethereum, the blockchain behind ether, could soon launch its long-awaited
    Merge update. The EIP will mean the end of Proof of Work for the Ethereum
    network, transitioning completely to Proof of Stake. Although the final
    schedule for this update is unknown, it is known that it will render
    cryptocurrency mining, based on proof-to-work, obsolete. This process,
    called Beacon, allows users to stake ether to support the blockchain and
    earn returns around 4% to 5%, Some industry experts predict that rewards
    with Merge will range from 7% to 12%.
</p>
<p>
    However, like everything else, staking has some side effects.
    Proof-to-stake essentially bets on the viability of the cryptocurrency
    being staked, so it is subject to the volatility of those digital assets.
    Added to this are potential restrictions on how quickly a cryptocurrency
    can be withdrawn after wagering, certain penalties for not actively
    validating transactions, or minimum amounts required to wager, among other
    issues.
</p>
<p>
    Some myths related to this upgrade are that the high fees of Ethereum will
    be reduced. This is not true and how gas works in Ethereum will not be
    changed. Another misconception was that a new token would be created with
    Ethereum Merge. This is also not true, and Ethereum’s cryptocurrency – ETH
    – will remain the same. In general, the main goal of the Ethereum Merge
    update is making Ethereum cryptographic mining obsolete, reducing its    <strong>environmental impact</strong>, together with enhanced security
    against potential attacks.
</p>
<p>
    <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/staking/eth.jpg" alt="Key Takeaways">
    <span class="caption text-muted">The main ideas of Ethereum Merge are shown above</span>
</p>
<h2>
    What’s next for Ethereum?
</h2>
<p>
    Having seen that Ethereum is evolving, this can have interesting benefits
    for investors and users. In the past years, the rise of NFTs is also thanks
    to Ethereum. Some astonishing figures have been seen in the news in 2021
    and 2022. However, this is completely another topic
</p>
<p>
    Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin has been very concerned about the
    future of the blockchain and the use of NFTs (non-fungible tokens).
    According to him, cryptocurrencies were not created "to play with
    million-dollar monkeys, but to do meaningful things in the real world."
</p>
<p>
    In the face of the somewhat uncontrolled boom in non-fungible tokens,
    Buterin believes that many people are not taking advantage of the true
    potential of ether and its blockchain. In particular, he refers to the NFT
    Bored Ape Yacht Club NFTs, the collection of primate cartoons that have
    become a status symbol in the digital age and for which more than $1
    million has been paid.
</p>
<p>
    In Buterin's view, Ethereum's potential should be harnessed to change the
    world for the better: from fairer voting systems to urban planning and
    public works projects. In particular, he believes the platform could serve
    as a counterweight to authoritarian governments and even end Silicon
    Valley's stranglehold on the digital lives of millions of people.
</p>
<h2>
    Conclusion
</h2>
<p>
    There are several interesting projects out there and you may participate on
    those while generating passive income without many efforts. In this post,
    we have briefly introduced what Ethereum Merge will mean. However, in
    future posts we will describe other cryptocurrencies such as Algorand,
    which already use the PoS validation method.
</p>
<p>
    In general, via Staking, we can benefit of diversification, growing our
    income without big efforts. There are different platforms offering
    different APY for several coins, giving us the possibility of some juicy
    returns without doing nothing. Some of these platforms are Nexo or BlockFi.
    Nonetheless, as promised, we will get into details and see on how we can
    start with this.
</p>
<p>
    If you are interested on learning more about this, you may look for
    additional information in the following website or books.
</p>
<p>
    <a href="https://ethereum.org/en/upgrades/merge/">Ethereum Merge</a>
</p>
<p>
    <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/33584554">
        Mastering Ethereum
    </a>
</p>
<p>
    <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/21820378-mastering-bitcoin">
        Mastering Bitcoin
    </a>
</p>]]></content><author><name>Javier Freire</name></author><category term="Crypto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Staking: the next big thing in Crypto and what Ethereum Merge will mean]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/staking/staking.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/posts/staking/staking.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>